<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_0">
        <text>Damn, you sacred me beast! I didn’t think it was possible for a person to be knocked out for so long. Speaking of which: Oh man, are we in deep shit. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_1">
        <text>The hell? What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_2">
        <text>I don’t know, but I’m sure it’s nothing good. That creature must be playing tricks on us. Going to that place was a huge mistake. The minute I sent you that message, somebody whacked me over the head and I woke up here.  I think this must be the monster’s lair. At first, I was happy because I thought I was out of the anomaly but when I opened my PDA, It turned out that I was still inside it. It turns out we are still inside the anomaly, only beneath the ground.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_3">
        <text>Yeah, that’s sad news indeed. What creature are you talking about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_4">
        <text>I saw it a few times but I didn’t say a word about it to anyone.  I thought that everyone would think I’ve gone off the deep end but I assure this creature is real. Physically the mutant looks like a bloodsucker but it acts and talks like a human being and it wears clothes like one. Also when it was close to me, I could see a profile in my contacts list with the name “Stronglav.” But that’s not the worst part. When I tried to shoot it, the creature just disappeared instantly and it was laughing at me beast, it fucking laughed. I don’t even know what to do...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_5">
        <text>I also saw that creature but I thought it was just a hallucination. We need to find way out of here. Marcus, don’t worry, we’ll get out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_6">
        <text>You think I didn’t try that? Further into the cave there’s a ladder leading upwards but if you try to go there something teleports you back. Hold on... Can you feel that?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_7">
        <text>What am I supposed to feel?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_8">
        <text>That smell... It’s like something is burning. That’s the scent I felt when I saw that creature for the first time. Don’t move, I think the owner of this lair is coming back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_9">
        <text>Great, just what we needed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_0">
        <text>Goddamn it, you blew our cover and you managed to grab the attention of those mutants.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_1">
        <text>I don’t know man, I wanted to ice that creature once and for all... What the hell happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_2">
        <text>How the hell should I know? Listen, we got to get the fuck out of here; that creature is going to comeback any minute now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_3">
        <text>I Agree, we can’t stay here any longer. Let’s look for that exit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_4">
        <text>I’m no condition to do that right now. How about I cover while you look around?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_5">
        <text>Fine, it’s not like we have a better plan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_6">
        <text>Alright, Then you look for the exit and once you find it, message me, alright? Don’t worry about me, I can make it out on my own. Now go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_7">
        <text>Alright, I’m on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_0">
        <text>What the hell was that, Beast? What the hell is happening here? The creature is gone now, but I’m sure that it’ll be back pretty soon...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_1">
        <text>I can’t tell you, I can’t figure out myself what’s going on. .</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_2">
        <text>It laughed again, Beast. It must’ve seen us. We need to get out of here, fast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_3">
        <text>I Agree, we can’t stay here any longer. Let’s look for that exit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_4">
        <text>I’m no condition to do that right now. How about I cover while you look around?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_5">
        <text>Fine, it’s not like we have a better plan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_6">
        <text>Alright, Then you look for the exit and once you find it, message me, alright? Don’t worry about me, I can make it out on my own. Now go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_7">
        <text>Alright, I’m on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_0">
        <text>Hey Knucklehead, how are you feeling?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_1">
        <text>Not good, but I can handle it in the meantime. How about you, any news?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_10">
        <text>Alas, I only have two vaccines vial to give out and I can’t give it out to all three of you. I decided to give one of them to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_11">
        <text>No, Beast, I won’t take it, I rather you give it out to the other guys. Those two have their whole lives ahead of them, while I lived through most of mine. I much rather you save them, instead of me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_12">
        <text>I’ll try to find another vaccine, we still have some time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_13">
        <text>I appreciate your help, but for any case, let’s say our good byes now while I am still alive. This might be our last conversation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_14">
        <text>No, it’s too early for that. I’ll find a cure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_2">
        <text>I found some more of that vaccine, but it’s a really small amount.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_3">
        <text>I’m sorry Knucklehead but I gave the vaccine to someone else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_4">
        <text>Let’s talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_5">
        <text>Don’t worry, Beast, I understand, everyone has their own fate and if I have to die in this place then so be it. You shouldn’t blame yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_6">
        <text>I’ll try to find another vaccine, we still have some time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_7">
        <text>I appreciate your help, but for any case, let’s say our good byes now while I am still alive. This might be our last conversation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_8">
        <text>No, it’s too early for that. I’ll find a cure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_9">
        <text>That’s good to hear, do you have enough for everybody?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_0">
        <text>How are feeling, Marcus?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_1">
        <text>I want to say I’m fine, but that would be total bullshit. Beast, I’ve never felt so shitty in my life, I think I’m going to die soon. Have you managed to find a cure?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_2">
        <text>Yeah, I brought a dose of the cure for you, it should help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_3">
        <text>Let’s talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_4">
        <text>At least now I have a chance... Maybe I’ll get lucky and this thing will cure me. Alright, give me the medication.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_5">
        <text>Here you go, here’s the vial.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_6">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. This means a lot to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_7">
        <text>I wish could do more to help but alas this is all I can manage for now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_0">
        <text>How are you feeling, Rezak?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_1">
        <text>Not too good... What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_2">
        <text>I have found some medciation for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_3">
        <text>Nevermind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_4">
        <text>That’s good to hear. Did you find a lot of it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_5">
        <text>No, only two vaccine vials, one of which I’m giving to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_6">
        <text>So either this vaccine cures me or I die, alright then. Either way, thanks, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_7">
        <text>I’m rooting for you, man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_10">
        <text>Well, there isn’t much of a choice over here so you’re gonna have to adapt. You should go and kill a few boars and cook their meat on the campfire. Hey, I know it’s not exactly gourmet but at least you won’t be hungry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_11">
        <text>What is it, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_12">
        <text>Alright, if that’s the way it is then so be it. Is that all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_13">
        <text>I’m running out of supplies and Savage said you can help me with that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_14">
        <text>I don’t know if you are aware of this but we don’t really have any food left. Our last stock of canned goods and doctor’s sausages came from you. We have already ran out and that’s why we are going to have to go back to eating boar and blind dog even though it’s poisonous. However if it’s prepared correctly, it should be safe to eat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_15">
        <text>I didn’t think I’d ever have to eat the local wild life but sense there isn’t any other choice...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_16">
        <text>How do you I prepare the meat correctly then?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_17">
        <text>I tell you what: First try and cook a piece and when you’re done, I’ll tell you wither you did right or not. But when you’re craving the boar, try to keep the fatty parts, they are tastier.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_18">
        <text>Fine, I’ll do that now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_2">
        <text>Hold on, I know you... You are that same mercenary who helped me hunt down that psi-dog, am I right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_20">
        <text>So Beast, have you brought the meat?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_21">
        <text>Yeah, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_22">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_23">
        <text>Yeah, you did everything correctly, this is perfectly edible. There’s almost no chance of getting poisoned from this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_24">
        <text>Thanks for the very needed advice. At least, I have some steady source of food now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_25">
        <text>Don’t mention it, merc. I hope that you remembered what you did there, it’s important that you do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_26">
        <text>I remember, don’t worry. Aight, I got to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_28">
        <text>What do you need, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_3">
        <text>Yeah, you’re right. It turns out the zone is smaller than I thought.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_30">
        <text>What do you need, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_4">
        <text>Yeah, I agree. You guys sure caused some havoc back then... Don’t worry, I won’t say a word about it to anyone. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_5">
        <text>Everything that went down there was my job and nothing more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_6">
        <text>Whatever you say... Alright, I won’t take any more of your time. See ya.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_7">
        <text>Hey.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_9">
        <text>What do you need, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_0">
        <text>I am ready for the hunt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_1">
        <text>Excellent, that means we can move out right now. The chimera should already be at the bunker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_2">
        <text>I told you already, the chimera only goes to the bunker after midnight so you should know it’s way too early now. Come back at round 2 a.m. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_3">
        <text>Let’s go then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_4">
        <text>Got it, I’ll come by then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_10">
        <text>Alright, that’s all I needed to know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_11">
        <text>The chimera only appears in the bunker during nighttime, so we might as well go right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_12">
        <text>Alright then, get over here at around 2 a.m, that’s the time the chimera usually appears at the bunker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_13">
        <text>Hey, Beast, what’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_14">
        <text>Let’s get going then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_15">
        <text>Alright, I’ll to talk to you again at night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_17">
        <text>Great, now we don’t have to worry about that chimera sneaking into our base any longer. Thanks for your help, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_18">
        <text>Don’t mention it, this chimera being dead benefits us all anyway. Hell, even I will sleep better knowing that this creature is dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_19">
        <text>Yeah. By the way, I bet you have noticed that are food sources are running out. The thing is, I have, for a week, been trying out this new source of food.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_2">
        <text>Hey, Beast, I heard you found Scavenger... Yeah, I never expected him to be such a piece of shit but what’s done is done. Anyway, I have something important to discuss with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_20">
        <text>And what is this new source of food?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_21">
        <text>While everyone else eats their canned goods, I have been eating the local wildlife. There’s a chance, of course, that by eating that type of meat you can get poisoned but if you cook it correctly then you shouldn’t have anything worry about.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_22">
        <text>Nothing wrong with that. Sure it’s not some gourmet dish but a wild boar is perfectly edible. I have tried their meat before. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_23">
        <text>I knew that you would get me, Beast. However, boars aren’t the only animal that’s edible here. Blind dog meat, for example, is far tastier and softer.  Listen, how about we try and cook some of that meat right now? Go and hunt a few boars and try to prepare their meat in the campfire. At least we will have steady source of food that way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_24">
        <text>Yeah, sure. I was getting hungry anyway.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_25">
        <text>Listen, can you bring me a piece as well, all this hunting has made me hungry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_26">
        <text>Sure thing, Knucklehead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_28">
        <text>So what’s up, Beast, have you brought the meat?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_29">
        <text>Yeah, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_3">
        <text>Alright, tell me what’s up, I’m all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_30">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_31">
        <text>Alright... You even cooked it right, nice! Keeping cooking it this way, it’s the safest method. Anyway, Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_32">
        <text>Thanks for the advice. Good to know that there’s a food source always nearby.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_33">
        <text>By the way, before I forget, Marcus told me he wants to talk to you about something. Go see him, once you have some free time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_34">
        <text>Alright, I’ll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_36">
        <text>Hey, Beast, what’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_37">
        <text>By the way, before I forget, Marcus told me he wants to talk to you about something. Go see him, once you have some free time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_38">
        <text>Alright, I’ll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_4">
        <text>We have a serious situation on our hands:  A few days ago, I spotted a chimera not far from our base and sense I was alone and didn’t have much ammo, so I didn’t fight it... Good thing it didn’t see me. This is a very dangerous creature and if it sneaks into our base at night then we are all as good as dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_5">
        <text>What do you suggest we do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_6">
        <text>We need to eliminate it. The safest way to do it is at night; when the mutant goes it sleep in its lair, in the bunker. The two of us can handle a sleeping chimera without a problem, it won’t even know what hit it. What do you think?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_7">
        <text>We are only the two of us going there? Why can’t we get any more help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_8">
        <text>First of all, we are the only ones with enough ammo for the job and second, Two guys against a sleeping chimera is way more than enough. I fought these beasts before and I know this shouldn’t be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_0">
        <text>About your gun...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_1">
        <text>So, did you find it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_2">
        <text>Yeah, here it is, take it. By the way, the bloodsucker that sacred you was waiting for me there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_3">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_4">
        <text>Nah man, he didn’t scare me, I just had no other choice but to run.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_5">
        <text>Stop making excuses, I don’t care either way. Here’s your gun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_6">
        <text>Thanks man, really appreciate it. Now I can go on raids like everyone else and not stay behind. Plus it’s a lot safer here when you have a gun. Here’s a small reward for your good work. I don’t need this money here anyway but perhaps you will need it later.  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_7">
        <text>Thanks. I’ll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_0">
        <text>So... Where did you lose your gun? Can you at least give me a ballpark location?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_1">
        <text>I can tell you the exact location and I know where the gun is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_2">
        <text>So what’s the problem then? Why can’t you just get the gun yourself? It would take less effort then bothering me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_3">
        <text>The thing is, I didn’t lose the gun, I threw it away. When I was scouting, I was attacked by a bloodsucker and my gun jammed. I had no time to clear the malfunction, so I threw the gun at the bloodsucker, shot him a few times with my pistol and ran away. I can’t tell that to the general because running away from a mutant is considered a cowardly act  and going out there alone with a single handgun is near suicide. Help me out here merc, I’ll owe you big time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_4">
        <text>Well, what can you do? Alright I’ll look for your gun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Stay right there and don’t move a muscle! Who are you and what are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_1">
        <text>Take it easy lieutenant. I’m a mercenary and I came here you to reactivate the transformer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Let’s pretend I believe you... How did you open the cage door?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Someone helped me open it. What about you? How long have you been stuck here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_4">
        <text>And you think I’m going to tell you all that? Go talk to the general, he should be more inclined to discuss these things.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Fine, I’ll go talk to him then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_0">
        <text>Yo, merc... Give me some water, please... I can’t go on much longer. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_1">
        <text>The fuck? I can’t walk up to you. I’m trying to get to you but I keep getting teleported back. What the fuck is going on?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_2">
        <text>An anomaly, most likely... Only really small. I can’t get out of here and I’ve ran out of food and water. As for the other guys well, one guy disappeared somewhere while the rest are all dead. The major, he went batshit all of a sudden and started killing people after which he shot himself in the head. So I am left here alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_3">
        <text>Hold on, I was just here a while back and everything was fine. You sent me message just a second ago? How the hell did all of this happen so fast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_4">
        <text>A while back? A whole week has passed sense the moment I sent you that message. After that, I tried to make contact but my pda died all of a sudden.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_5">
        <text>A whole fucking week!? What the hell is going on even? How the fuck is any of this possible?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_6">
        <text>I don’t know and I don’t really give a shit anymore...Go away merc, leave me alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_7">
        <text>Goodbye, general.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_11">
        <text>Greetings, stalker. Do you have some spare food by any chance? We are all just tired of eating mutant meat and are really craving some real food.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_12">
        <text>No, general, I don’t. I could go for some real food myself right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_13">
        <text>Yeah, I thought so.  Listen, we are not asking for it for free. When we were out on our raid, we collected a couple of artifacts and wanted to sell them off the scientists but couldn’t due to our current circumstance. How about you give us some food and we will give you the artifacts? Canned goods, sausages, bread...  We don’t really care what as long as it’s real food. Bring us at least 8 pieces. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_14">
        <text>Alright, general. I’ll try and find some food for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_15">
        <text>Sorry, I can’t help with that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_17">
        <text>So, Beast, are you helping us or what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_19">
        <text>So... Have you found some food?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey, stalker! What the hell is going on in here? Where are we?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_20">
        <text>Here you go, general. It took some effort to find it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_21">
        <text>Yeah, okay. Alright, you did your part, good job. Here’s your artifacts, when you finally get out of here you can sell them for a good price. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_22">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_23">
        <text>Great. Yeah, Only I’m not so sure we will ever get out of here, although I hope we do. Alright, goodbye general.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_24">
        <text>Hold on, stalker, there might be another job for you. When we were out of the bunker, Tug dropped his gun. Perhaps you can help him find it. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_25">
        <text>Sure, I’ll help. Where did he drop it, roughly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_26">
        <text>Go ask him, he should know where it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_27">
        <text>Alright, I’ll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_29">
        <text>Hello, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_3">
        <text>I’d like to know that myself... by the looks of it, we are inside some kind of anomaly. Do you remember how you got here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_4">
        <text>A spatial one.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_5">
        <text>A spatial one. You are not alone here by the way, there’s a group of stalkers nearby and they have been stuck here for a while. More than 2 months to be exact. So, do you remember how you ended up in here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Fuck! Another “gift” from the zone. All, I remember is that we were walking through Agroprom and then we saw a bright light. After that, we woke up here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Alright, I need to turn on the electricity right now, I’ll talk to you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Hello, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_0">
        <text>I see you are finally starting to grasp the seriousness of the situation... I’ll ask again, where the fuck is the Compass?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_1">
        <text>Fucking hell, I am not lying. You know me, you know I don’t lie about these things.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_2">
        <text>Times change and so do people. Take you for example: Your friends now are a bunch of peasant stalkers who got stuck inside the spatial anomaly. You were unpredictable before so who knows what the hell is in your head now. Alright, I’m getting tired of this conversation, Mrakobes told to take you outside so that’s what I’ll do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_3">
        <text>Wait! No, hold on...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_0">
        <text>Wake up, asshole. Welcome back to the real world...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_1">
        <text>What the hell is going on? What the fuck are you doing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_10">
        <text>Wrong answer... But I’ll give you another chance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_11">
        <text>I’m telling the truth, I don’t have any artifacts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_2">
        <text>I came here to check up on you, Jackal was beginning to worry where you gone off to.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_3">
        <text>Do you even know what this place is or better yet, how you’re going to get out of here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_4">
        <text>Why would I want to leave? We just came, plus we might like it here. And if we would want to get out of here we could using our scanner. By the way, I should take that away from you. You know, for safe keeping...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_5">
        <text>Why the hell did you even come here? To save me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_6">
        <text>You think too highly of yourself, Beast. Think, why would we save you? We have a mission related to this anomaly. You and your friends give us the Compass and we go away peacefully.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_7">
        <text>What are you talking about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_8">
        <text>Compass is a type of artifact, Stop pretending you don’t know what I am talking, you should’ve found it by now. Okay either you give it to me or things will get ugly fast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_9">
        <text>We don’t have it and even if we did we wouldn’t give it you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_0">
        <text>You need any help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_1">
        <text>Good thing you’ve asked merc. Our generator is running out of fuel and there isn’t any left in the jerry cans. If we don’t find fuel for it then we won’t have any electricity which means no light in our base. We need it to see mutants during night time. If you manage to find some fuel I’ll give you a couple of bandages and a medkit. I’d give you more than that but you know how it is in this shithole.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_2">
        <text>Alright, I’ll try and find some.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_3">
        <text>I’m kinda busy right now, maybe later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_4">
        <text>Our generator is running out of fuel and there isn’t any left in the jerry cans. If we don’t find fuel for it then we won’t have any electricity which means no light in our base. We need it to see mutants during night time. If you manage to find some fuel I’ll give you a couple of bandages and a medkit. I’d give you more than that but you know how it is in this shithole.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_5">
        <text>Alright, I’ll try and find some.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_6">
        <text>I’m kinda busy right now, maybe later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_7">
        <text>I don’t need your help but thanks for asking.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_10">
        <text>Well, if you managed to befriend a dutyer than surely a mercenary won’t be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_11">
        <text>Yeah, Snake’s a good dude and we managed to find something in common. This place forced has to work together, it’s impossible to survive any other way here. Plus, I am far more concerned with getting out of here then fighting in some endless faction war.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_13">
        <text>Hey, merc. I’m listening...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_15">
        <text>So what’s merc, have you managed to find some fuel?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_16">
        <text>Yeah, I did, actually.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_17">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_18">
        <text>Best news I heard all week. At least now we won’t have to worry about electricity for a while. Give it to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_19">
        <text>Yeah, Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_2">
        <text>Merc, let’s talk later. First we got to get rid of these zombies.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_20">
        <text>Thanks, merc, you helped us big time. Here, just like I promised, Two bandages and a medkit, they should prove useful.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_21">
        <text>No need to thank me, we are all helping each other after all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_23">
        <text>Yeah, merc, I’m listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_24">
        <text>Alright, See ya.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_3">
        <text>Okay, I’ll be on my way then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_5">
        <text>You should go get some sleep man... Plus, I’m in no mood to talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_7">
        <text>Hello, merc. I should probably introduce myself... Everyone here calls me Sledgehammer and I used to be a freedomer, not anymore though. This place made me change my outlook on life.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_8">
        <text>Well, you already know that my name is Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_9">
        <text>I’m not going to lie and pretend that I’m glad you are here. Your faction was a constant threat to us. If I would have seen you a few months ago, we wouldn’t be having this conversation but like a said before this place changed me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_0">
        <text>Merc, where the hell were you? I was getting tired of waiting for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_1">
        <text>Where’s everyone else...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_2">
        <text>They’ve already left. I’m the only one who stayed behind to wait for you. You said something about some dutyers, aren’t they coming?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_3">
        <text>Sadly, they’re dead. Where are we going exactly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_4">
        <text>Let them rest in peace then... Where will the exit lead us, I don’t know. Alright, so are you ready to leave?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_5">
        <text>Yes. Ready as I’ve ever been.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_6">
        <text>Just so you know, once you exit the anomaly, there’s a chance you will pass out. Usually, that doesn’t happen but there’s still a chance. I’m just warning you in advance, just in case. Alright, now when we exit, you need to stick close by me and follow my exact path. Don’t stop even for a second. Any questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_7">
        <text>No, lets go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_0">
        <text>Thank you, young man. I’ve defiantly wouldn’t have handle it myself, I’m way too old for these kind of things. I don’t know what’s going on but the wild life in the zone has really gotten crazy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_1">
        <text>Don’t mention it, old timer. Who are you but the way?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_2">
        <text>They call me forester and I live in the red forest, heard of that place? I caught your call for help on my radio and went to help you out with my Compass. I’m guessing you are the one who called for help? Or is there someone else stuck here with you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_3">
        <text>Wait, so you came here to save us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_4">
        <text>That’s exactly right, son. That’s why a brought the Compass with me, this artifact shows you the way out of this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_5">
        <text>Well, I am not alone here. There’s a stalker base not far from here and there’s a squad of dutyers stuck underground.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_6">
        <text>Well then, show me the way to your base so I can meet all the rest of you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_7">
        <text>Sure, follow me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_10">
        <text>Alright, enough about that, right now we need to take the bodies out of the bunker and bury them and we need to pay respect to Sledgehammer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_11">
        <text>Alright, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_13">
        <text>Hey, Beast, who did you bring this time?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_14">
        <text>He calls himself forester and says he can get us out of the anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_15">
        <text>Are you serious!? I need to talk to him as soon as possible and while I do that you should check out another signal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_16">
        <text>Another signal? Where’s it coming from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_17">
        <text>It’s almost in the same place as you were before, I’ll send you the coordinates. Go there and check it out while I talk to Forester.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_18">
        <text>Fine, I’ll go check it out. Give me the coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_19">
        <text>Alright, you should get them in a second.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_2">
        <text>Excellent work, Beast! Now, at the very least, we have some light. How did everything go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_20">
        <text>Alright, I’ll be on my way then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_22">
        <text>Beast, let’s talk later. First check the signal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_24">
        <text>So Beast, Any good news? Have you managed to find any meds that may help our sick? their situation is really bad, if they don’t get any medication in the next two days, they will surely die.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_25">
        <text>I did find some meds, for one use only though. What’s worse though that there’s isn’t enough medication for everybody seeing that there only two doses of this shit. And even these two doses might not do anything... Man, we should have known eating mutant meat was a bad idea.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_26">
        <text>The important thing right now is not to give up. Right now, more than ever, we have to keep fighting. There’s a different problem though: I don’t think I can choose who gets the medication. Can you make that decision for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_27">
        <text>It’s a tough decision but some has to do it, I guess it’s gonna have to be me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_28">
        <text>Thank you, I could have done it myself. Quick reminder, the people that are sick are: Knucklehead, Marcus, and Rizak. Good luck, Beast. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_29">
        <text>See you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_3">
        <text>When I was in the underground, I found a squad of dutyers. Five people to be exact.</text>
    </string>
 <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_31">
        <text>So, Beast, have you gave out the meds?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_32">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_34">
        <text>You were gone for a few days, where the hell were you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_35">
        <text>I was out all this time looking for a cure, I even slept inside the barn for a higher chance of encountering survivors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_36">
        <text>Yeah, about that… Knucklehead died last night and we buried him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_37">
        <text>And I never even told him goodbye...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_38">
        <text>I myself didn’t get the chance to tell him my goodbyes; I was still hoping he might get better... You said you were looking for meds, did you find anything? Marcus and Rizak are feeling better but they are still sick. Oh yeah, we found this in Knuckleheads stuff, it’s for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_39">
        <text>No, sadly I couldn’t find anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_4">
        <text>Who would have thought... Do you know how long they have been stuck there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_40">
        <text>Too bad... Let’s hope that they will get better with what they have. Alright, you should get some rest after all that endless searching and as for me, I need some alone time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_41">
        <text>See you around, Savage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_5">
        <text>No, they got here only recently.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_6">
        <text>Did you say anything about us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_7">
        <text>I told them about our group but they didn’t want to join us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_8">
        <text>Well, if they don’t want to join us, then I see no reason for asking them. I don’t really give a shit as long they don’t start causing trouble when they run out food.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_9">
        <text>I wouldn’t worry about that, If we managed to fight off the mercenaries then surely they won’t be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_0">
        <text>How are you Beast? How’s Screw, is he alright? I think that Marcus already told you what happened.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_1">
        <text>Yeah, everything is alright. I killed all the mercenaries that were in the barn. Screw’s with me, he’s fine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_2">
        <text>Too bad that Dagger escaped along with a few other assholes; they have probably already exited the anomaly. Don’t worry though, I’ll make him pay for Sledgehammer’s death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_3">
        <text>That peice of shit, he stole the scanner to boot...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_4">
        <text>So you found him? Although, that doesn’t matter that much now, does it? Listen, I’ve been thinking: now that we have access to the bunker we should stay here, it’s a safer place. I already talked to the guys and they think it’s a good idea. What about you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_5">
        <text>Yeah, this place is way better than the barn. It’s a no brainer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_6">
        <text>Glad we are all on the same page. By the way the mercenaries we managed to capture tried to escape so we had to kill them. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_7">
        <text>They knew the risk... Anyway, did Marcus tell you that he found the key to the storage room? There should be plenty of ammo there. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_8">
        <text>Yeah, he already told me about it, this is great news indeed. Alright, there will be enough time to chit chat later but right now we have to find a way to turn on the electricity. When you turned off the power in the barn you also turned it off here in the bunker and when Screw tried to turn it back on it wouldn’t work. There must be a transformer somewhere nearby and we need to reactivate it in order to turn on power. Me and Rizak were looking around and we found some blueprints according to which the transformer should be not far from the barn underneath the ground. Screw said he can unlock the door leading to the underground. He’s already waiting for you near the door so I suggest you get going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_9">
        <text>Right, I’ll get going then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_0">
        <text>What the hell happened? Did you ice those two guys?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_1">
        <text>No, it wasn’t me. The stronglav appeaered out of nowhere and made these to guys kill themselves.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_2">
        <text>Holy shit, he can do that!? Fuck, we are lucky to be alive... Alright what’s most important right now is to free the other guys from captivity. Luckily, I have a plan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_3">
        <text>And what’s your plan?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_4">
        <text>A few of our guys are still held up in the barn, they are guarded by a few mercs. First we free them and then we go for the rest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_5">
        <text>Not like we have any better choice... By the way, how did you manage to get out of the cave?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_6">
        <text>Nothing too complicated really: after you climbed out, I just followed you and managed to find my way out. When I finally climbed out, I could piss myself from happiness... But anyway, we are getting side tracked and we have to get moving fast. Follow me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_7">
        <text>Fine, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_2">
        <text>Alright, this place is an old military reserve and it should have plenty of firepower. I don’t for how long these weapons have been stored here but let’s hope they all work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_3">
        <text>How are you going to open the door?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_4">
        <text>I found the key to it when I was inside the Stronglav’s lair. I’ve already taken some stuff out of there but there’s still plenty to go around in there.  Here’s the key, take all you need while I wait for you here  and guard the area.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_5">
        <text>Alright, I won’t take too long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_7">
        <text>Beast, get a move on... Take what you need and let’s get going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_8">
        <text>Alright, I won’t take too long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_0">
        <text>So, are you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_1">
        <text>Yeah, ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_2">
        <text>Okay so, listen up. Even though most of the mercs are at the bunker, there’s still a big chunk of them in the barn. They are holding Screw hostage there for some reason, and we need to save him. The best option we have right now is to kill the electricity and uses the darkness to our advantage. What do you think? Also, I need to ask you something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_3">
        <text>Your plan is solid. As for your question, this isn’t the best time for chit-chat right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_4">
        <text>Well, it’s about our current situation. Are you sure that you are going to be able to fight these guys? There’s a chance that you might ran into an old friend among them, you used to work for the syndicate after all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_5">
        <text>Don’t worry, there shouldn’t be any problem. These assholes were never my friends.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_6">
        <text>There’s a chance, I might ran into someone I know but I have to do what needs to be done. Our lives are at stake here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_7">
        <text>Huh... Alright then. If that’s the case then let’s not waste any more time. Alright, you go take care of the mercs in the barn while go help the rest. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_8">
        <text>You’re right about that... Alright, you go take care of the mercs in the barn while go help the rest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_9">
        <text>Got it, I’ll join you when I’m finished here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_10">
        <text>When you’ll be ready, talk to snake. He’ll mark the location on your pda.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_11">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_13">
        <text>Beast, this is no time to chit chat. We got to take out this fleshes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_15">
        <text>Hey, Beast! I noticed you’re not too bad of a detective. First, you and Knucklehead found the chimera then you found Scavenger and uncovered all of his dirty deeds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_16">
        <text>Alright, what’s your point?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_17">
        <text>We need your help. Before Savage came along we had a different leader by the name of Shell. Good guy... Only he disappeared.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_18">
        <text>And how long has it been?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_19">
        <text>About a month. Even though, it’s most likely that he is dead but I did catch the signal of his pda a few days ago when I was near the abandoned basement, although only for a split second. I tried looking everywhere but couldn’t find anything. Maybe he, like Scavenger, used teleports to move around but got stuck somewhere... Maybe you can find him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_2">
        <text>This no time to flap your gums! The zombies are closing in and you are the only one with ammo to spare so get going and then maybe will talk. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_20">
        <text>You think he could survive all this time on his own?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_21">
        <text>Anything is possible here, plus he’s one of the tough ones. He wore an exoskeleton and always carried a PKM with him. The last time he was seen, he had plenty of food and ammo so there might be a chance he’s still alive. Shell was a great leader and he’s the one who made us work together in the first place. That’s quite an accomplishment considering we have stalkers from rivaling factions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_22">
        <text>Alright, I’ll try and look for Shell. Who knows? Maybe I’ll get lucky.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_24">
        <text>Greetings, merc! I haven’t had the chance to meet you yet but my name’s Marcus. First of all, I wanted to thank you for helping us out, now, at the very least we have some resources to spare.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_25">
        <text>Don’t mention it... My name’s Beast by the way but you should already know that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_26">
        <text>Yeah you’re right about that. So this place is called spatial anomaly right? So it turns out there’s supposed to be a way out of here, we just have to find it.  By the way, are you busy right now? I need your help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_27">
        <text>Nope. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_28">
        <text>No, my hands are full right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_29">
        <text>Nothing too difficult, all you have to do is find me a Wrenched. This artifact cleanses your body of radiation very well. There are plenty of gravitational anomalies here so finding one shouldn’t that much of a problem. I’d go myself but I am all out of ammo. As for the reward, don’t worry, I’ll give you a different artifact in return. Even though it’s radioactive, it does have some positive qualities. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_30">
        <text>Alright, I’ll try to find you a “wrenched”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_32">
        <text>So are you still busy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_33">
        <text>Not anymore, what’s the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_34">
        <text>Still busy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_36">
        <text>So, Beast how’s the artifact search going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_37">
        <text>Yeah, It’s here. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_38">
        <text>No, I haven’t found it yet. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_39">
        <text>That’s awesome! I can stop worrying about antirads... It’s been two weeks sense I ran out. Doesn’t matter though, this artifact does the job way better. Give it to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Me and the guys are planing to go find some food and we need your help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_40">
        <text>Here, take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_41">
        <text>Here’s your reward. I’m really grateful for what you have done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_42">
        <text>Sure, I’ll be glad to help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_44">
        <text>Hey, Beast! any news?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_46">
        <text>So, Beast, any news about Shell?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_47">
        <text>When I found Shell, he was zombified so I had to kill him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_48">
        <text>No news yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_49">
        <text>That’s really fucked up. Man, he shouldn’t have ever left on his own like that, if he hadn’t he would probably be alive right now. How the hell did you manage to kill him though, wasn’t he wearing an exoskeleton?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_5">
        <text>So how do you need my help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_50">
        <text>It was really hard but I managed to do it somehow...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_51">
        <text>Did he have anything interesting on him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_52">
        <text>No, only this dogtag, here have a look.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_53">
        <text>Yeah, that’s his dog tag alright... Thank you, beast. Here’s a reward for your hardwork.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_54">
        <text>feel free to ask for help anytime. Alright, see you around.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_56">
        <text>Hey, beast! What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Rizak told me that you saw some Fleshes nearby. We decided that, since we don’t have any other food, we are going to eat flesh meat. You wanna help us out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_60">
        <text>Alright, we will talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Alright, let’s talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_8">
        <text>Snake, Sledgehammer, and I will come with you but I have do something first so I’ll join a bit later. In the meantime make sure those two won’t start fighting with each other.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Got it, Marcus. Alright, send me coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_10">
        <text>I help, Don’t worry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_11">
        <text>So, Beast, have you found the SVD ammo yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_12">
        <text>Yeah, I have the ammo, here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_13">
        <text>No, not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_14">
        <text>Excellent work, man. I never thought you could actually find them here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_15">
        <text>Yeah, okay. Where’s my reward?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_16">
        <text>Here it is, just like I promised.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_17">
        <text>Thanks. Alright, I’ll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_19">
        <text>Hey Beast, what do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Yo, Beast, Thanks for taking care of those zombies. Are you busy now? I need your help with something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Nope. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_5">
        <text>So, have managed to find some free time?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Yeah, what do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_7">
        <text>I have an SVD stashed nearby, only there’s one problem, I don’t have any ammo for it. Can you help me find some ammo for it? Even a single pack will suffice for now. I will give you some ammo for your ak in exchange and I’ll throw some cash on top. So, are you in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_8">
        <text>No, I’m too busy right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Sorry, I’m too busy</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_0">
        <text>LLook who it is... Hello, creature, what the hell are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_1">
        <text>I could ask you the same question... Do you even know where you are? You have no idea how much you’ve fucked up by coming here. Anyway, either you get out of my way right now or I am going to shoot you in the head.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_2">
        <text>Huh... Look at you talk like you’re all tough and shit. No worries though, you’re going to be singing a different tune soon enough. By the way, the syndicate says hello.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_3">
        <text>I’m going to...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_0">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. This is the second time you’re saving my skin. Are the mercenaries really here because of me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_1">
        <text>No. They’re here for some kind of artifact... Compass it’s called, they think we have it. What’s even worse though is that these pieces of shit killed Sledgehammer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_2">
        <text>Man, this some fucked situation we’re in... That means that there still some mercs out there and there holding our friends hostage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_3">
        <text>Yeah, Marcus is working on a way to free them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_4">
        <text>Listen, you better go help him and as for me, the mercs fucked me up pretty bad so I better just hang back here. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_5">
        <text>Fine, Stay here then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_0">
        <text>Oh, you finally came? Did Savage tell you what you need to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_1">
        <text>Yeah, he did.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_2">
        <text>Then let’s go. I help you open the door but remember I am not going down there with you; I don’t know what’s in there. I’ll open the entrance and head back to base, not like you need my help anyway. So, are you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_3">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_10">
        <text>They told me to find a battery for the radio, so give it here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_12">
        <text>Yeah, Merc, what is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_13">
        <text>Then give that battery to the man. In the meantime, I’m gonna catch my breath.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_14">
        <text>All right. I’m off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_2">
        <text>Thanks for the help, man. I think we can exchange a few words now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_3">
        <text>You said a few mercenaries were after you. Why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_4">
        <text>Well, basically, the scientists gave me an assignment to try out a radio transmitter. If I remember their words correctly: “Just test it out and see if you pick up anything.” I messed around with the hunk of junk and happened to pick up a mercenary channel, and man, they were having some serious negotiations. I heard it all, mouth shut. Didn’t even move a muscle. Then, all of a sudden, the mercs got that someone was listening in on them and ordered everyone to sweep the area, and that’s when this whole shitstorm started. Because of my screwup, the place was crawling with mercs within minutes. I randomly happened upon an anomaly; good thing it didn’t happen to be a whirligig or anything… No, it was some kind of space anomaly. And now I’m here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_5">
        <text>Do you still have that transmitter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_6">
        <text>I have it, but it looks like it broke when I was sent here. When I was running away from the mercs, I threw it into my backpack, and when I left the anomaly, I dropped the backpack. Now, the transmitter is more of a puzzle game than a working device.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_7">
        <text>Did any of the parts inside the transmitter survive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_8">
        <text>All right. Let me have the battery for now. I’m going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_9">
        <text>A couple of busted microchips… and a battery that I could give you if you have any use for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Merc, who the hell are you, God damn it? Answer or I’ll open fire!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_1">
        <text>Calm down. I’m here to help. I go by Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_10">
        <text>Calm your tits… or do you want me to calm you down myself?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_11">
        <text>You’re dead, merc… All of you are dead…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_12">
        <text>That’s your choice…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Here to help, huh? You pulling my leg or something? What the hell do you mercs want from me, anyway? I never heard anything! Go away!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_3">
        <text>“You”? Who are you talking about? There are no mercs here but me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Let’s say you’re telling the truth… Wait. You said “here.” What do you mean by that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Oh, man. Fortune doesn’t smile on you. You’ve ended up in a spatial anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_6">
        <text>What? Damn! I need to get out of here, immediately! The mercs will be here soon. They’ve seen where I ended up…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Don’t panic. We’ll go to the base and talk about everything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_8">
        <text>Is it far? Are there other stalkers there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Like I said: we’ll talk about it when we’re there. Come on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_0">
        <text>Mercenary, you’re very lucky that phantom didn’t take you with it. If you hadn’t passed its trial, you’d never be waking up after that. Phantoms are extremely deceptive, but that which gives rise to them is much more dangerous.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_1">
        <text>Wait. What are you saying? Who are you, even?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_2">
        <text>That’s not our priority to discuss. You need to stay away from phantoms. They’re very dangerous. Remember that…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_3">
        <text>What’s going on here? What are phantoms?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_4">
        <text>What you saw here last night was a phantom. Phantoms are the souls of dead people; they appear at the site of their death, or close to their dead body. Normally, they aren’t dangerous, but the phantom you saw here was made to lure someone into a trap.</text> <!-- fix -->
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_5">
        <text>Then, the one who did it didn’t succeed. I mean, I escaped.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_6">
        <text>You have more fortune than the stalker who came here before you, but you cannot always rely on your chances. Be vigilant, mercenary, and do not let yourself fall into another trap.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_7">
        <text>How do you know all of this, old man?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_8">
        <text>I know much. Follow my advice; you are in danger. Do not let yourself be deceived. Farewell, mercenary. I hope we see each other again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_9">
        <text>What?! Hey! Wait! How are you going to leave the anomaly?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_0">
        <text>I can do it… Why don’t I want this to… with me… This thing…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_1">
        <text>Hey, man, what’s going on with you? You all right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_10">
        <text>There’s a lot I don’t remember… At the Radar… we decided to take a shortcut… We went through the Red Forest… As it turns out… there were no dangers there… There’s a hole in the fence… I can get around a few Monolith patrols… No… No… You…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_11">
        <text>What?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_12">
        <text>I don’t remember… The voice is calling… I need to get… I was there! I’ve seen it! It got into my head and spoke to me. It spoke to me! A terrible voice sounded in my head, scorching my brains out. Terrible… Terrible. Terrible! Do not go there! It will become you, just as it became me. A wild pain in my head… And the voice… whispers to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_13">
        <text>Calm down, buddy. Everything’s alright. You’re safe here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_14">
        <text>A whisper… A whisper and the creaking of swings… It’s in my head, and I’ve become a monster myself. No. I can’t. Friend, hand over my artifact to Baldy. That’s all I found there when It came into my head. Baldy will give it to my wife, my son. This will compensate them…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_15">
        <text>What’ll compensate them?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_2">
        <text>I’m fine! I’m fine… I can contain myself. I can…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_3">
        <text>Do you hear me?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_4">
        <text>No! It won’t be with me! It will not be with me!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_5">
        <text>Answer me already!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_6">
        <text>My skull… It’s tearing at me… It’s… I’m Spotty. Radiation… took him! Hunchback! Hunchback is dead!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_7">
        <text>Hunchback? Who’s Hunchback?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_8">
        <text>A stalker… We went together to the Scorcher. Hunchback, Savage, and I.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_9">
        <text>What did you do at the Scorcher?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_10">
        <text>First, we have to eliminate the nearby zombies, or else, they’ll be taking us with them. Do you have any ammunition for my Kalashnikov?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_11">
        <text>I would if I’d never have woken up in this place…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_12">
        <text>Then give me two packs. I’ll share them with Mosquito. He’s a good shot. You guys can take care of yourselves.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_13">
        <text>Okay. Take the ammo.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_14">
        <text>Okay. This is bad.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_15">
        <text>We should find Scavenger. Without him, we won’t last very long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_17">
        <text>Welcome back from the world beyond, buddy… Nobody was thinking you’d be coming back to your senses; you were unconscious for four days. Hmm… That blowout messed you up bad. Nobody would’ve survived that… or so we thought. You’re alive. Whether that’s a good thing or a bad thing is something I don’t know. The fact remains that this is very strange, though. Very strange indeed. Anyway: you seem to be an all right man, but your merc attributes seem a little suspicious. Whose side are you on?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_18">
        <text>I’m Beast: a mercenary… What is this place, and who are you?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_19">
        <text>Hmm. A mercenary? Looks like I was right… Well then, merc: answering your first question is going to be difficult, because I myself don’t know where exactly we are. This place here is mystical; we’ve been here for a long time, and all the while, the Zone’s been messing with us. I’m Savage. Nice to meet you. By the way, though, the guys aren’t very happy about having a mercenary around here, so I’m going to ask you to behave yourself. We’re all in a rather difficult situation; many nerves have been shot around here. Let’s all get along here and manage without any conflicts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_2">
        <text>Merc, now would be a great time for your assistance… Zombies are approaching our base. We have to take them out, or this place is going to be overrun within seconds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_20">
        <text>What do you mean? How is this place “mystical”?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_21">
        <text>I don’t know, merc. There’s no way out of here… You go anywhere, you always end up back at this godforsaken barn. We barely make ends meet around here, living another day without escaping malnutrition or any of the local mutants. Lost a lot of munitions, too, and that’s not counting any of the mutants. Only God knows how they keep finding a way here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_22">
        <text>Damn… What have I gotten myself into? How long have you been here, and where is my equipment?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_23">
        <text>Another stalker and I have been holed up here for about seven months. The others: about one to three months… As for your equipment, four days ago, one of our men scouted the neighborhood and stumbled upon your unconscious self. I have no idea about the location of your stuff. All you had on you was a pistol, a few magazines, and your suit, which was close to looking like a floorcloth. It’s obvious that I can’t force you to follow my orders, but I suggest you join our group so that you’ll have a chance of biting the dust a little later than if you go on by yourself. In addition, we’d be very interested in having a man of your talents around. I hope you’ve heard my words and understood everything; otherwise, you’ll have a few more problems on your hands.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_24">
        <text>I understand. I have no ill intentions toward you and your men.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_3">
        <text>Is nobody else able to help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_4">
        <text>We don’t have time to worry about that. You need to help Cutter. He’s the one who you brought you here, even if some of our men were against it. Now, it’s your turn to repay the favor. And, I noticed a few Kalashnikov mags in your uniform. If you hand me two of them, I can help you out. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_5">
        <text>I can’t even remember how I ended up here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_6">
        <text>Damn this place! What do we do? Without rations or munitions, we won’t last a week! We haven’t seen any new stalkers for almost two months. Usually, they die in anomaies, and we live off all their possessions, but now… And on top of that, Scavenger’s gone off somewhere.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_7">
        <text>We’ll figure something out. Don’t worry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_8">
        <text>Who’s Scavenger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_9">
        <text>Scavenger? If it wasn’t for him, we’d all be worm food right now! He scouted the area and gathered valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and didn’t return.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_1">
        <text>I think so. The hard part’s over with; his wounds aren’t fatal anymore. He’ll be able to move a bit faster soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_10">
        <text>Beast, if it wasn’t for Scavenger, we’d all be dead right now. He combed the whole area and gathered valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and still hasn’t returned… He picked up on a signal not far from the base, then went to check it out and never got back. I sent a few guys to look for him, Cutter and Mosquito, but they didn’t find him. Instead, what they found was you. Here’s what I don’t get, though: how did you manage to survive in the first place? There were blind dogs no further than ten meters from where you were found.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_11">
        <text>I don’t know how I’m still alive, but that’s the important part. Anyway, I’ll go check out the area. Maybe I’ll find something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_12">
        <text>I don’t know how I’m still alive, but that’s the important part. Anyway, I’ll go check out the area. Maybe I’ll find something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_13">
        <text>It’d mean a lot. No one can really replace Scavenger; he gathered so much stuff in a single day, and we can’t even match half of his efforts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_14">
        <text>If I find anything, I’ll shoot you a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_15">
        <text>It’d mean a lot. No one can really replace Scavenger; he gathered so much stuff in a single day, and we can’t even match half of his efforts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_16">
        <text>If I find anything, I’ll shoot you a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_17">
        <text>Speak to Knucklehead on that matter. He’ll help you solve the issue. Oh, also: Snake wanted to see you. Said that he’s got an important matter. After you’re done with that, you come to me. I’ve got something else for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_19">
        <text>Well, this is great. I thought this was going to be our ticket to freedom. This anomaly doesn’t want to let us free… How’s that soldier? He going to live?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_2">
        <text>That’s great. I have a feeling this place used to be some kind of military area before the anomaly showed up. Maybe the jarhead can give us some info about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_20">
        <text>All right. I’ll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_22">
        <text>Hi there, Beast. You need something from me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_24">
        <text>I need your help with a little something… We had this stalker. Called him Scavenger. He went missing two days ago, but I don’t want to think that he’s dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_26">
        <text>Hi there, Beast. You need something from me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_28">
        <text>Hi there, Beast. You need something from me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_3">
        <text>Maybe so, but in his current state, he can barely even stand. Let him have some rest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_4">
        <text>Yeah. No need to bother him right now. I’m quite sure we have enough medicine to get him on his feet eventually. Too bad we have no actual medics. By the way, I see you’re looking much better than before. Sleep did you some good.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_5">
        <text>Yeah. I feel better; at least my headache’s over… I have some provisions with me. Do you guys have any rations?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_6">
        <text>That’s great, Beast. Remember when I told you about Scavenger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_7">
        <text>The one who snatched loot from local corpses and brought it back here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_8">
        <text>What about him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_9">
        <text>Yeah. Scavenger combed the whole area and gathered valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and still hasn’t returned. He picked up on a signal not far from the base, then went to check it out and never got back. I sent a few guys to look for him, Cutter and Mosquito, but they didn’t find him. Instead, what they found was you. Here’s what I don’t get, though: how did you manage to survive in the first place? There were blind dogs no further than ten meters from where you were found.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_0">
        <text>So that’s where the zombies came from. An unexpected guest showed up at our doorstep, though. Thanks for helping us take it out, Beast. I won’t forget that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_1">
        <text>I helped you, and later, you’ll be helping me… No reason to be grateful, Savage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_10">
        <text>It’ll mean a lot if you find him. Scavenger was a good stalker. He’s been a great help to us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_11">
        <text>If I find anything, I’ll shoot a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_2">
        <text>All right. We should get out of here, else the pseudogiants will show up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_3">
        <text>We’ll figure something out. I’ll try to find a way out of here. Do you have anything else for me to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_4">
        <text>Yes, Beast. Remember when I told you about Scavenger??</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_5">
        <text>The one who snatched loot from local corpses and brought it back here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_6">
        <text>I remember him, but I don’t know who he is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_7">
        <text>Yeah. Scavenger combed the whole area and gathered valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and still hasn’t returned. He picked up on a signal not far from the base, then went to check it out and never got back. I sent a few guys to look for him, Cutter and Mosquito, but they didn’t find him. Instead, what they found was you. You helped us eliminate both the zombies and the controller, and for that, Beast, I thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_8">
        <text>Beast, if it wasn’t for Scavenger, we’d all be dead right now. He combed the whole area and gathered valuable supplies from corpses. Two days ago, he left camp and still hasn’t returned… He picked up on a signal not far from the base, then went to check it out and never got back. I sent a few guys to look for him, Cutter and Mosquito, but they didn’t find him. Instead, what they found was you, but I’m glad you showed up. You helped us eliminate both the zombies and the controller, and for that, Beast, I thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_9">
        <text>No need to thank me. I’ll go comb the area; maybe I’ll find something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_0">
        <text>So, what did you find there, merc? Did you deal with the zombies?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_1">
        <text>Yes. The zombies have been neutralized. Mosquito’s fine as well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_10">
        <text>Hmm. A spatial anomaly, you say? Does the note have any clue about an exit?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_11">
        <text>No. I have a question, though: how did zombies end up here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_2">
        <text>The zombies are down, but… they got Mosquito.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_3">
        <text>That’s good news, merc! Did you find anything interesting on those fellas?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_4">
        <text>How? Ugh. I’m sorry for the guy… But what’s better: staying around here waiting for starvation or leaving for another world?…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_5">
        <text>Yes. The first thing I found was some info about the zombies: they were all part of Duty. I retrieved a note from one of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_6">
        <text>Yeah. I wanted to tell you, though: all the zombies were part of Duty, and one of them carried a note.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_7">
        <text>What’s written there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_8">
        <text>What’s written there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_9">
        <text>The note describes this very place: we’re inside some kind of anomaly. The Dutyer described this anomaly as spatial. I’ve heard about it before…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_0">
        <text>Damn. My head… What the hell attacked us?! Okay, at least we know how the zombified stalkers ended up here, even if an unexpected guest showed up at our doorstep. Hey, I wonder: why didn’t you fall under its influence like everyone else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_1">
        <text>I don’t know. I did fall under the control of one of those mutants in the past. It almost managed to zombify me, but then Fish saved me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_2">
        <text>That Fish is certainly a good man. Anyway… Good thing you managed to steer clear of that controller’s influence, else we’d all have been on a leash. What was I thinking?… With our security, anyone can waltz in here without a problem. The really scary part is that these zombies have been wandering around the barn for a while, and that means that the controller was also under our nose this whole time…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_3">
        <text>Right now, we need to get the guys some more ammo. We won’t be able to protect ourselves otherwise.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_4">
        <text>You’re right about that, but the ammo shortage isn’t our main problem: our food supply is dangerously low, and we’re almost out of drinking water. The morale here is dropping every day. Several of our men are saying that there’s no way out of here and that we’re all going to die of starvation. I do get such thoughts myself from time to time, but I try to keep them at bay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_5">
        <text>I’ll do everything I can in my power to find a way out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_6">
        <text>I hope we can still find a way out of here, because I don’t want to die here. I didn’t think that the Zone would give me such a horrible present; to live out my days in this cage. I want to go back home to my wife and daughter. Why in the hell has this Zone entrapped me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_7">
        <text>Yeah. The situation isn’t easy. Do you have any other task for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_8">
        <text>Listen, Beast: you look pretty beat up. You spent a lot of time in that bed, blacked out, but I can see it didn’t help you nothing. A face-to-face meeting with a controller isn’t the best treatment, either. Go and rest up; seeing you in your current state is painful. We’ll talk more in the morning. In the meantime, the guys and I are going to deal with the corpse of that controller.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_9">
        <text>Some shut-eye wouldn’t hurt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_10">
        <text>Just a sec… Okay. The marker should be on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_12">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_13">
        <text>Then let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_14">
        <text>I’m listening, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_15">
        <text>Hey. Did you need something from me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_16">
        <text>Yes, Beast. As you can see, we have a shortage of food and munitions. That’s not our only issue; on top of that, our amount of drinking water is dangerously low. I mean, there’s a well outside the barn, but the water in there is radioactive, and drinking any of it without any prior purification is life-threatening. But there is, in fact, a way to purify it. From time to time, you can find an anomalous plant inside this anomaly. At one point, I helped the scientists at Yantar with purifying water, and they did it by boiling the flower in the water.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_17">
        <text>You want me to go flower picking? Not my style.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_18">
        <text>No, Beast. You won’t have to pick anything. Cutter sent me the locations of a few such plants; he spotted them from the tower. You just have to stay by my side. The place is crawling with mutants, and I don’t have a lot of ammo to deal with them on my own. Will you give me a hand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_19">
        <text>All right. I’ll cover you. When are we heading out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_2">
        <text>Merc, we can talk later. Right now, you should deal with the zombies together with Mosquito.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_20">
        <text>Right now. If you’re ready, of course…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_21">
        <text>I’m ready. Let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_22">
        <text>Wait just a moment. Need to check my gear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_24">
        <text>I’m listening, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_26">
        <text>We’re back, safe and sound. I have the plants. Thanks for covering me, Beast. Now, I’ll be able to work with purifying the water for the men. These plants should suffice for at least some time. By the way, if you run out of water, come see me, and I’ll be able to provide you some.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_28">
        <text>So, Beast, are you ready to pick some flowers?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_29">
        <text>I’m ready. Let’s head out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_3">
        <text>Then I’ll go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_30">
        <text>Wait a moment. Not quite ready yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_31">
        <text>No problem. I’ll come by if I need any H2O.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_33">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_34">
        <text>My flask’s already empty. Can you fill it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_35">
        <text>No problem, Beast. Hand it over.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_36">
        <text>Right. Here’s your flask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_37">
        <text>I’m purifying the water. Waiting for it to cool down. After that, I’ll message you so you can come for the flask. Cool?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_38">
        <text>All right. I’ll wait for a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_40">
        <text>Here. Take your flash. The water’s all clean and cooled down. You can drink it right now if you like.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_41">
        <text>Thanks, Snake. You’re a big help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_42">
        <text>Here’s the thing: I haven’t purified the water for you yet. We’ll deal with the flesh later. Once it’s done, I’ll give you a message. ’Kay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_44">
        <text>The water’s still contaminated. Drop by a bit later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_46">
        <text>’Kay. I’m ready to go. The water’s been purified; here’s your flask. Now, let’s go hunt some flesh while we still have our dinner waiting for us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_47">
        <text>Thanks for the water. Put a marker where these flesh are at and let’s drop ’em.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_48">
        <text>Just a sec… Okay. The marker should be on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_49">
        <text>Then let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_50">
        <text>All right. The flesh are waiting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_51">
        <text>All right. I’ll go later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_53">
        <text>Here. Take your flash. The water’s all clean and cooled down. You can drink it right now if you like.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_54">
        <text>Thanks, Snake. You’re a big help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_6">
        <text>Hey there, Beast! So, you ready to shoot down a few radioactive piggies?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_7">
        <text>I’m ready. Let’s head out right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_8">
        <text>Great. Let’s go hunt some flesh while we still have our dinner waiting for us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_9">
        <text>Put a marker where these flesh are at and let’s drop ’em.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_0">
        <text>My flask’s empty. Can you help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_1">
        <text>No problem, Beast. Hand it over.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_2">
        <text>Here’s your flask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_3">
        <text>I’m purifying the water. Waiting for it to cool down. After that, I’ll message you so you can come for the flask. Cool?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_4">
        <text>It’s a deal. I’ll wait for a message from you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_0">
        <text>Tell me about your group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_1">
        <text>Who do you want to know about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_10">
        <text>I’ve changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_11">
        <text>Cutter’s a strict man. He’s hard to understand, but he doesn’t cause a lot of conflict; on the contrary, he helps break up any arguing in the group, if it ever comes up. He ended up in the anomaly about two months ago. He couldn’t get it together for the longest time, but nonetheless, he adapted. His main role is reconnaissance, which used to be Scavenger’s thing. All in all, he’s a decent guy, but as of late, he’s been pretty down; he keeps talking nonsense about us being stuck here forever.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_12">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_13">
        <text>About Sledge? Well, he went through thick and thin in his days. He’s like steel; a force of nature. Not a man. I knew him from before the whole fiasco with the anomaly. Back then, he worked with Freedom at the military warehouses. Everybody there cherished and respected him, but after he appeared here, he became different. He found friends among enemies here and generally became a kinder person. He’s been with us for about two and a half months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_14">
        <text>Hm. So this place has some kind of use. Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_15">
        <text>Quite a young fellow, who made the mistake of joining Duty; or rather, that’s what he believes. If he gains experience, he might become a very good fighter one day, but if he gets out of here, he probably won’t be joining up with his faction again. He made friends with Sledgehammer, though they both got pretty hot-headed when they first met ’cause of Sledge’s time in Freedom. He’s been here for almost over a month.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_16">
        <text>Markus is the musician here, and, if I may say, my right hand man. If there’s ever something I can’t quite deal with on my own, he’s always there to help me. He was part of the original group that ended up in here. We had a third guy, but let’s leave that for now. You could say that we brought some order to this place, if you can call it “order.” Eventually, some new stalkers came along, including yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_17">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_18">
        <text>Thanks for the info, Savage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_19">
        <text>Mosquito used to be a marksman; hence, his accuracy is on top. If you need help from a good shooter, he’s the one to talk to. Regarding his other qualities, he’s a very kind-hearted and talkative man, and he never let his presence in the anomaly get to him. He’s been with us for about three months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_2">
        <text>Tell me about Cutter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_20">
        <text>Mosquito used to be a marksman; hence, his accuracy was on top. Regarding his other qualities, he was a very kind-hearted and talkative man, and he never let his presence in the anomaly get to him. He was with us for about three months. It’s unfortunate that he was killed in this anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_21">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_22">
        <text>Without Knucklehead, we’d have been much worse off. He’s a hunter and a gatherer. After Scavenger came here, they’ve both been helping the group by supplying us with mutant meat. I don’t know how things would work out here without him. He’s been with us for over three months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_23">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_24">
        <text>Not much I need to say about Screw. He’s the heart of our group. Without him, we wouldn’t be able to maintain any of our equipment, and without equipment, we wouldn’t last very long. The guys hand him all sorts of trash, which he buys for money, and then, with the help of that trash, he fixes all of our gear. He doesn’t do it for free, but that doesn’t matter to us. He got here about a week ago or two after us, and since then, he’s been a steady helping hand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_25">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_26">
        <text>I won’t take up too much time talking about myself. I ended up here during the assault on Limansk. At the time, I was in a detachment in Clear Sky together with Markus and Shell. Everyone here ended up at the same time, and not everyone’s lived until the present moment. Shell was the leader of our detachment, and he remained our leader after our appearance in the anomaly… well, until he disappeared, after which I assumed his position.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_27">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_28">
        <text>Not at all. If you want me to share more about anyone else, just ask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_3">
        <text>Tell me about Sledgehammer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_4">
        <text>Tell me about Snake.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_5">
        <text>Tell me about Markus.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_6">
        <text>Tell me about Mosquito.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_7">
        <text>Tell me about Knucklehead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_8">
        <text>Tell me about Screw.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_9">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_0">
        <text>Hi there, Beast. You need something from me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_1">
        <text>Markus should’ve returned by now, but there’s not a trace of him… Do you know where he went off?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_2">
        <text>Hm… Nope. I don’t know. He didn’t tell me anything. Wait just a minute; I’m going to try picking up his PDA signal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_3">
        <text>All right. I’m waiting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_end_2">
        <text>Beast, it seems I’ve picked up the Markus’ PDA signal… or, rather, his last signs of activity. Head over there at once. I can tell something’s not right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_end_3">
        <text>Got you, Savage. Send over the coordinates and I’ll head there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_end_5">
        <text>Beast, not now. Go to Markus’ last known location and find out what happened. We need to find him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_0">
        <text>I’m here about the SOS.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_1">
        <text>I’m listening. Did you talk to whoever sent it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_10">
        <text>Most likely.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_2">
        <text>Yep. The stalker who sent the signal is already here; I led him to the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_3">
        <text>I think you did the right thing, Beast. In a situation like this, you need to stick together. Another soul here won’t hurt. He does know where he is, right? Have you told him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_4">
        <text>Yeah. I told him. When I found him, he said he was being pursued by mercenaries.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_5">
        <text>All right. Well, that’s a problem… Whatever. They’re probably clever enough not to end up in the anomaly. Beast, go over to him and ask him about himself. The more we know about him, the more he can be trusted.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_6">
        <text>Yeah. I’ll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_7">
        <text>I’m listening. Did you talk to whoever sent it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_8">
        <text>The stalker who sent it was killed. I wasn’t able to bring him back to base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_9">
        <text>Sad to hear. But the Zone is merciless. I’m sure you did everything in your power to save his life.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_0">
        <text>I found Scavenger. He’s dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_1">
        <text>How is he dead? Where’d you find him, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_10">
        <text>The stalkers Scavenger was looking for weren’t always dead; he killed them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_11">
        <text>Strange. He never told us about that. Beast, we need to find that decoder; in all likelihood, it’s just what we need right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_12">
        <text>Don’t worry. I, too, want to find it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_13">
        <text>Great to hear, Beast. As soon as we get more info about it, come to me and we’ll talk. What else was on Scavenger’s PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_14">
        <text>Hm… Well, this is certainly his doing. I’m glad he tried to help us somehow. If you find his stash, bring it to base. We’ll find out what to do with it; it’s not like Scavenger needs it anymore. Did his PDA contain anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_15">
        <text>So that son of a gun took all the most valuable loot for himself? God damn… If you find his stash, bring it to base. We’ll find out what to do with it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_16">
        <text>You serious right now? Motherfucker! If I knew about this earlier, I’d have him pulverized. Good thing he kicked the bucket. That’s what he deserves.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_17">
        <text>Yeah. He was a slippery type, but now, he’s dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_18">
        <text>God dammit! And I trusted him all this time… Thanks for opening my eyes. Did that weasel’s PDA contain anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_19">
        <text>Nope. That’s everything. You can have his PDA. It’ll describe everything in more detail.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_2">
        <text>By the fence. Apparently, he went through the teleporter to the north. That’s how I found him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_20">
        <text>M-hmm. He turned out a slippery bastard. Prepare to find that decoder; in all likelihood, it’s just what we need right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_21">
        <text>Don’t worry. I, too, want to find it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_22">
        <text>Great to hear, Beast. As soon as we get more info about it, come to me and we’ll talk. What else was on Scavenger’s PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_23">
        <text>Hm… Well, this is certainly his doing. I’m glad he tried to help us somehow. If you find his stash, bring it to base. We’ll find out what to do with it; it’s not like Scavenger needs it anymore. Did his PDA contain anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_24">
        <text>I’ve already found his stash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_25">
        <text>Oh? Good work, Beast. What did you find in it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_26">
        <text>Munitions, medical supplies, and most importantly, a locked container… and the stash had no key in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_27">
        <text>Mmm-hmm. Hand over that container. I’m gonna give it to Screw; maybe he’ll manage cracking it without a key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_28">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_29">
        <text>I’ll call you as soon as Screw’s done opening it. What else was on the PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_3">
        <text>Yeah… Sad. He was a sharp stalker. Saved us many times…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_30">
        <text>Yeah, turns out we didn’t know much about Scavenger at all… All right. So, Knucklehead was looking for you, and our fellow jarhead told us that he has something to say to you. Go and talk to them. I need some space to deal with my own business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_31">
        <text>All right. I’ll talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_4">
        <text>Scavenger was sharp, but not that sharp. By the way, I forgot to mention something: he had a PDA on him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_5">
        <text>What are you on about, Beast? And throw that thing away. There won’t be any useful on it…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_6">
        <text>As it turns out, it does have quite a few interesting entries.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_7">
        <text>Oh? And what did you find out from Scavenger’s PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_8">
        <text>There’s an entry about him finding some kind of decoder that’s supposed to provide an exit out of the anomaly, but its location isn’t mentioned anywhere.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_9">
        <text>Scavenger kept his most valuable findings away from you and hid it all somewhere, but where exactly, I don’t know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_0">
        <text>Regarding Scavenger: when did he go missing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_1">
        <text>Scavenger went missing two days ago. He picked up on a signal not far from the base, then went to check it out and never got back. I sent a few guys to look for him, Cutter and Mosquito, but they didn’t find him. Instead, what they found was you, but don’t get any wrong ideas; I’m glad you showed up. You helped us eliminate both the zombies and the controller, and for that, Beast, I thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_2">
        <text>No need to thank me. I’ll go comb the area; maybe I’ll find something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_3">
        <text>It’ll mean a lot if you find him. Scavenger was a good stalker. He’s been a great help to us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_4">
        <text>If I find anything, I’ll shoot a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_0">
        <text>I found Scavenger’s stash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_1">
        <text>Oh? What did you find in it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_2">
        <text>Munitions, medical supplies, and most importantly, a locked container… and the stash had no key in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_3">
        <text>Mmm-hmm. Hand over that container. I’m gonna give it to Screw; maybe he’ll manage cracking it without a key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_4">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_5">
        <text>I’ll call you as soon as Screw’s done opening it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_6">
        <text>Got you, Savage. I’ll drop by later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_10">
        <text>Can you tell me something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_11">
        <text>Perhaps I can, seeing as it interests you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_12">
        <text>What do you think about the other residents of the base?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_13">
        <text>What do you think? Are we going to get out of here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_14">
        <text>Who were you before?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_15">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_16">
        <text>I’ll be off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_17">
        <text>What’s there to think? They’re all right people. We’re all different, but the tragedy of this situation applies to us all; we’re united like cement.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_18">
        <text>I don’t know, but even if we do find a way, not everyone will make it. That’s for sure. I’m still amazed that we’ve been able to hold out for this long. Not only do we barely have any grub or munitions, but we have more dangerous concerns. I left the barn the night before yesterday to get some fresh air, and I could smell burning. I thought, “Maybe something’s burning…” but then I saw a huge pillar of smoke, and I could make out someone standing in the center of it. I looked through my binoculars to see who it was, but I couldn’t make out rat shit from dog shit. I decided to take a closer look, and suddenly, there was a laughter. All that smoke was gone, and so was the figure who stood in it. I don’t know what the heck that was, but it sure wasn’t anything good for us. It didn’t bode well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_19">
        <text>I’m a stalker; a loner. I made a living working under Sidorovich, and after that, I set off to Yantar for science. They’ve got regular-paying jobs and medical supplies, and the military doesn’t poke their nose there. What sucks, though, is that those eggheads tend to send you to places so bad that even shit looks good in comparison. Before I ended up in this anomaly, I remember how I went up to an anomaly by myself at Yantar to gather a few specimens, and then all I saw was a white flash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_2">
        <text>Oh, it’s you, merc. Looking better already. Thanks for helping us drive off the zombies.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_3">
        <text>And thanks to you for saving my hide. So, where’d you even find me? Maybe some of my equipment was left behind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_4">
        <text>Of course I remember. How could I not? You won’t find anything there, though. I scouted that place far and wide. Tried finding your stuff by myself, and I also looked a the possibility of an exit from this hellhole, but, as you can see, I’m still here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_5">
        <text>Send the coordinates anyway. I want to see it for myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_6">
        <text>Be my guest. There. You should have it. Check your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_7">
        <text>Thank you. Time to go find my backpack.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_9">
        <text>So, merc, what’ve you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Hey there, merc. I’m glad that you’re okay. I’m basically the local technician. You can bring me broken shooters, and I’ll buy them off you, though I don’t provide any repairs or modifications for free, because in the end, I’m going to get out of this place someday, so I try to gather whatever I can, and I also need to get hold of intact weapons in exchange for any parts. By the way, if you find any tools around here, then bring them to me. I’ll find a way to make use of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Hi, merc. Need anything repaired, or improved?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_5">
        <text>I’ll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Come talk to me if you need anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_0">
        <text>How’s Scavenger’s container doing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_1">
        <text>I opened it. Turns out there are quite a few goodies inside; even a few useful tools, which means I can now work on additional upgrades, but let’s leave that for later. As I told you in my earlier message, you can take some of this stuff for yourself, and I’ll share the rest with the others.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_10">
        <text>Give it to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_11">
        <text>I don’t need that. What else you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_12">
        <text>That’s everything. Not much else is left in the container; only medical supplies and bullets, which I’ll give to Savage. He’ll distribute it among the group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_13">
        <text>No problem. Here’s your shooter. And, by the way, have a few rounds for it as a bonus. They were also in the container. It’s a rare caliber; a type that nobody here uses. Other than that, there are two packs of 5.45x39 mm military armor-piercing ammo. Very useful against armored targets.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_14">
        <text>That’ll come into handy. Give it here</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_15">
        <text>Nah. I don’t need ammo right now. What else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_16">
        <text>All right. Take the ammunition. What else… A Black Angel artifact. Not bad in its qualities; it gives you resistance to psy-fields. You want it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_17">
        <text>Yeah. I’ll take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_18">
        <text>I don’t need it. Anything more?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_19">
        <text>Here. Take the artifact. Not much else is left in the container; only medical supplies and bullets, which I’ll give to Savage. He’ll distribute it among the group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_2">
        <text>Then show me what’s inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_20">
        <text>Inside are two packs of 5.45x39 mm military armor-piercing ammo. Very useful against armored targets.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_21">
        <text>We also have a Black Angel artifact. Not bad in its qualities; it gives you resistance to psy-fields. You want it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_22">
        <text>Great. See you, Screw.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_3">
        <text>Right. Let’s start with a 1PN58 scope. Very useful item. Contains a built-in night vision device, which’ll help you spot targets in the dark. It fits on weapons with dovetail-type rails.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_4">
        <text>I’ll take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_5">
        <text>Don’t need it. Show me more</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_6">
        <text>Mhm. Here’s your scope. Let’s keep looking… Right. Here’s a decent pea-shooter: the FN FNP-45. Not exactly up to date, but its destructive capabilities are not disappointing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_7">
        <text>I’m taking it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_8">
        <text>I have no need for it. What else is there??</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_9">
        <text>Got you. So, here’s a decent pea-shooter: the FN FNP-45. Not exactly up to date, but its destructive capabilities are not disappointing</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_toolkit_1_0">
        <text>I found a few tools. Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_toolkit_1_1">
        <text>You found tools for basic work? They surely won’t be of much use for any fine work, but they’ll be handy nonetheless. Thank you very much, merc. I’ll lower my prices for repairs and upgrades for you. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_toolkit_1_2">
        <text>Deal. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_10">
        <text>Find the assholes!</text> <!-- fix -->
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_12">
        <text>So, merc, are you still occupied with anything? Can you help me out with something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_13">
        <text>Remind me, what help do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_14">
        <text>We could do with fixing the radio transceiver that’s located in this basement. For that, we need to find a working battery and two copper wire coils. It’s gonna take some luck and persistence to find a battery in these parts, but since we ended up here in the first place, I wouldn’t say our chances are too high… Copper wiring should be pretty easy to find somewhere, but without a battery, this thing won’t work. All in all, if you find anything resembling a wire or a battery, bring it to me. I might actually be able to fix this thing, and then you can try to send a signal that’ll reach outside the anomaly. Someone will surely get the signal and help us in some way…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_15">
        <text>You have me on board. If I find anything of note, I’ll bring it to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_16">
        <text>I’m busy right now. We’ll talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_18">
        <text>So, what’s up, merc? Find anything?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_2">
        <text>Hey, merc. See, I’m resting up in here. Decided to go into the basement so that I don’t keep being an eyesore for the others. I think it’ll be better for everyone that way, including me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_20">
        <text>I happened to find a battery all along. Another “lucky man” ended up in the anomaly and shared what he had.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_21">
        <text>I’ve found two coils of copper wiring.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_22">
        <text>Sad to hear about the stalker, but he’s helped us big time. I’d say I’m glad that he ended up here. So, hand me the battery. You sure it’s in working condition?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_23">
        <text>Here you go. It’s hard to say whether it works; he snatched it from a broken radio transceiver, but let’s hope for the best.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_24">
        <text>Here you go. It’s hard to say whether it works; he snatched it from a broken radio transceiver, but let’s hope for the best.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_25">
        <text>Okay. Let’s see… Yeah. That should do it. It’s just that even if this thing works, I can’t get it to restart yet. Got no copper wiring to replace the already fried wiring in here. Try to find two coils with copper wiring, and then we’ll try to get this pile of trash working.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_26">
        <text>Okay. Let’s see… Yeah. That should do it. If everything works out and the transceiver successfully restarts, I can send a signal for help beyond the anomaly. Come back to me in about twenty minutes. In the meantime, I’ll try to replace all the fried wiring.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_27">
        <text>Okay. I’ll come back in twenty minutes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_29">
        <text>Hey there, merc. Let’s talk a bit later, you and I. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_3">
        <text>Well, that’s relatively good news. Savage told me you wanted to have a chat with me. Is that right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_30">
        <text>All right. I’m going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_32">
        <text>Hey there, merc. What is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_33">
        <text>Ah, it’s you, merc. Got any questions for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_34">
        <text>Hey, merc. I’m all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_35">
        <text>Nope. Haven’t found anything yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_36">
        <text>Excellent, merc. Hand me the wiring. Too bad that not much will come out of it without a battery…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_37">
        <text>Here you go. Regarding the battery, I’ll try to figure something out, though it seems more and more that we won’t be able to find anything that’ll work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_38">
        <text>Well, in any case, keep me updated. All right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_39">
        <text>Yeah. I’ll be going now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_4">
        <text>Yes, merc. Got a bit of an important task for you. I’ve found out that the radio transceiver that’s been lying in this basement can be fixed; I’ve had my moments with such devices before. The main thing of note is its broken battery, as well as some of the wiring having fried. I could use a couple of rolls with copper wiring and a new battery. Once I have all that, I might be able to breathe some life into that thing. It might save our day; if we get it working, we might be able to send a signal outside the borders of this forsaken anomaly, and if anyone gets the signal, maybe they can help us escape.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_40">
        <text>Excellent, merc. Hand me the copper wiring and come back to me in about twenty minutes. I’ll try to get the battery and the fried wiring replaced.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_41">
        <text>Here’s the wiring. I’ll come back in twenty minutes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_42">
        <text>All right. I’ll try to find the wiring for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_44">
        <text>Come back in a little while, merc. I still need to get this thing repaired.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_46">
        <text>I managed to fix the damn transceiver after all. Now, we need to find someone that we can broadcast the signal to. That’ll be my business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_47">
        <text>Did you pick up anything useful while you were fixing the transceiver?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_48">
        <text>It doesn’t seem like I’ve picked up anything. Might be a few phrases here and there along with some unintelligble muttering, but there are more than likely old broadcasts. I’ll keep scanning for any more signals, but nonetheless, thanks, merc, for helping me repair the transmitter. Who knows? Maybe it’ll can help us get out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_49">
        <text>No need to thank me. We’re all together in this. I’ll see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_5">
        <text>Good idea, but where am I going to find a battery, and one that still works, at that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_6">
        <text>I’m busy right now. Let’s discuss that later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_7">
        <text>I’m just giving us options, merc. It’s gonna take some luck and persistence to find a battery in these parts, but since we ended up here in the first place, I wouldn’t say our chances are too high… Two rolls of copper wiring should be pretty easy to find somewhere, but without a battery, this thing won’t work. All in all, if you find anything resembling a wire or a battery, bring it to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_8">
        <text>You have me on board. If I find anything of note, I’ll bring it to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_9">
        <text>What help do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_final_2">
        <text>Hey there, merc. What is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_final_3">
        <text>Ah, it’s you, merc. Got any questions for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_final_4">
        <text>Hey, merc. I’m all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_10">
        <text>Damn… Man… Give me a medkit, or I’m riding the pale horse…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_11">
        <text>We’re here… Thanks for the help. Who knows what would’ve happened if you didn’t come by. I’m feeling a bit better now. Can you tell me where we are? What is this place?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_12">
        <text>Have you ever heard about space bubbles?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_13">
        <text>Well, I’ve heard things, and I know what they do in general terms. What about them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_14">
        <text>Congratulations: you’re in a spatial anomaly right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_15">
        <text>Well, then… Sucks that they sent us to fly today of all days… And most importantly, how the hell did we even end up here? This place never appeared in any of our maps. Whatever. What’s done is done. And, as I understand it, you haven’t found any way out of the anomaly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_16">
        <text>Nope. So far, not a thing. Where are the other soldiers who were in the helicopter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_17">
        <text>Just great… The chopper crew was most likely torn apart. Me, though… Seems like I got lucky. God damn aerial anomaly. Thanks to it, all electronics were fried in seconds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_18">
        <text>Yeah. Anyway, get better, soldier. We’ll be needing your help soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_20">
        <text>All right. I’ll see if your shooter’s still around.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_23">
        <text>Hey there, merc. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_3">
        <text>I’m finished… Man… Man, finish it. I won’t last…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_4">
        <text>Just you wait. I might be able to help you still.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_5">
        <text>You think I still have a chance? This pain is hellish… I can’t handle it… Relieve my suffering…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_6">
        <text>You’ll live; I’ve seen worse. First, we need to get you a medkit, so that I can get you back to base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_7">
        <text>Alright… Do whatever you want… Just… Just make this pain stop… Give me your medkit…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_8">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_9">
        <text>I don’t have any medkit right now, but I’ll find one.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="super_0">
        <text>default text</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
