<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_0">
        <text>Tell me something interesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_1">
        <text>So one time I was with my team in Garbage and we were inspecting some old hangar. Everything was covered in dust and cobwebs, the place looked like shit. Our detectors stopped working; our PDAs couldn’t even show our own position. We occupied our usual positions: Sanyok scouting the front with us covering his back. Everything was going smoothly until all of a sudden, a bunch of metal beams fell from the roof. Sanyok managed to dodge them by some miracle. He fell, rolled back and without even standing back up started firing. The others were also scared shitless, and those idiots started shooting everywhere. Then, Sanyok started yelling something about a creature sitting in the corner. There was nothing there when I looked though.\n \nEither way, it was clear that our operation was fucked. What happened after that was a total mess. Everyone was panicked, shooting at nothing thinking they saw something. Two of them were really unlucky. One guy was walking on what appeared to be flat ground until he disappeared down a dark hole. The other guy was crushed by a heavy metal door; his spine was turned into mush. After a while, we finally got our shit together, put on our psy-protection and tossed a smoke grenade towards every corner in hopes of luring the creature to the center. Well, it turned out this beast could fly and while we were all losing our shit on the ground, that bitch was just sitting up there watching us.\n \nBy the time we figured it out, it was too late. The beast knocked loose a few more steel beams from the scaffolding and splattered four of our guys. In the meantime, Sanyok heard ruffling in the rafters and fired in its direction without a second thought… Incredible reflexes. The beast screeched, and we started shooting where Sanyok landed his shot, bringing the bitch to the ground. Its bloodcurdling screeches left my ears ringing. Even after we ran out of ammo we kept beating the shit out of the creature with anything we could find, Sanyok finishing off the creature with his knife. When we were through, the beast was splattered all over the floor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_10">
        <text>That’s one hell of a story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_11">
        <text>You wanna know what I think? Or rather what I’m guessing? Maybe… Maybe all of this is just an experiment on humanity done by aliens. It kind of makes sense when you think about it… more than any of the other rumors people spread about this place. You know what’s interesting? Why did the Zone emerge here out of all places? If this place was just some military experiment, then why isn’t it better guarded and hidden? Are they checking which artifacts we want the most? What if these artifacts are actually bombs? Think about it: these artifacts are popping up in laboratories all over the world and in the hands of rich people. That would be cool, if some rich asshole would buy an artifact just to have it explode in his face. Ha ha ha!… anyway, who knows what’s really going on? The only people who really know are those made it past Radar. Yeah… They might know. Too bad they can’t say anything. All they do is moan and drool all day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_12">
        <text>Yeah, anything is possible here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_13">
        <text>We used to have this idiot with us. He was the laziest fuck to ever make it into the Zone. Whenever it was break time he was the first one near the campfire but when shit was about to go down he couldn’t be bothered to help out. Eventually, his laziness got him killed. His team spotted a controller and he couldn’t be bothered to get up from the warm campfire to save his own ass. The controller fried up his brains.  People forget that this is the Zone and you can’t drop your guard here, not even for a second. You need to pay attention to every noise no matter how insignificant you think it is. You need to keep your guns cocked and loaded and your grenades ready to go. As for controllers, that’s a different story altogether. They’ll kill you before you even realize it. If you ever see a controller, even in the distance, get to cover immediately. They need to see you in order for them to start frying your brain and even when they see you they need a few seconds to concentrate. Once you are in cover lay down some suppressive fire and throw a few grenades to hold back the controller and distract him. While it’s busy figuring where all of that lead just came from, you run… Run as fast and as far away as possible. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_14">
        <text>Thanks for the story. I’ll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_15">
        <text>Yeah, somebody told me about something the other day and I can’t remember what… Oh, yeah! Even though there are plenty of interesting materials in the Zone - the type any scientist would go crazy over - foreign scientists won’t go anywhere near the Zone. There are several reasons for it: first, why go yourself when you can hire a stalker for a small amount of cash to do your dirty work for you? Second, back a few years ago, there was actually a huge expedition from abroad that ended really badly… What, you didn’t hear about it? Strange…\n \nBack when it happened, everybody in the Zone was talking about it. The expedition had 30 scientists from all over the world coming here. They all had a shitload of money and the best gear out there. They had a special military unit escorting them, mind you, these weren’t just regular grunts, I’m talking elite soldiers. They also hired some of our guides, three very experienced stalkers, to guide the way and they took a BTR just for the fuck of it. When they got back a week later, that BTR was wrecked to shit. It turned out the expedition was ambushed by bandit raiders who killed almost everyone from that expedition save for three people, two of our guides and one foreign scientist. That same scientist was severely traumatized and he had to be hospitalized in a mental institution.  Right now he’s writing some kind of book about the Zone, and as for our guys, well, they just shrugged it off. Though, being honest, I think they went through some trauma as well. One guy went to Radar and disappeared and as for the other one, well, he just left the Zone.\n \nYou’re probably wondering how such a force could be taken down by a just a bandit ambush. That’s not the whole story, though.\n \nHave you heard anything about City 32? They say that’s where the people of the expedition started to lose their mind. Some kind of mass hysteria spread from person to person and everyone started to lose their shit at the same time. Some even started scratching their throats out while others bashed their head on the wall. A few just shot themselves in the head instantly. To make matters worse - at the same time, a flock of large mutants showed up. Anyone who hadn’t yet lost their mind fled to nearby houses and barricaded themselves in. Can you imagine the situation? It’s midnight and pitch black outside, everyone has lost their minds, and at the same time a flock of powerful mutants is about to have you for dinner. Those who didn’t lose their sanity spent the entire night locked in abandoned houses waiting for morning to come. When morning finally came, chances were already slim. Some died in anomalies on the way back, and the rest encountered those bandits… I already told you how that ended. Since then, no scientific expedition has dared to set foot in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_16">
        <text>Thanks for the story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_17">
        <text>So I was in Dark Valley once and I wanted to scan the area from somewhere high. I found place where I could climb up, a chimney in a boiler station. So I entered the station, looked around and the coast seemed clear. I found the chimney and started climbing up - there was a ladder inside it already, so it was real easy. I was climbing up at my own ease since the ladder was real sturdy and comfortable. When I got to the top I slowly lifted myself on top of the chimney to get a better look. And man, what a beautiful view… It felt like the entire Dark Valley was in my hands. I took out my binoculars and started scanning the area, everything seemed clear.\n \nJust as I was about to climb back down, it occurred to me that I should check what was happening beneath my feet. So I looked down around the station and man what do I see: A burer! Good thing I didn’t go down, I would have dead for sure. Lucky for me he didn’t see me yet or I wouldn’t be here to tell the tale. I wanted to snipe him with my AK but the chimney I climbed up from was way too thin and the AK was stuck on my back. As for trying to hit him with my Makarov, that’s almost impossible. Plus if I miss, and I will miss, the burer will notice me right away and kill me. So I was stuck there thinking of what to do while the burer was messing around in the station, throwing some metal garbage around. This continued about a minute until the dwarf froze in place, like he was listening in on something. Then the garbage started to move on its own and the burer jumped back and put his hands to his head in a very awkward position. Suddenly all the metal scrap in the building flew right into the burer, burying him underneath. I thought to myself, I am finally saved, that fucker is dead!\n \nBut no… That pile of trash was only still for a few seconds before it started to move again. Eventually the crap started to fly around in the air and then it flew into a nearby wall, smashing it with immense force. Then the burer entered a different building and I thought to myself, "It’s time to get the fuck out of here." Just as I began to climb down I started to smell smoke and feel intense heat. I look below me, and what do I see?… There’s a fire inside the fucking chimney! I was starting to suffocate so I climbed on top of the chimney where I could at least get some air. Mind you, the smoke was still irritating my eyes. Good thing I always carry 40 meter paracord with me, because I knew the only way out was to rappel down the chimney from the outside. I made a knot at the chimney and tied the rope around my waist and legs and slowly started to rappel down. The only thing that was going through my head at the time: Please don’t rip. The rope was cutting into my hands as I made my way down, but it didn’t rip. However, just as Murphy’s Law predicts, the rope was 5 meters too short and I had no choice but to cut myself free and fall the rest of the way down. Thankfully I didn’t break anything but I got torn up bad and busted up my right leg. I thought I ripped a tendon or something. I ran out of there as fast I could despite my leg hurting. Hell, I could’ve have won gold medal with that speed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_18">
        <text>Damn, that’s intense.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_19">
        <text>Sorry, merc. I’m all out of stories.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_2">
        <text>Interesting story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_20">
        <text>Come back another time, perhaps I’ll have something more interesting to tell you then…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_3">
        <text>Have you heard about Guide? The very first true stalker. He was the one who originally broke into the Zone and he’s still alive. People say he can take you to any place, you just need to name it. Now, finding him’s a bit tricky, ain’t no posters around with his address… And he won’t go with just anybody, either. From what I hear, he charges quite a bit. But if you find him and have enough cash, you can rest assured he’ll take you where you need to go. Now, that’s someone I’d like to have a chat with. You can bet he’s been past Red Forest…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_4">
        <text>Interesting information, thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_5">
        <text>They say there’s this one gang… People call them Shamans or Druids. It’s said they don’t use any electronic equipment at all, they want to stay close to the nature and stuff… Well, they reason the Zone reacts stronger to equipment… To all this "electromagnetic emissions" or something… They say it attracts monsters. Basically, they believe the Zone is like a living being, you know. Like, it’s no good going into it with all these gadgets. If you’re right in your mind you’ll get by fine without ‘em. Doesn’t stop them from carrying assault rifles, though… Guess the old teeth and nails are not up to the task, eh? But then again, you don’t hear a lot of stories about one of them kicking the bucket. Well, at least no more than about us… So, who knows, maybe they are on the right track there… They seem to be coming more from the Belarussian side, though… I’d like to have a look at them one day and check out their pockets for some artifacts…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_6">
        <text>Thanks for the story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_7">
        <text>Have you heard anything about the secret laboratories that are located deep within the Zone? Some say that they are still active. How the hell do this labs still remain active nobody knows, considering the fact that people can’t survive there due to lack of resources. Here’s a possibility: What if it’s not people working there but ghosts? I talked to this one guy, he hadn’t been in the laboratory himself but he did manage to catch some signals on his radio when he was in Yantar. He caught a conversation about some kind of laboratory. Another guy swore that he saw some kind of transparent figure when he was in Radar. It had some kind of upgraded SEVA suit and it told him to get the hell out of there and that he was interrupting some kind of important project.  Although it was awfully close to the scorcher so the whole thing could have been a hallucination for all we know… On the other hand, there different kinds of mutations, maybe the Zone turned those lab workers into something else…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_8">
        <text>No idea. Anything is possible in this hellhole.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dm_say_me_story_9">
        <text>Yo merc you know anything about the Interception group? It’s a highly skilled special unit the goes on missions deep inside the Zone. They’re nothing like the dipshits we have here in cordon, these are real pros. Not only do they go into the most dangerous places inside the Zone but they stay there for months. They have a few hidden bases throughout the Zone and they have plenty of stashes to boot. They also get supply drops from a helicopter if they need it. Their commander’s last name is Gromov. I am sure it’s just a fake name. What you don’t believe? Belly caught their frequency once but he immediately turned it off and ran off. This is top secret info after all and he could have been shot just for listening in on it. Man their pay though, it’s something else. If I had a third, no, a tenth of their pay I could just retire somewhere in Sochi. They even have some kind of special device that can locate mutants from a far, no matter what kind. Some say that they even travel into the center of the Zone while others say they’ve learned how to tame mutants. There are also rumors that these guys aren’t military but rather they are highly gifted stalker who signed a contract with the government. Duty knows all about them but they won’t talk those assholes… They say it’s all rumors but trust me, they know better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_0">
        <text>Don’t move! Password, now!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_1">
        <text>Swordfish. You might want take your finger off that trigger before you hurt yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_10">
        <text>Almost. Valerian’s got a friend by the name of Belly. If he dies, we won’t be disappointed, and you’ll receive an additional bonus for disposing of him. After you complete the mission, contact me. I’ll show you where to meet us again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_11">
        <text>Understood. I’m moving.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_2">
        <text>Okay. You must be Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_3">
        <text>Yep. Let’s get straight to the point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_4">
        <text>Let us. You probably know about the stalker base that’s by the railroad. Well, we need to get rid of their leader—for good.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_5">
        <text>Can’t you take him out yourself? I’d think all these soldiers could take on a stalker base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_6">
        <text>We have our reasons. The thing is, we can’t kill every stalker in that base. That’ll attract too much attention. We need someone to eliminate Valerian without alerting anyone else. After that, the stalker base will fall apart on its own. I don’t care how you take him out as long as you do it quickly. This has to been done in no longer than three days.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_7">
        <text>What’s the pay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_8">
        <text>Oh, don’t worry about that. The pay is good. You’ll get it once you finish the job—we don’t pay in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_dialog_kill_valeryan_9">
        <text>Is that all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_0">
        <text>Someone must’ve heard the gunfire. They probably told their men they were going to inspect the area around this vehicle station. This could cause some serious problems… What are your orders, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_1">
        <text>Don’t get too worked up, Raven; these aren’t Wolf’s people. We already informed the rookie village about our arrival. We should find out who sent those men here. And also, get rid of the bodies.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_2">
        <text>I’ll get on it. Anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_3">
        <text>We need to have a word with Wolf and see if he knows anything about this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_4">
        <text>Leave it to me. I’ll talk to the stalkers and see what they know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_killer_raven_meet_to_dead_5">
        <text>I’m with you. I need to see Sidorovich and make sure he doesn’t find out that his job is just a cover.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_0">
        <text>Yeah? What the hell is so important that I can’t even lay down for twenty minutes without being bothered again?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_1">
        <text>A job. Get up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_10">
        <text>Yeah, that would work… Do you have any tips on gaining their trust and listening in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_11">
        <text>Christ. Act new and confused, and shorten information mentally. Avoid writing notes in plain sight. Write them when you know for sure you’re alone. Use acronyms to make your notes less incriminating if they find them. And remember that you have thirty million reasons to do your job well, if you ever want to actually make profit off of your assignments.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_12">
        <text>R-Right. You can trust me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_13">
        <text>The target’s name is Father Valerian. After you’re done, go to the bus station near the grain elevator. Set up a low-visibility camp there and wait until I dead drop you further instructions. And don’t let me down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_2">
        <text>Oh, is that you, Beast? I didn’t recognize you for a second. Sorry. What’s the job entail?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_3">
        <text>Gaining entry into that free stalker base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_4">
        <text>That’s what they have the Syndicate doing nowadays?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_5">
        <text>I wasn’t done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_6">
        <text>Oh. Sorry. Continue.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_7">
        <text>Once you’re in, *quietly* take out their leader and return. Gather basic information on their guard shift pattern, defensive location, armaments, and combat capabilities. Listen in on some of their conversations and see if they have any information we don’t, and then go in for the kill.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_8">
        <text>Uh, that’s a tall order for one agent, let alone a conscript. Not to mention I can’t get within ten feet feet of the base perimeter without fifty barrels aiming at me, so I would need extra equipment to make a disguise. How am I supposed to do this just as-is? They’ll know something’s wrong if I’ve got a fancy, unrusted gun but just a sweater.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_9">
        <text>It’s your duty as a member of the Syndicate to carry out your jobs no matter what kind of obstacles you face, regardless of whether you’re an agent or not. You’re contractually bound to handle these things with little to no outside support. You must act accordingly. Store your issued equipment in a well-concealed spot near the base in case you absolutely have to get to it quickly, scavenge a basic pistol off of someone, and make yourself look like a rookie. Gain their trust, thrust your knife into the leader’s carotid artery, clean up the blood spatter, and then leave without anyone knowing. The standard three-step-assault procedure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_0">
        <text>Hey, merc. I take it you are the leader of the group at the ATP? Thanks for saving us from the bandits, you guys are real pros.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_1">
        <text>My partner told me that you want join the syndicate, is that true?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_2">
        <text>Yeah, it’s true. I am tired of working my ass off for pocket change. I want to make some real money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_3">
        <text>Alright, but first you have to do a job for me. A test of loyalty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_4">
        <text>What do I need to do? I'm ready for anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_5">
        <text>I need you to have the mechanic leave his workshop. Distract him, lead him away. It doesn't matter how, just get it done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_6">
        <text>Hmm… I need to think. There might be one way, although he will only be gone for a short while. I can go to the bar and get drunk with him. Won't be the first time I get him under the influence. Will that work?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_7">
        <text>Yeah, as long as he empties more bottles than he could handle. Do you have enough cash?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_8">
        <text>Yeah, that won’t be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_enot_first_9">
        <text>All right, get to it. Make sure he's passed out by night time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_0">
        <text>Are you busy? Do you have time to talk?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_1">
        <text>No, I haven't got anything to do right now. I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_10">
        <text>Fine, it’s your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_2">
        <text>Do you need anyone to guard this place? Don’t you have anywhere to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_3">
        <text>Do you want something to drink? I have a spare bottle of vodka that I've been keeping for a special occasion.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_4">
        <text>Aren’t you tired? Don’t you want to take a nap for a little while? I can ask the bouncer to come guard the workshop while you're gone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_5">
        <text>Ain't that a strange question… No, I don’t need to go anywhere and if I did I would send someone else to do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_6">
        <text>No, thank you. I don’t want any vodka. I don’t want sit here drunk off my ass while there is a special order waiting to be done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_7">
        <text>Hmm… Why do you care exactly? No, I don’t want to sleep. I’ve had 8 energy drinks and I have the whole night ahead to work on a special order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_8">
        <text>Whatever, It’s your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_furgon_9">
        <text>Alright, It’s your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_0">
        <text>Greetings, mercenary. Did everything go according to plan?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_1">
        <text>Wait, where’s the lieutenant?  Or... Are you the one who ordered the contract?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_2">
        <text>Yes, indeed. I sent Yarishchuk to talk to you yesterday, just as a security measure, no offense, and I wanted to meet you personally today. So, how did everything go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_3">
        <text>Smooth as butter, Valerian and his friends are dead. Here’s the proof.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_4">
        <text>Thank god that asshole is finally dead. Good work, merc. By the way, do you know a guy by the name of Scar? He's one of yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_5">
        <text>Nope, Don’t know him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_6">
        <text>That’s too bad.  He was also a professional, like you. It’s a shame he disappeared somewhere, no one knows where. Yeah I still remember how I was locked up in that base and Scar helped me escape. Man, That Valerian sure caused a lot of problems, to me, to the stalkers he claimed that he protected, and to Sidorovich. I was almost thrown in jail because of that cretin. Hell, we are still under investigation. Anyway, here’s your payment, you did a damn fine job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_halezky_7">
        <text>Goodbye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_11">
        <text>Hey, merc. Keep this conversation quiet, we can’t let anyone hear about this. Jackal has a very serious mission for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_12">
        <text>So you're the coordinator? I thought a secretive person like you would be doing something more serious than guarding a bar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_13">
        <text>How about you stop fucking around and work on how you’re going to execute your mission. You have no idea how hard it was to work under this cover. For three weeks, I had to act like regular security guard just so they would start trusting me. All so I could get the needed info for your ungrateful ass.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_14">
        <text>Fine, tell me then, what Jackal has in store for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_15">
        <text>Okay, so about a month ago, Sidorovich managed to get his hands on a locked “Black Box” which was retrieved from a fallen military helicopter and someone’s willing to pay good money for it. Your mission is to steal the “Black Box”. Sidorovich keeps it in his storage room which is located here. Your main obstacle is Van, the local Technician, his workplace is near the entrance and you must neutralize him in order to get through. Van keeps drinking energy drinks and he barely sleeps… Oh and an important detail, you mustn’t kill him, it will attract too much attention. You only need to make sure he's passed out long enough for you to get the “Black Box”. Meanwhile, I will make sure the storage room door “accidentally” opens.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_16">
        <text>All right, if that’s everything, I’m going to discuss the mission with my partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_17">
        <text>One more thing, this needs to be done tonight! So hurry up and do what you got to do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_18">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_19">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_2">
        <text>So, merc… How’s our mission going? Have you gotten the “black box” yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_3">
        <text>Yeah, Here it is. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_4">
        <text>Excellent, you did your job well; the syndicate will take note of your success here. I’ll prepare an alibi for you in case Sidorovich gets suspicious and starts pointing the finger at you. Also, Jackal called, he said that he has another mission for you that’s ordered by the military</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_5">
        <text>What’s the mission?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_6">
        <text>I have no idea. You will get all of your instructions from a representative of the client and remember, most important of all, In order for the military to identify you as their contractor you will need to say the password: “swordfish”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_7">
        <text>All right, Give the coordinates for the meeting point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_koordinator_9">
        <text>I have given you everything I have. I don’t have no more info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_0">
        <text>What up, Creature! He-he… So how’s Sidorovich’s contract going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_1">
        <text>Have you forgotten who's in command here? Call me “creature” again and I’ll break your fucking jaw!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_2">
        <text>Yeah, sure you will. Though, you should probably remember what Jackal said about that… You remember, right? Anyway, back to the point, I called you here for a reason. You see, Jackal has gotten tired of waiting for you to do his personal contract, so he made someone else in charge and you, Creature, are supposed to drop everything and start doing his mission. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_3">
        <text>Like that, huh? Who did he put in charge by the way?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_4">
        <text>Me, In the meantime. But once Sidorovich’s contract is done Jackal will pick a new permanent commander. I don’t get one thing though, why the hell did he pick an idiot like you in the first place. You couldn’t even secure a good place for your team, not to mention your awful execution of the contracts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_5">
        <text>Me, in the meantime, but once Sidorovich’s contract is done Jackal will pick a constant commander. I don’t get one thing though, why the hell did he pick an idiot like you in the first place. You couldn’t even secure a good place for your team, not to mention your awful execution of the contracts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_mrakobes_6">
        <text>That’s none of your business… Anyway, tell Jackal that I will get his contract done. I’ll find Vektor and kill him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_2">
        <text>Hello, merc. What’s up? Do you have Sidorovich’s package?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_3">
        <text>Yeah, I have it. Pay me first, then you'll get the package.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_4">
        <text>Heh, how careful of you… Don’t worry, I am not Sidorovich and when I say that I am going to pay someone, I pay that someone. Give me the package and I’ll give you the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_5">
        <text>Alright, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_6">
        <text>Okay, take your money. Take note of the fact that I've paid you twice the amount Sidorovich asked to pay you, I have my reasons. I have a feeling I’ll be stuck here for a while. Valerian has disappeared somewhere and its uncertain wither he will return or not and someone has to keep things in order here. Anyway, our trader needs your help. He asked to send you over to him. Go talk to him, see what he wants. He should pay you more than I have.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_7">
        <text>Okay, I’ll see what he wants.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_orest_9">
        <text>Good day, merc. Any news?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_10">
        <text>One of our squads hasn’t responded for a few minutes. I fear something happened to them. I don’t have anyone else to send, so will you lend me a hand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_11">
        <text>Of course I can lend you a hand... For a price.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_12">
        <text>Almost forgot who I’m talking to… We don’t have a lot of time for negotiations, Beast, so could you find those men ASAP? We’ll discuss payment after your return.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_13">
        <text>I’ll hold you to it. Where do I need to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_14">
        <text>They went over the hill, toward one of our outposts, but the problem is, that area was overrun with bandits not long ago. I see your gear is quite advanced, unlike ours, so a few bandits should be a piece of cake. I’ll mark the area on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_15">
        <text>Got it. I’ll find your men.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_17">
        <text>Any news, merc? Did you find the missing squad?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_19">
        <text>Get out of here, merc!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_2">
        <text>Greetings, merc. I take it you received my message? I’m Wolf. To tell you the truth, we’re not really happy with your presence in these parts… I know you’re here on Sidorovich’s orders and all, but let’s try and make each others’ lives easier. Try not to meddle in anything that doesn’t concern you or your group in the Cordon. Understood?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_20">
        <text>I’ll get going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_21">
        <text>Not yet, I’m on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_23">
        <text>Great job! Zokhan told me the whole story: about you saving him and his entire squad. I would never have thought a group of mercenaries would save our boys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_24">
        <text>No need to thank me. Just pay me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_25">
        <text>No, I feel I should, since mercs don’t care about anyone but themselves, from what I've seen. You, though… You’re something else. You actually do seem to care.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_26">
        <text>Don’t get the wrong idea. I’m only here to do my job and nothing more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_27">
        <text>I got the message. Anyway, here’s the payment for the job. I don’t have a lot of money on me, so here’s an artifact as well. Hope it’ll be useful.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_28">
        <text>That all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_29">
        <text>Yeah, that’s—oh, I almost forgot: Sidorovich told me he’s ready to take you. And, thanks again for your help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_3">
        <text>Understood. I’m Beast, and this is Raven. Thanks for the warm welcome. What’s up with Sidorovich?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_30">
        <text>All right. I’ll get going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_32">
        <text>Hello, merc. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_4">
        <text>Sadly, the old man’s doing all right, but you’ll have to wait a while. He’s got some important business to attend to, and he won’t let anyone in his bunker for the time being.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_5">
        <text>When can I see him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_6">
        <text>Not any time soon, that’s for sure. Sidorovich likes to take his sweet time with his business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_7">
        <text>We’ll be on our way then. Please inform me when Sidorovich has a moment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_8">
        <text>Wait, wait. Hold up. Can you help me with something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_meet_from_wolf_9">
        <text>Tell what that “something” is, and then we’ll see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_0">
        <text>Listen, Beast, I didn’t call you here just to chit-chat. Not everyone’s accepting the fact that Jackal made you head of the group, especially Obscurant. He flew off the handle when he heard the news, and he’s not the only one who wanted to be in your position. Just be careful—who knows what goes on in that man’s head. He’s a dangerous, unpredictable man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_1">
        <text>Thanks for your concern, but I can handle it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_2">
        <text>Of course. Just be aware of the general consensus. If Jackal made you the commander, he must’ve had a specific reason, despite the disagreement of a number of individuals. A few well-done contracts will help strengthen your reputation, though.\n \nBy the way, we just got word from Vulture that an unknown group of stalkers is heading toward the base. They’ve ignored our warnings not to come here. Either way, it’s your call what to do with them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_3">
        <text>All right. I’ll talk to them. Is that all?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_4">
        <text>No, that’s not all: the locals won’t be happy about our arrival here. If we want to stay on good terms with the area, we shouldn’t poke our noses into everything. The only place that welcomes us right now is the rookie village, but you know that already. That’s about it. I won’t keep you any longer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_5">
        <text>Thanks for the briefing. I’ll go deal with our visitors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_0">
        <text>You the man in charge here? What the hell are you doing in the Cordon? You know that mercs aren’t allowed here… or am I mistaken?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_1">
        <text>Indeed you are. The less you know, the better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_2">
        <text>Listen here, merc: either you tell me what the hell you’re doing here or things are going to get ugly real quick. This isn’t your place, you don’t make the rules here, and if I were you, I’d fess up right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_3">
        <text>Was that a threat? What the hell are the three of you going to do against an entire platoon of mercenaries?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_4">
        <text>We’ll slaughter you all if it comes to that. Now state your business here! We don’t want any trouble now, do we?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_5">
        <text>Our business is our business, none of your business. Last chance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_6">
        <text>*Your* last chance, you spineless piece of shit… You come into our territory making these crazy demands, and now you expect to get away with it? Nobody walks this territory but us, and you’re going to suffer the consequences.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_start_memmory_meet_to_stalker_atp_7">
        <text>Too bad. I warned you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_0">
        <text>Hey there, merc! What brings you here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_1">
        <text>I can ask you the same question. What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_10">
        <text>A psy-dog. I won’t give you its tail, but you can keep everything else. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_11">
        <text>Deal! Let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_2">
        <text>Me? I’m hunting a mutant. I’ve been tracking this creature all the way from the Agroprom, and no matter what I try, it always manages to slip away. This mutant is dangerous, but I have taken a mission from the scientists at Yantar, and I have to complete it. So anyway, I was sneaking up to it here as it was eating a dead stalker and the second it saw me, it ran away. That poor stalker suffered a terrible death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_3">
        <text>I was looking for that stalker, did you search his body?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_4">
        <text>I searched him but I didn’t take anything, there wasn’t much to take. I’m just here trying to figure out where that mutant went.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_5">
        <text>When you were searching him, did you run across a flashdrive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_6">
        <text>So that’s why you’re here… Sorry to break it to you, there was no flashdrive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_7">
        <text>But?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_8">
        <text>There’s a chance that the mutant swallowed the flashdrive along with the guy’s leg. Since we don’t have any better option, I suggest we start looking for that mutant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_9">
        <text>Yeah, okay, but first tell me what type of mutant we’re hunting here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_after_quest_0">
        <text>Oof, that was a strong one.  I can finally wrap this mission up and get my reward from the scientists. How about you, did you find your flashdrive? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_after_quest_1">
        <text>Yeah, you were right, the mutant ate it. Good thing that it didn’t start digesting the flashdrive yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_after_quest_2">
        <text>It takes long to digest a flashdrive, so I wouldn’t worry about that. Alright, I have to get moving, I have to haul my ass all the way to Yantar now.  Goodbye, merc and thanks for the help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_actor_talk_from_hunter_after_quest_3">
        <text>Goodbye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_tick_start_dialog_text">
        <text>Yeah. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_0">
        <text>Wanna chit-chat a bit, while there aren’t any clients to bother you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1">
        <text>Sure. What do you want to know?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_11">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_111">
        <text>I’ve been buying and selling shit since before the fall of the Soviet Union. I was one of those “evil speculators”, and I used to buy and sell serious shit, the real deal. That was until I got caught and thrown in jail, that is. After that, I made friends with professional thieves in jail and started running with them when I got out. Got locked up again for another 3 years, and when I got out, the Soviet Union was already gone. Once I was free, it felt like a totally different world in which I couldn’t find my place in. For a long time, all I did was small time work and I was barely able to scrap together a living. Then the Zone appeared and there I found my place.  Everything here is like the old days, and with my experience in trading, I will always able to make good living here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1111">
        <text>Cool. Tell me something else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_1112">
        <text>Alright, I got to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_12">
        <text>What do you think about Logoped?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_121">
        <text>I’ll tell you this: Logoped won’t stay on top for long. I have a gut feeling that Koba will make him disappear. Logoped keeps showing off and, by the looks of it, he thinks he's untouchable. What’s worse he can’t notice the fact that a good chunk of us are getting sick of his shit. Remember though, I am telling you this because I trust you and this conversation needs to stay between us.  By the way, if you find anything interesting about either Logoped or Koba, bring it here. Keep in mind though, it doesn’t matter who’s in control, I’ll still be here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_13">
        <text>Tell me about Garbage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_131">
        <text>Yeah, the guys weren’t happy about heading to the Garbage. Back then, nobody even thought about going there and avoided those radioactive heaps of junk like the piles of shit that they are. That was until a few stalkers decided to start digging through those mounds of junk, and after that everyone flocked there. At first there was massive chaos there, but then the bandits came, and they put everyone in their place. I think the Zone should be like any other “Zone”, with a clear hierarchy and firm rule, either instilled by cops or by bandits. Hedgehog here also pays to keep the peace around here and we get a good cut out of everything. We need to eat too. Maybe one day I will visit the Garbage myself, even though this place isn’t half bad, there’s some serious cash flowing through Garbage right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_14">
        <text>What's the latest news in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_141">
        <text>I don’t like that expression, “latest news”. If I were you I would stop asking around, before one of those "latest news" become your last. Even though the people here aren’t that bad, not long ago something really fucked up happened. A stalker came in here, all scared shitless, pale and his hands were shaking. He and his friend were running away from a group of poltergeists and they ran into a flock of rodents. I think the wave of hairless rats were so terrible, that the guy got scared and shot his friend a few times in the back. So then, the rodents, instead of running after him decided to just eat his dead bro. The guy that came back, after he drank his second bottle started crying his heart out. “Igor, you gave me your last medkit that one time, and I killed you like the last piece of shit on earth”. He was crying all day long and when the night came he hung himself on his belt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_15">
        <text>Yeah, not that interesting really.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bandit_trader_questions_151">
        <text>Whatever you say.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_bar_0">
        <text>Why is this place called Bar No92?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_bar_1">
        <text>It’s simply because in the periodic table of elements, No 92 is Uranium, which is usually used in nuclear reactors. I think it was Sidorovich’s idea... Hey, at least you gotta admit that it’s pretty original. Me and Sidorovich should copyright this name and sell it to some big shot from Moscow. He would then open a bar with the same name with some Zone decorations: a few artifacts, a stuffed rodent, some worn out chimes and a tooth from a pseudogiant. That place would bring a lot of clients and me along with Sidorovich would get rich just by getting a small fraction of the business’s earnings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_0">
        <text>So Shaman, is this enough muscle for you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_1">
        <text>Yes, this enough, thanks for your help; I’ll pay 1500 for each guard just like we agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_2">
        <text>Yes, this enough, thanks for your help; I’ll pay 2500 for each guard just like we agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_3">
        <text>Yes, this enough, thanks for your help; I’ll pay 3500 for each guard just like we agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_fin_4">
        <text>Pleasure doing business with you, goodbye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_0">
        <text>Sidorovich said that you might have a job for me. What problem do you need taken care of?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_1">
        <text>Problem? I don’t have any problems. I just need a bit more security in my bar, can you help with that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_10">
        <text>All right, 2500 for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_11">
        <text>All right, 3500 for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_12">
        <text>No, I Wont lower the rent price.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_13">
        <text>In that case no deal. Forgot about this conversation; I guess I’ll have to make do with what I got.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_14">
        <text>Whatever you say.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_15">
        <text>All right, that’s an affordable price. We need four people with their own gear sense I have none to spare. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_16">
        <text>All right, they’ll come soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_2">
        <text>I can send a few people your way, for some cash of course. It will take some time for them to get here though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_3">
        <text>All right, Money isn’t a problem. How much for each head?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_4">
        <text>1500 for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_5">
        <text>2500 for each guard</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_6">
        <text>3500 for each guard</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_7">
        <text>5000 for each guard</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_8">
        <text>No, merc, that’s too much. Perhaps you could lower the price a bit? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_work_start_9">
        <text>fine. 1500 for each guard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_about_zone_1">
        <text>Do I look like an egghead? They’re the ones who study the Zone under the microscope. Me, I don’t know much about this place. I am only interested in making money here and that’s what I’m doing. So that after a few years I could afford my own piece of land with a grapevine near the lake.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_0">
        <text>I’d like to rent a bed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_1">
        <text>No problem, it will cost you 2500 for a day. I don’t rent them out for more than a day, if you need it for longer come back later and pay me for the next day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_2">
        <text>All right, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_3">
        <text>Nah, I’ll pass.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_4">
        <text>Excellent, your bed is located to the right of the entrance of the bedroom. There is also a footlocker near your bed where you can put your stuff in.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_bed_buy_5">
        <text>Whatever your say, it’s your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Greetings, merc! You have just entered the bar with the biggest assortment of food and drinks in the whole Zone. Welcome and enjoy your stay. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barman_chizhik_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Hi, merc. Do you want a drink?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_0">
        <text>Dude, do me a solid, turn off the radio.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_1">
        <text>Yeah, sure I can, just not for free. A lot of people here want to listen to the radio so you’re gonna have to pay up, 500 rubles to be exact. Once you pay, I will turn the radio off but keep in my mind that once you leave the bar I am turning it back on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_2">
        <text>Fine, here’s your 500 ru.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_3">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_4">
        <text>Pleasure doing buisness with you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_off_5">
        <text>Whatever, your call.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_on_0">
        <text>Can you turn on the radio?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_on_1">
        <text>Changed your mind, eh? Here you go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_on_2">
        <text>There, I turned it on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_barmen_bar_radio_on_3">
        <text>Listen to as much as you want, I don’t mind but if you want me turn it off you’re gonna have to pay again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_borland_fee_dialog_4">
        <text>Hey!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_0">
        <text>I want to take what I ordered.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_111">
        <text>Here, “Desert Eagle”! I had to fiddle with it a bit… One collector really wanted this gun so I had to steal right from under his nose. Take a look at it: it’s handmade; every piece is carved out like jewelry. This handgun has the range of a sniper rifle and is just as accurate. You owe me 2800.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1111">
        <text>All right, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_11111">
        <text>Pleasure doing buisness!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1112">
        <text>I don’t have that much cash right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_11121">
        <text>Well, I can hold then to the product for a while, let’s hope you find the money in time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1113">
        <text>I don’t want to buy it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_11131">
        <text>If you refuse to take the product then that means I won’t be able to trust you next time and I’ll charge you extra on your next order. Getting your hands on these guns is risky as it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_111311">
        <text>Eitherway, I won’t take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1113111">
        <text>Fine, it’s your choice.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_1114">
        <text>I’ll think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_11141">
        <text>Whatever you want… I’ll hold on to your order in the meantime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_112">
        <text>Here you go, a “Desert Eagle,” a heavy, accurate killing machine. That’ll be 2800.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_121">
        <text>The “Alpine”, a unique model of the Sig P229 handgun. Part of a small limited edition made for an unidentified special forces unit. The model benefits from an increased magazine capacity, a high durability steel barrel, and an ultra-durable polymer frame. 2800 and it’s yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_122">
        <text>Here an “Alpine” with an increased mag capacity, 2800 and it’s yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_131">
        <text>Take a look at this, a “March”. It used to belong to a mercenary named wolfhound. It is a compact, large caliber pistol with short bolt movement and lightweight bolt assembly. Even though, Wolfhound is a complete psycho, he knows his way around a gun. They say that Wolfhound used to execute people in a really brutal way with this handgun. He would start off by shooting off all of their 4 limbs and once they fall on the ground he would shoot them in the head… Yeah, sick shit. Anyway, it will cost 2800.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_132">
        <text>Here’s your “March,” that’ll be 2800.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_211">
        <text>Take a look at this: “Frasier”. Don’t let the old look fool you, this gun is brand new. This one isn’t even part of a series; it’s a unique prototype and it’s completely handmade.  It has a large caliber, an insanely fast fire rate, and it’s really accurate. It’ll cost you 8000. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_212">
        <text>Yeah, here’s your “Frasier”, that will be 8000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_221">
        <text>Check this out: “Carabiner”, An army shotgun designed specifically for assault units on the basis of the SPSA-14. Capable of automatic fire like its predecessor, but provides better recoil compensation thanks to a balanced shock free system. 8000 rubles and it’s yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_222">
        <text>Here you go: One “Carabiner” for 8000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_231">
        <text>I bet you’ll like this. “Eliminator”, one of the most modern inventions! A shipment of these was supposed to be sent to central Africa but a guy who worked for me managed to steal one. It’s an automatic shotgun with a very large mag capacity and an excellent fire rate. 8000 and it’s yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_232">
        <text>Of course, An “Eliminator” for 8000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_311">
        <text>Here: An automatic grenade launcher called “storm”. This is a modified version made especially for elite military stalkers. Wonderful piece of technology made by our brother slaves… 16000 and it’s yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_312">
        <text>Here’s Your “storm” with an extended mag. That’ll be 16000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_321">
        <text>Take a look at this: The GP37, The assault rifle of the future. It’s accurate, Reliable, powerful, and it has a built in scope. It used to belong to a soldier who was part of expedition sent by the UN, They were sent here to figure what was going on here. I’ll sell this rifle for 16000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_322">
        <text>Here you go, the GP37, the assualt rifle of the future. That’ll be 16000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_331">
        <text>One sec! Here: an FT-200M, a creation of beguine weapon manufacturers. An accurate, universal, fully ambidextrous so it you can shoot it with both hands… It also has a built in scope and grenade launcher. I got it from a UN soldier. That’ll be 16000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_332">
        <text>Here’s your FT-200M, for 16000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_411">
        <text>Here, “tide”. Based on the Vintar BS, a silent sniper rifle, it was made especially for fighting zombies and was supposed to be given out to military units who fought them. This model, although has slower fire rate but compensates with heavier fire power so that a zombie hit by its bullet would die instantly. However, in the end the rifle never made into the hands of soldiers sense it was discovered that zombies don’t really go anywhere past the barrier.  If you want, this rifle can be yours for 16000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_412">
        <text>Here, “tide”. A slienced sniper rifle with increased damage and it’s yours for 16000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_421">
        <text>Here, an SVU2-A, a shortened sniper rifle with an increased fire-rate. I bought it from Max, a legendary stalker from the freedom faction. He said that this rifle is one of a kind throughout the whole Zone and even if he lied, I doubt you will find another one in these parts. 16000 and it’s yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_422">
        <text>Yeah, here you go. SVU2-A, a shortened sniper rifle with an increased fire-rate. That’ll be 16000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_431">
        <text>Of course. Here, look: “Lynx”, it was handmade by a professional who is now dead and no one else can make one like it so this one is really rare. Even though it doesn’t differ from a regular SVD by appearance it’s stopping power and accuracy are far greater than that of the original. I’ll take 16000 for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_432">
        <text>Yeah, “Lynx.” A highly accurate and powerful sniper rifle. That’ll be 16000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_511">
        <text>Look here, I managed to get what I planned: CH-3a and its helmet. The helmet, on its own, isn’t anything special but it can be upgraded to a pretty good one. As for the CH-3a itself, that’s a different story. This armor has a strong defense against both bullets and anomalies and yet its user can remain totally mobile which is a rare case. 32000 for both the armor and the helmet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_512">
        <text>Here you go, CH-3a and it’s helmet. I’ll take 32000 for both of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_611">
        <text>Especially for you, Seva suit, just like you ordered. This armor has a built in breathing system, an electric shock protection system, an anti-corrosive layer on its surface and it’s fireproof.   As a bonus it also has a built in artifact container, a thing that is essential for any stalker. Just like we agreed, this suit will cost you 24000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_612">
        <text>Here’s your Seva suit. That’ll be 24000, just like we agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_711">
        <text>Here it is, a mercenary exoskeleton, I only managed to find one of these! Its protection against bullets, explosions, and mutant bites is the best in whole Zone, with a few very rare exceptions. It has a huge weight capacity so you don’t need worry about overloading yourself. You can have it for 48000, and I’ll even throw in a free battery.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_get_order_712">
        <text>Here it is, mercenary exoskeleton, I’ll sell it for 48000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_0">
        <text>I Would like to make an order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_1">
        <text>No Problem, What do need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_11">
        <text>A pistol.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_111">
        <text>Easy. A pistol will cost 3500, with 700 given in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_1111">
        <text>All right, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_11111">
        <text>I’ll contact when your order is ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_1112">
        <text>I don’t have the money right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_11121">
        <text>Okay then… Comeback when you have skrilla.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_1113">
        <text>You know what? I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_11131">
        <text>Aight, comeback if you need anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_112">
        <text>Well, you aren’t a reliable buyer so I am going to charge you 4200 for the pistol with 1400 given in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_113">
        <text>I am afraid that I’ve sold all my good pistols, and as for shitty ones, you can buy those from Owl.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_12">
        <text>Weapons for close range combat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_121">
        <text>Easy, that’ll cost you 10000, with 2000 given to me in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_122">
        <text>Îò ïðåäûäóùåãî çàêàçà òû îòêàçàëñÿ… Çíà÷èò, ýòîò îáîéäåòñÿ òåáå â 12000, ïðè÷åì 4000
            ïîíàäîáÿòñÿ ñðàçó.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_123">
        <text>Sorry, I can’t help you with that. I already sold everything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_13">
        <text>Assualt rifles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_131">
        <text>Okay, the regular price is 20000 and from it I will take 4000 in advance. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_132">
        <text>You’re difficult to work with, so for you the price will be 24000, 8000 of which I will take in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_133">
        <text>There’s a problem with that. right now, the soldiers at cordon are pissed and I can’t do business with them. Someone attacked their outpost not long ago and now they refusing to do business with stalkers, however this should be handled soon though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_14">
        <text>Sniper rifles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_141">
        <text>I could get you one for 20000, with 4000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_142">
        <text>And how do I know you won’t change your mind… Sense you are an unreliable client I’m going to charge 24000 for it, and I’ll take 8000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_143">
        <text>Sorry, not right now. The guy who gets these rifles for me got… Uhh… Sick.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_15">
        <text>Armor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_151">
        <text>Armor eh? I could get you one for 40000, but I’ll take 8000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_152">
        <text>I have a few armors lying around but sense you reneged on our last deal, I am going to charge you 48000 for it and I’ll take 16000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_153">
        <text>I couldn’t get anything good, and the last armor you took was the last one I had.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_16">
        <text>A suit with a closed off breathing system.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_161">
        <text>That’s a rare order… I could try and get one for 30000, but you’re gonna have to pay me 6000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_162">
        <text>Sense you backed out on that last deal so I’m going to charge you extra for it. I’m going to try and get one for 36000 and you’re going to pay me 12000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_163">
        <text>I could barely get that last one and right now I have nowhere to get another one.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_17">
        <text>mercenary exoskeleton.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_171">
        <text>That’s a serious deal… I think I can manage to get just for you but it will cost 60000 rubles, don’t worry it’s worth it and I will take 12000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_172">
        <text>Sense you backed out on our last deal, for such a serious order I will charge 72000. Keep in mind that I will take 24000 in advance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_173">
        <text>Not a chance. Sense the factory that produces these exos was closed, the only way to get one is too take one off a dead body but that’s not the way I work. .</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_18">
        <text>Still nothin’.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_place_order_2">
        <text>Sorry, I can’t do any orders right. Temporary difficulties…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_11">
        <text>Greetings, Beast, if you need any weapons or gear, you came to the right place. I can get my hands on even the rarest prototypes, some of the best out there. Each order is handled by me personally so they are always top quality.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_12">
        <text>Hey, What do want to order?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_13">
        <text>Hey.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_14">
        <text>You order will be ready soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_duplet_start_15">
        <text>You order is up, you can take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_10">
        <text>Sidorovich asked me to find this courier; I didn’t expect to find him dead.  My sympathies, man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_11">
        <text>Damn… He was one of the good ones; I’ve been through a lot of shit with this guy. You’d think this would be the last place he’d die sense cordon is the safest place in the Zone and yet here he is…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_12">
        <text>Did you see who killed him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_13">
        <text>Did you find anything else interesting?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_14">
        <text>Did you search his backpack?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_15">
        <text>All right, did you know this stalker?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_16">
        <text>I found a pda in his backpack but it’s locked. Do you know by any chance anyone who can hack it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_18">
        <text>Nope, I don’t know nor have I seen who did it. I accidently caught the signal of his pda when I was walking by and he wasn’t answering. So I came here in order to check it out. I thought maybe he dropped his pda or something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_19">
        <text>Yeah, this is a sad turn of events but what’s done is done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_2">
        <text>Man, what assholes! Why would somebody do such a thing? Fuck, I told him not to take that damn job, that it was too risky, but no he had to go and get himself killed. Anyway, what do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_20">
        <text>No, I haven’t searched his backpack yet, I doubt there’s anything valuable there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_21">
        <text>Yeah, I knew him well and I used to help him with his courier jobs from time to time. He was a good, kind stalker; I don’t know why some would kill him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_22">
        <text>I don’t know for sure but I think wagon can help with that, you should ask him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_23">
        <text>Well, I am going to search him, he might have something that I need.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_24">
        <text>I feel you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_25">
        <text>All right, I’ll ask him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_26">
        <text>All right, that’s all I needed to know, good luck out there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_3">
        <text>Did you know this guy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_4">
        <text>Yeah, I knew him well and I used to help him with his courier jobs from time to time. He was a good, kind stalker; I don’t know why some would kill him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_5">
        <text>Who could do this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_friend_kurer_quest_line_start_6">
        <text>text in default</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_">
        <text>?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_1">
        <text>Sidorovich, some say you sell info, is that true?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_10">
        <text>Yeah… Nevermind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_11">
        <text>What can tell me about Shaman?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_12">
        <text>500 rubles and I tell you all I know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_13">
        <text>Okay, here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_14">
        <text>Shaman’s a good guy, he used to be in some kind of special force unit or something… He is nowhere near Wolf but he still knows his way around the Zone and his been around for more than a year now. Most stalkers can learn a lot from him especially new ones. He’s a real leader and keeps all the stalkers here in line and make sure that they are covering each other’s back. He is also a good strategist and always knows how to solve a problem by using his head. Anyway, good stalker and I’m glad he’s here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_15">
        <text>Do you know anything about Mark?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_16">
        <text>500 rubles and all the hot goss is yours…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_19">
        <text>What do you know about Borland?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_2">
        <text>Depends what info… Tell me what you need to know and then we will see if I can help you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_20">
        <text>The price for such info is always the same, 500.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_21">
        <text>Got change for a 1000?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_22">
        <text>According to the rumors, Borland wasn’t a soldier nor was he a scientist. Rather he was a thirty-two year old professional racer. Due the mess that was going on his country every race track and stadium was closed and Borland was forced to find something else to do with his life. He quickly understood that the only place for him is the Zone. All of his talents are useful here. His dexterous eyes and hands, his ability to remain cool in dangerous situations, and his stamina all serve him well here in the Zone. Borland had the ability to find the solution to any problem on the fly no matter how tough and he had great sense of time and distance. Really the Zone was nothing new for him; it was all the same except the stakes were a bit higher.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_23">
        <text>I heard about this guy named Fang. You wouldn’t happen to know anything about him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_24">
        <text>Î, Ñàâàí, ýòî òû î êîì íàäî ñïðîñèë. Äàâàé 500 ðóáëåé è ñëóøàé.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_25">
        <text>I am all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_26">
        <text>Fang is a legendry stalker. In strelok’s group he was the muscle, he would take care of anything combat related. He was a terrific shot and more than that he was also really smart when it came to technology. He upgraded his own exoskeleton and made it the best in the whole Zone. Too bad he disappeared somewhere, nobody knows for sure. Some say that he died while others say that he simply left the Zone. I can’t tell you, I don’t know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_27">
        <text>Do you know anything strelok’s group? How about Ghost.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_28">
        <text>I’ll tell for 500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_29">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_3">
        <text>What do you know about Wolf? Who is he, how did get here, etc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_30">
        <text>Ghost was something of a spy, he could sneak anywhere undetected; he wasn’t called ghost for nothing. Too bad he is no longer with us. He died in the laboratory that’s located in Yantar. He was a good stalker, maybe one of the best. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_4">
        <text>info costs money pal, so fork over 500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_5">
        <text>Whatever you say…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_6">
        <text>Don’t you think that’s a tad bit much? I’ll pass.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_7">
        <text>Sergey Ykimov (Wolf) and his family were always in a bad shape. His wife left him in the same time that he got fired. At first all he did was get wasted, drinking all day and night but once after his brother, Peter, got in too trouble things changed. Peter had been badly beat up, his nose was broken and his hand were all messed up. Wolf was so pissed off that he found one of the guys who did it and shot him. After that wolf ran to the Zone and with time he gained respect and experience. That’s how he been came rookie leader we know today and even though today he barely goes out of cordon back in the day he would go deep into the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_8">
        <text>Do you know anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_info_ot_sidora_9">
        <text>All right, thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_2">
        <text>All right, beast, what are your orders?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_4">
        <text>Hey, what’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_5">
        <text>I need you to patrol the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_6">
        <text>Sit back for a while, I don’t have any work for you right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_7">
        <text>Get back to base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_bizon_meet_patrol_8">
        <text>Nevermind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_0">
        <text>I want to hire some extra security.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_1">
        <text>Tell me where you need the guard, so I can message him the location.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_10">
        <text>Excellent, Jackal has sent extra muscle form the nearst outpost.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_11">
        <text>I want to hire some extra security.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_12">
        <text>Okay, the price for the extra soldier is 2500 and you will have to pay out of your own pocket sense you are the leader. So what do you say? Are you hiring?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_13">
        <text>Okay, the price for the extra soldier is 2500 and you will have to pay out of your own pocket sense you are the leader. So what do you say? Are you hiring?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_14">
        <text>Okay, the price for the extra soldier is 2500 and you will have to pay out of your own pocket sense you are the leader. So what do you say? Are you hiring?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_15">
        <text>Yeah, here’s the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_16">
        <text>Yeah, here’s the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_17">
        <text>Yeah, here’s the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_2">
        <text>Adminstration buliding, second floor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_3">
        <text>Near the tunnel leading to dark valley.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_4">
        <text>Yard, south enterance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_5">
        <text>Yard, north enterance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_6">
        <text>All right, I need to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_7">
        <text>Okay, the price for the extra soldier is 2500 and you will have to pay out of your own pocket sense you are the leader. So what do you say? Are you hiring?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_8">
        <text>Yeah, here’s the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_security_9">
        <text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_11">
        <text>Hey beast! What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_12">
        <text>The coordinator will be waiting for you in Bar No92 but I don’t know who is he or how does he look like, Jackal didn’t say, but he did say that he will approach you first. Perhaps we are finally going to get a serious mission, maybe Jackal finally decided to take us seriously.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_13">
        <text>What kind of jobs did you do before this one?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_14">
        <text>Small shit mostly, nothing too serious and the pay wasn’t that good either.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_15">
        <text>All right, I’ll go meet this coordinator, the more info I can get about this mission the better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_17">
        <text>Hey, Beast! Do you have some buisness for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_18">
        <text>Yeah, I need you to contact Jackal and tell to send 4 fighters our way. Tell him that we need these soldiers for a security job at the bar and that if the op goes as planned we will get paid well but in the meantime we are not going to pay for them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_19">
        <text>Jackal won’t be too happy to send troops without payment up front but he will go through as long as the pay is good. When the mercs come I will need to brief them on their mission so tell me what exactly they need to do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_20">
        <text>They just need to guard the bar in the rookie village, nothing too compliacted. Just send them there when they get here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_21">
        <text>All right, I do that. Once the mercs arrive, I will contact you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_22">
        <text>Right then, see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_24">
        <text>Hey beast! What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_25">
        <text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_26">
        <text>Excellent, Jackal has sent some extra muscle form the nearst outpost.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_27">
        <text>Alirght, I got to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_3">
        <text>Hey, Beast, even though Jackal won’t send any extra muscle for free, we can still pay him. We are low on manpower right now so I would suggest you ask Jackal too send us a few more troops if you have some extra cash. Who knows what these stalkers will try to pull next.  Either way, I can contact Jackal any time so he could send some more men.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_4">
        <text>Hey beast! What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_6">
        <text>Greetings, Beast! Bizon told me that Sidorovich sent us the pay for his mission so does that mean you have news about the contract? Is there any work for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_7">
        <text>Yeah, I need to tell Jackal that Sidorovich needs two men to guard his bunker and that don’t have men spare, I think he’ll understand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_8">
        <text>Got it, I get to it right now. By the way, almost forgot, Jackal said that the coordinator is ready to meet you and that he has a new job for us. Jackal said that you need to meet him personally.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_grif_meet_to_killers_9">
        <text>That must be the secret mission that Jackal was talking about earlier… All right, where will this coordinator be waiting for me? I want to see what Jackal has in store for us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_0">
        <text>Hello, Beast. Grief said that you talked to the coordinator. So what’s the job? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_1">
        <text>We need to “barrow” something from Sidorovich’s warehouse but before that we need to find a way to neutralize the technician.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_2">
        <text>All right, let’s start thinking… By the way, I found out who were those three dudes that came here a while back. They were Valerian’s men and they were sent here to found what we were doing here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_3">
        <text>Good, that means they weren’t here on Sidorovich’s orders. I was getting worried for a second.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_4">
        <text>We tried to negotiate with them at first but you know how that turned out… Yeah, one of the stalkers we saved, Raccoon is his name, said that he wants to join the syndicate but I told him that his way too green.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_blackbox_5">
        <text>And you did the right thing, although having a mole in the rookie village is not that bad.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_0">
        <text>Of what use will that stalker be to us? He could compromise our whole operation and we would have to spend days unfucking the mess that would come after.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_1">
        <text>Relax, I have a plan. Raccoon could help us with our current mission.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_2">
        <text>Hmm… What will be his task?  He will probably get caught the minute goes anywhere near Valerian. What are you thinking?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_3">
        <text>We need to make Valerian leave the base and then we can kill him without witnesses.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_4">
        <text>So that stalker is only bait? I get it now: Valerian will find out that we sent an assassin after him and then he will try to escape and that’s when we kill him, right? Good plan, this could totally work.  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_5">
        <text>Yeah, exactly, tonight we will see if my plan goes through. I’ve told grief to send a few guys to keep an eye on the stalker base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_6">
        <text>All right, and what will you do now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_kill_leader_7">
        <text>I’ll head back to the auto depot and wait for the message from the recon team, that’s all for now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_leader_in_td_0">
        <text>Hey, Beast, what’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_leader_in_td_1">
        <text>Raven, I need you to take two fighters and haul ass to the tunnel leading to Dark Valley. Valerian ate the bait, and he’s heading there as we speak. We are going to ambush him there. Come on, lets go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_leader_in_td_2">
        <text>Got it, Heading out now. Are you with us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_leader_in_td_3">
        <text>Yes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_10">
        <text>Not now, I’ll head there in a little while.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_12">
        <text>You should probably talk to the hostage first.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_13">
        <text>You’re right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_2">
        <text>Well, this checkpoint is ours. We’ll hold it until you decide what to do next. What about those stalkers, though? Can they go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_3">
        <text>Yeah, they’re fine. Listen: my sniper rifle needs some adjustments. When we get back to the village, tell the technician to take a look. He should know what to do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_4">
        <text>Gotcha. Are we heading back the the village?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_5">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_6">
        <text>Just wait for a moment. I need to check something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_8">
        <text>So are you ready to go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_meet_to_operation_9">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_0">
        <text>We’re in position, Beast. Another group just arrived in the Cordon, and they’ll be joining us in the assault. Everyone’s ready to go; the bandits won’t know what hit ’em. Before we go, though, can I ask you a question?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_1">
        <text>Excellent. Ask away, Raven.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_2">
        <text>Are you sure it’s worth it—risking our guys for a couple of nobodies? I doubt Wolf will pay a lot for this, considering the fact he’s probably not rich or anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_3">
        <text>I’m not really sure, but this is our best option at the moment. By carrying out this contract and saving those men, the people around here will recognize and trust us. We need that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_4">
        <text>Got it. How’s the sniper spot I picked? I thought it matched your request. Plus, I couldn’t find anything better, so…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_5">
        <text>The position is perfect for my needs, Raven. Great place to test out this new sniper rifle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_6">
        <text>Glad to hear it. Now let’s go over our plan one more time: I help our guys distract the bandits while you snipe them off one by one from up here. That right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_killer_raven_quest_sniper_atack_meet_7">
        <text>That’s our plan, all right. Now let’s do this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_0">
        <text>I need medical attention.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_1">
        <text>Okay, let’s take a look…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_11">
        <text>[Next…]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_111">
        <text>All right, you’re good to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_medic_antibiotic_need_health_care_2">
        <text>Okay, so you’re lever’s kind of swollen but that’s a professional hazard… Other than that though, you’re fine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_0">
        <text>Can you refill my flask with water?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_1">
        <text>Yes, of course merc, no problem. However it will cost you a 1000. That might seem expensive but keep in my mind that it’s hard to filter out radiation out of water. So what do you think?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_2">
        <text>Yeah okay, Here’s the money and my flask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_3">
        <text>Nah, changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_4">
        <text>Sense this process takes time, I have a full flask ready for you, here you go and in meantime you can give me your old one so I can refill that. It’ll be ready by the time you come back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_shaman_water_full_5">
        <text>All right, thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_0">
        <text>I found a pda of “Final Day” will you pay anything for it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_1">
        <text>Really? Is the pda encrypted?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_2">
        <text>Only partailly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_3">
        <text>I’ll pay 10000 for it, no more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_4">
        <text>Sure, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_dialog_shved_pda_5">
        <text>Here’s your cash, merc. Now let’s take a look…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_10">
        <text>He’s always alone and I doubt anybody hangs around him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_11">
        <text>Where can I find him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_12">
        <text>That’s a bit more difficult, I have no idea where he went but I have an idea. I’ll give you a GPS tracking unit and you will put it where I tell you. Then we will be able to track him down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_13">
        <text>All right, give me that tracking unit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_14">
        <text>Take it from the basement downstairs and plant it on the railroad bridge. I’ll send you the exact coordinates to your pda.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_15">
        <text>All right, I’ll go get it. Tell your guard to let me through.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_17">
        <text>Merc, don’t forget that you need to set up that tracking unit before I can find this “Klim” guy. All right, see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_18">
        <text>Later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hello, merc. Let’s get straight to business, I take it you already know that you were hired for more than one job, right? Good. Not only have I managed to make a lot of enemies in the long time I’ve been here, but there are a lot of other things I need taken care of.  Before we begin let’s establish a few rules that will keep you all from getting in to trouble. First of all, you know that stalker base over the railroad bridge; don’t go there because Valerian really dislikes mercenaries. Second, don’t do any business behind my back. Third and final, all of this must remain between us. Are we clear?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_20">
        <text>So merc, have you found the flashdrive yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_21">
        <text>Yeah, here it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_22">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_23">
        <text>Excellent, bring it here. Don’t bother telling me how you got it; I don’t care about the details. Tell me this though, the guy that was caring it, Is he dead?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_24">
        <text>Take the flashdrive… Yeah, you won’t have to worry about him ever again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_25">
        <text>That’s good to hear… And that asshole thought he could rip me off. All right, let’s not waste any more time.  You’re free to go for now, I’ll message you when I’ll need you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_26">
        <text>Okay, now it’s time to do your part of the deal, pay me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_28">
        <text>Hello merc, how are you? Listen, I didn’t call you for a job, instead I have a different offer for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_29">
        <text>Yeah? And what sort of offer would that be?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_3">
        <text>So it’s true what they say about you… All right, now hear out my rules, although it’s pretty much one rule.  I get paid on time, right after the job is finished, no exceptions. Are we clear?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_30">
        <text>I need you to send me two of your guys to guard my bunker, I’ve been getting some extra heat recently, some people don’t like the way I do business. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_31">
        <text>Sure, I can send you a couple of guys. How much will you pay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_32">
        <text>Hey, merc, have you forgotten the fact that I signed contract with your leader? I can remind you the hard way. Either way, I want two guards near my bunker as soon as possible. You got that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_33">
        <text>Not a chance, I don’t have a lot of people as it is and the once I do are all busy and there’s no way in hell I am paying for your security out my own pocket.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_35">
        <text>I don’t loan cash!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_37">
        <text>Yeah whatever… I am not here for that. Did you hear anything about what happened last night?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_38">
        <text>No. What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_39">
        <text>Something really strange, last night Valerian and his group went off somewhere and haven’t returned sense. No one can contact them via pda, they won’t answer, and those who remained at the base have no idea where Valerian could be.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_40">
        <text>Okay… And why are you telling me this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_41">
        <text>You know, just making conversation. Thought maybe you know something, clearly though you don’t.  Either way, in the meantime Valerian’s place is going to be taken by Orestes, an experienced stalker who just came back from a raid in Agroprom and he will be temporarily residing in the stalker base. I need you to give him something from me and don’t worry I talked to them, they will let you in.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_42">
        <text>I’m not your delivery boy, If you don’t have any real work then I’ll be on my way…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_43">
        <text>Listen here, you sellout piece of shit. Either you do what I tell you or I am cancelling the contract. Are we clear here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_44">
        <text>Oh, all right, give me your package. Let’s get this over with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_45">
        <text>I hope this is the last time you refuse to do your job. Here’s the package, give to Orestes personally, I told him you’d come. Also, Shaman was looking for you, he has a job for you. His in the bar right now so pay him a visit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_46">
        <text>Bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_48">
        <text>I don’t loan cash!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_5">
        <text>I don’t loan cash!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_50">
        <text>Merc, don’t forget that you need to set up that tracking unit before I can find this “Klim” guy. All right, see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_51">
        <text>All right, I’ll go get it. Tell your guard to let me through.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_52">
        <text>Fine, I’ll pay for your guys. 5000 for both of them, no more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_53">
        <text>That’s more like it, they’ll be here ASAP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_54">
        <text>Good work merc, the guys you sent are real professionals…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_55">
        <text>I Doubt you called me just for that so let’s get straight to the point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_6">
        <text> Yeah, you’re right I also need to brief you on your first job. A while back a guy came here who wanted to sell some info to me but he the price he demanded was too high. The stalker’s name is Klim and he keeps the needed info in his flashdrive which he always carries with him. Your job is to get me that flashdrive and get rid of this Klim guy once and for all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_7">
        <text>All right, what does this guy look like? Is he heavily armed? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_8">
        <text>No. He’s just some random trash with subpar gear. When he came here all he had was sawn-off shotgun and I doubt he had the time to get something better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sidor_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Does he have any friends? does he work in a group?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_1">
        <text>I always liked my independence and that’s why most of the time, I worked by myself and for myself and when I heard that the stalkers organized their own base, I knew I had to join in. You know, I’ve been in many places in the Zone and to me, being among independent stalkers is the best. There the only normal people around here, you feel me? They don’t have any “codes”, rules, or any other nonsense. They are just regular dudes trying to make a living and that’s the way it should be.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_11">
        <text>It’s really hard to come by good parts in the Zone… How do you manage to work with what you have?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_111">
        <text>Well, it’s not like I am upgrading gauss rifles over here but I can manage to get some decent work done. I’ve been doing this for many years now and I’m good at what I do. That’s pretty much it. Most stalkers don’t bring anything that complicated, mostly regular guns and armor that they need fixed. From time to time a stalker will ask for an upgrade and I can do that too. You can take a look at what upgrades I do, maybe you want something. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_1111">
        <text>From what I undersatnd you’ve been around the Zone… Have you seen anything unusual on one of your trips?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_mechanic_about_you_11111">
        <text>Unusual? I came here from Agroprom when the big emission hit, you know, the one that changed everything. The things that happened after can only be described as miracles. A place that once was totally empty become a total shit show, part of the land there was all massed up with parts of it rising up, it was like something Salvador Dali drew and the radiation there was so strong that you couldn’t be anywhere near it without getting a lethal dose. The guys later told me that this anomaly was one of the most dangerous in the Zone and that it had the rarest artifacts. If you are ever near that place, beware…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_0">
        <text>Woah… Man, if it wasn’t for you, we would be dead right now! Raccoon and I are very grateful. It’s a good thing you came when you did… Who are you men, and why did you risk your lives for us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_1">
        <text>We’re mercenaries. We were hired by Wolf to look for your squad. We found Zokhan, who told us of your location.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_2">
        <text>Zokhan’s alive? Oh, thank God! I thought he was dead for sure; I’m really happy to hear that!… Hey, can I ask you one more thing? Where are you going now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_3">
        <text>Don’t worry. We’ll escort you back to the rookie village. After that, we’ll be on your way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_4">
        <text>Good to hear. Those damn bandits took all of our gear, so we’re left with nothing… and walking around in the Zone without a gun isn’t exactly the smartest thing to do. So, we heading out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_5">
        <text>Hold on a sec. I need to talk to my partner.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_6">
        <text>Hold on a sec. Let me tell my guys where we’re headed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_muravei_free_7">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_1">
        <text>I am trader who’s just starting out. When we came here not that long ago, Shaman said that everyone can pick what role they like, I wanted to be a trader.  I have the talent for this job, I’ve been buying and selling things sense I was a kid. Back in school I used sell those old electronic games, you know the ones where there’s a wolf that catches eggs, an old soviet toy…  Right now I am just trying to figure out how things work around here you know… Most of my products I get from Sidorovich so there’s not that much profit but hey slowly but surely I am starting to get my own clients so there’s that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_111">
        <text>Man, right now we are living the good life. No more will the military try to steal our loot, now all of our earning will remain ours. Now after a deep raid we can actually rest easy in cordon and we can actually obtain good gear here. Hell, we can start making real money not like before when the minute a stalker would show up with a decent artifact the military would immediately take it from him. Maybe one day, we will drive out these jarheads out completely. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_2">
        <text>What do you think of about the life in Cordon right now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_trader_about_you_3">
        <text>Man, right now we are living the good life. No more will the military try to steal our loot, now all of our earning will remain ours. Now after a deep raid we can actually rest easy in cordon and we can actually obtain good gear here. Hell, we can start making real money not like before when the minute a stalker would show up with decent artifact the military would immediately take it from him. Maybe one day, we will drive out these jarheads out completely.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_10">
        <text>Fine, I won’t tell about this to anyone. What do you have?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_11">
        <text>Usually, bandits don’t go anywhere near that place, meaning that they had a special reason for being there. They must’ve being looking for something and we ran into them by accident. Their behavior was also really strange, I saw one of them drop a blue notebook when they were there, and I heard a few shots. After that, my vision went black, and when I woke up, I saw you. They must have taken the hostages and left.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_12">
        <text>Okay. And what do you suggest we do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_13">
        <text>Can you go there, where you found me, and take a second look? Maybe you can find something. I have a gut feeling that those bandits were there for a reason. Don’t worry: I’ll pay up. You know me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_14">
        <text>All right. I’ll see what I can find.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_15">
        <text>I have better things to do than waste my time looking for something only God knows.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_16">
        <text>Merc, I’m counting on you here, please, if you can, find some free time for this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_17">
        <text>Fine… I’ll go there and see what’s what.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_18">
        <text>All right, but not right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_2">
        <text>You’re back… Thank you, you saved that guy’s life, if not for you, he would be dead. The bandits don’t hold hostages for long and the minute they see they are useless, they would kill them. Also, thanks for the medkit, it was a life savior. Was it hard to take down those scumbags?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_20">
        <text>So, Beast, have you found some time for the job yet? I’ll pay up good, you know me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_21">
        <text>Fine… I’ll go there and see what’s what.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_22">
        <text>fine… I’ll go there and see what’s what.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_24">
        <text>Hey, Beast, What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_26">
        <text>Hello Beast, have you found the notebook?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_27">
        <text>Yeah, I found your notebook and I lost 25 grand in the process. Now I need that money back and your payment for the job which would amount in total to 30000. Any questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_28">
        <text>Yeah, I found the blue notebook and it had the coordinates of a meeting  that was supposed to take place. in the meeting place I found a note that lead me to the tunnel under the railroad bridge. When I went there, I got jumped by some guy and he demanded 25 grand from me, so I iced him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_29">
        <text>What? How? What exactly happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_3">
        <text>A sad turn of events, Yeah… I’m used to bullshit like this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_30">
        <text>There isn’t that much to explain. I went to the tunnel and there was a bandit who tried to rob me, so I shot him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_31">
        <text>That’s impossible, there’s a stalker base nearby so why would a bandit be anywhere near there. The bandits that hang around the northern checkpoint know full well not to go anywhere near that tunnel. This was done by someone else, I’m telling you. Did he tell you why he wanted 25 g’s? And how the hell did you know how to get to that tunnel anyway?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_32">
        <text>I found that blue notebook you mentioned before and in it the coordinates of the meeting were written down. When I went to the meeting place I found a note that said that someone will be waiting in tunnel at night. I went there and it turned out to be a trap. The guy stuck a gun to my chest and demanded 25k for some case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_33">
        <text>We need quickly see what’s inside that case… Do you have it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_34">
        <text>I have the case but it’s locked and there’s no way we are opening it without a professional lock picker. More than that though, the case is really light, like it’s empty, so I doubt that there’s anything valuable in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_35">
        <text>All of this is really strange… I need so what’s in that case, It might have some valuable info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_36">
        <text>Fine, I’ll take care of cracking that case and you need to come up with the money that you owe me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_38">
        <text>Hey, Beast, What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_39">
        <text>That’s impossible, there’s a stalker base nearby so why would a bandit be anywhere near there. The bandits that hang northern checkpoint know full well not to go anywhere near that tunnel. This was done by someone else, I’m telling you. Did he tell you why he wanted 25 g’s?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_4">
        <text>Too bad you guys didn’t come earlier; you would have saved a few more lives… either way though you saved lives today. Here, take this artifact, I found it in Garbage and I’ve never seen anything like it. I wanted to sell it to Sidorovich but you’ve earned it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_40">
        <text>That cash must’ve been payment for that case, the one he brought.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_41">
        <text>We need quickly see what’s inside that case… Do you have it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_42">
        <text>I have the case but it’s locked and there’s no way we are opening it without a professional lock picker. More than that though, the case is really light, like it’s empty, so I doubt that there’s anything valuable in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_43">
        <text>All of this is really strange… I need so what’s in that case, It might have some valuable info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_44">
        <text>Fine, I’ll take care of the case. Keep in my mind though I am not giving contents of the case away for free.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_5">
        <text>Hey thanks man, If you ever need my help, you know where to find me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_7">
        <text>Hey, Beast, What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_8">
        <text>Thanks. You said that you needed to talk to me about something, was it about the reward?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_start_9">
        <text>No, Beast, I need to talk to you about something else but you have to promise me that you’ll keep it between us. All right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_10">
        <text>Dude, I already told you everything I know… Please, man… Give me a medkit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_11">
        <text>Thanks a ton, man… Whew. Feeling better already. You saved my life… Wait, why are you here, anyway?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_12">
        <text>Wolf hired us to check up on your squad. I take it you’re the only survivor?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_13">
        <text>No. Two of us were taken hostage by the bandit attackers. I heard one of them say they need hostages for something, but I don’t know what the hell they’re planning to do. I’m fairly sure the hostages are still alive, though, so maybe there’s still a chance to rescue them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_14">
        <text>Where did they take them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_15">
        <text>The northern checkpoint; the one that leads to the Garbage. They set up a small base and everything, the bastards.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_16">
        <text>Got it. We’ll try to save them. And you should get back to the rookie village—this is no child’s play.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_17">
        <text>No, dude! I can’t just sit on my ass while my friends are in danger! I can shoot, and I’m already feeling better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_18">
        <text>Not a chance, kid. Get back to Wolf. You’re wounded, and you won’t be of any use to us during the fight. We can handle a few bandits on our own, no problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_19">
        <text>Urgh… Fine. Just make sure you bring everyone back alive! I’m counting on you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_20">
        <text>Sure thing. Now go see Wolf and tell him what happened while we prepare the assault.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_3">
        <text>Dude, help me… I’m bleeding here. Please…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_4">
        <text>After you answer a few questions. Then we’ll see what I can do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_5">
        <text>Real funny… I can’t hold out much longer… Gimme a medkit…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_6">
        <text>No, I’m serious. Tell me right now: who the hell are you, and where is Wolf’s squad?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_7">
        <text>I’m Zokhan… As for the squad… you’re looking at it… We were ambushed by bandits, and they killed everyone… They left me for dead… We… We managed kill a few of them… but it wasn’t enough. There was too many of them… Dude, please, just give me a medkit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_8">
        <text>All right. Here’s your medkit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_zohan_wounded_9">
        <text>I don’t have any medkits. Sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_10">
        <text>Well, it seems true to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_100">
        <text>First time I’m hearing about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_101">
        <text>It’s a well-known fact by now that what we call “zombies” are just people who completely lost their sanity and intelligence and yet people still endanger their mind in hopes of finding better loot, that’s human greed all right. Duty, for example, doesn’t even go anywhere near controllers, always keeping a kilometer between them and that dangerous mutant.  They rather not risk their mental health; it’s just not worth it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_102">
        <text>Yeah, scary shit…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_103">
        <text>So a Freedom stalker heard about Duty’s well known zoo…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_104">
        <text>Promising start…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_105">
        <text>God knows what was going in that freedomer’s head, but he got into his mind that he must see those mutants that were held up in duty’s zoo. Even though that guy was a good dude, it always seemed like he was too good. His honesty and loyalty had no limits and it was clear that it was only a matter of time before he does something really stupid. That’s why nobody was really surprised when the stalker said he was going to infiltrate duty’s base and attempt to free those mutants.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_106">
        <text>What was he thinking…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_107">
        <text>Sense it was Freedom, an anarchist faction, as long as nobody does anything to harm the faction itself everyone can do whatever they want. So they let the deluded freedomer continue with his crazy plan. Everybody said their goodbyes to him because they knew he was done for but our hero wasn’t as simple as he looked. I don’t know how but he managed to catch a live rodent so he could use it as a peace offering to Duty. So what do you think Duty did? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_108">
        <text>I doubt they invited him over for tea…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_109">
        <text>I don’t whether it was because the guards were in a forgiving mood or was it because the freedomer appeared totally harmless but they let him through. However, when the stalker got to Duty’s zoo is when shit hit the fan!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_11">
        <text>Too bad they couldn’t enjoy their victory for long. They were hit by a psi emission! It’s like the brain scorcher was living creature that suddenly realized they were there and wanted to get rid of them. When the psi emission hit, only one of the guys was zombified. He had a suit with a strong psi protection so he managed to survive that wave while the other guy’s brains frayed for good. Some say this happens a lot, where not everyone gets zombified at once. The guy whose brains were intact tackled his friend and dragged him towards red forest in hopes of saving his him…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_110">
        <text>Plotwists… Cool.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_111">
        <text>It turned out, that the freedomer was crazier than everyone thought. When he entered the zoo and saw the state the animals in he lost his shit. The animals were locked in small cages with barely an inch to move and there were so starved that they looked like scarecrows. The sight drove our hero mad so he started screaming at the top of his lungs and  jumped on the zookeeper, inquisitor was his name, and started beating the shit out of him. At the same time Inquisitor wanted to put their newly obtained rodent at the rodent cage so the door to it was open so once the freedomer started assaulting him all the rodents escaped. The Duty soldiers of course shot the freedomer almost instantly…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_112">
        <text>Too bad… Poor fellow.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_113">
        <text>Though, he did manage to follow through on his plan. He exchanged his own life for the freedom of those rodents who escaped. They ran between the dutyers legs without them noticing untill finally the rodents found their way out of the base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_114">
        <text>Not a bad story. All right, </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_115">
        <text>Did you hear about the village, the one that’s near Radar and is in habited by bloodsuckers? Even though, everyone knows about that hellhole, I bet you don’t know why all the bloodsuckers flock there in first place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_116">
        <text>Can’t say that I do…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_117">
        <text>Way back, before the big blowout that created the Zone, that village was inhabited by the military. Keep in mind though, these were no ordinary soldiers. They had some kind of different uniform with its own strange emblems.  They were some kind of special unit. However what was their purpose no one knows for sure and it doesn’t matter much to our story. Anyway, when the big blowout hit almost all of the soldiers died instantly. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_118">
        <text>Sounds interesting but what does this have to do wtih the bloodsuckers?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_119">
        <text>However a few people managed to survive in that same village by hiding inside the cellars people used to store all the pickled goods. You know how our people are, we love our pickled shit and we can’t have enough of it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_12">
        <text>I doubt he could accomplish anything but that’s some loyalty…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_120">
        <text>Well they had to come out some time didn’t they? They had to eat after all, it’s not like there was an unlimited supply of food in those cellars. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_121">
        <text>Yeah, you’re right. They had to come out of there at some point and they did. The soldiers would come out of the cellars from time to time to find some food and other supplies, grabbing whatever they could get their hands on. They didn’t have any detectors so they had no idea when they were walking through a radioactive field and they amount of radiation they took was enormous. But they had no other choice due to food supplies running so low.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_122">
        <text>Hell, there wasn’t much to do…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_123">
        <text>When they ran out of food completely, the soldiers resorted to cannibalism. What ensued was total nightmare. Those guys were so starved that they ate the people who were too weak to go on, their own friends, no less. But that’s not what’s important in this story, believe it or not but things get weirder.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_124">
        <text>I’ve have completely lost my appetite, and now you telling me things are going to get even weirder. This is the Zone after all, what else was I supposed to expect?   </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_125">
        <text>Yeah, the Zone is an unpredictable place and some even say that it’s a living creature. In the Zone some things don’t die out but rather adapt to it, revealing their ugliest form in the process. That’s what happened to our beloved soldiers, who instead of dying turned into the bloodsuckers we all know and love. The first generation of these mutants would wear a special soldier uniform, the same one as the guys that were stationed in the army warehouses wore. To this day bloodsuckers flock to that village… maybe they feel it’s their home. Who the hell knows what in the head of those overgrown ticks…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_126">
        <text>Man, I don’t even know what to say…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_127">
        <text>Yeah, trying to figure that out is a waste of time. The moral of this story is though, that sometimes it’s better to just accept your death instead of turning into a complete monster. The latter is a fate way worse than death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_128">
        <text>Yeah, maybe you’re right… all right, I gotta go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_129">
        <text>There was a time when The Barrier was totally unprotected and nobody was around to guard it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_13">
        <text>Fate had more hardship in store for those two. All that noise attracted the attention of a monolith unit who was patrolling the area and saw the two stalkers. They opened fire the second they noticed them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_130">
        <text>I like stories about the old days, keep going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_131">
        <text>Back then, huge waves of monsters would run through the barrier and travel all the way to garbage. That’s why most stalkers preferred not to set camp anywhere near the radar barrier and the farthest place you could see stalkers camping was the bloodsucker village. But that village was no less dangerous as it was always occupied by packs of bloodsuckers. That’s how the place got its name, nobody knows why but those mutants would always flock to that village. Yet, even though the danger, stalkers would still in sleep in the houses of that village with one eye open.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_132">
        <text>Sounds like a story about me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_133">
        <text>So one time, a certain screwball decided to spend the night on top of the tower that was located at the edge of the village. He claimed up, opened a bottle of vodka and slowly started drinking it whilst gradually falling asleep at the same time. Then all of a sudden, he saw a human silhouette in the distance, rustling around in the bushes. The stalker at the tower grabbed his rifle and his binoculars and got in better position to take his shot. For all he knew, it could have been a bloodsucker or a snork looking for some fresh prey or far worse a controller. However, it turned out be a regular stalker who was looking for a place to sleep the night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_134">
        <text>He got lucky…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_135">
        <text>Our hero was happy to see another stalker in the area so he started throwing stuff out of the tower in hopes the other guy would see him. The stalker wondering around the village finally realized what was going on and went straight to the tower. Only the problem was this wasn’t a regular stalker but an experienced bandit with some serious gear. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_136">
        <text>Damn…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_137">
        <text>He was probably looking for a place where he could set up an ambush. Our hero didn’t beat around the bush and the minute he saw it was a bandit he opened fire on him. A serious firefight ensued between the two. The stalker threw a few grenades from the top of the tower but the bandit was a tough one and he avoided those grenades like a pro. After that the two started shooting each other from behind cover and the fight lasted for hours. Finally after long night of shooting the bandit fell on the ground…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_138">
        <text>I am guessing the bandit was dead…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_139">
        <text>No matter how you spin, the stalker had a better position in that tower. After he shot down the bandit he went down to check on the body. When he went inside the building where the bandit was hiding it and saw the body, he froze from shock. It turned out that the bandit didn’t die from a bullet but rather when they were busy shooting each other a bloodsucker snuck in and broke the guy’s neck. Before the stalker could even close his mouth, the bloodsucker killed him as well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_14">
        <text>That was some luck out there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_140">
        <text>The bloodsucker got a 2 for 1 deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_141">
        <text>If only those two would have just put their differences aside, they would have lived to fight another day. Instead of everyone going their own separate way in the morning, they are both dead and all for not. But that’s too much to ask for; we can’t help but shoot at each other.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_142">
        <text>Hey, sometimes people can help, only it’s not in Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_143">
        <text>Man, have I got weird story for…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_144">
        <text>Things are werid enough already but I guess it can’t hurt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_145">
        <text>One stalker went to the Zone to search for his beloved girl who was known to the people of the Zone as Sneguruchka. I don’t know why she got that nickname. She was average in the looks department, nothing special, although some say she had nice personality. The guy that was looking for her on the other hand was a total scumbag but that’s how it usually is. The good ones always fall for the bad ones.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_146">
        <text>Yeah, I think we’ve all seen an instance of that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_147">
        <text>The two finally found each other and went to the bloodsucker village. You know the one in near the Army Warehouses. Bloodsuckers would always flock to that place for some reason but it was possible to survive there. That village had a group of stalkers there, a real bunch of assholes who would steal loot from dead bodies and sense this was the army warehouses a lot of experienced stalkers with good loot would die there. Sneguruchka and her boyfriend were members of said group and despite the fact that the girl felt sick from the whole thing she would stay there because she wanted to be with her boyfriend.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_148">
        <text>She was an idiot…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_149">
        <text>Hey, what can you do? You can’t pick who you love. Anyway, one time this group of raiders had disagreement about who gets what loot. As for our heroine, it was the worst day of her life. The raiders took out all of their frustration out on her by torturing and raping her. Thinking about it makes me sick. She was locked up in the water tower all day and night. However, strange things tend to happen in the Zone…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_15">
        <text>Just as it seemed the stalker and his friend were done for, things turned for the better. While the stalker was exchanging fire with the monolithians, his zombified friend stood up and instead of attacking the stalker he just stood and looked at him for a second and after that covered his friend from enemy fire with his own body thus saving him. The monolithians were shocked when it happened because zombies are supposed to be their biggest alley and yet here we are. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_150">
        <text>Hopefully, it would be something that would aid our heroine. Poor woman, being tortured like that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_151">
        <text>A controller had entered the village and he had killed the majority of the group in a matter of seconds. The few that remained claimed up the tower and barricaded themselves from within. That didn’t help much though, obviously. The controller broke the door apart and slaughtered everyone inside but do you know what the strange part is?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_152">
        <text>What?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_153">
        <text>The controller didn’t touch the girl! Makes no sense but that’s what happened. He just left her there and ordered his zombies not to touch her. Nobody can explain why it happened the way it did it but the Zone saved the girl’s life, a real miracle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_154">
        <text>I’m at loss for words…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_155">
        <text>The only thing we can know for sure is that this forsaken place we call the Zone doesn’t only destroy people but it helps people from time to time. The only thing that is certain is that nobody knows how the Zone works.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_156">
        <text>Risking your life for answers isn’t always the best solution, some things are meant to remain a mystery.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_158">
        <text>Sorry, I don’t have anything interesting right now… I ran out of stories.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_16">
        <text>Yeah, that is highly unlikely.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_17">
        <text>The zombie just kept covering his friend while his buddy was crawling towards the trees. When the stalker got to the tree they looked at each other for a second, and said their goodbyes non-verbally. After that the stalker ran away and managed to get back to the barrier. Sense then, that stalker never harms any zombies and instead just passes them by. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_18">
        <text>Yeah, I can kinda get him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_19">
        <text>As for his zombified friend, some say that to this day he wanders around in radioactive forests and protects lost stalkers. And that meeting him is a sign that great fortune will come to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_2">
        <text>Hello, good sir, what brings you here? Everyone calls me Storyteller because I like to tell story whilst I drink some vodka. If you give me a bottle, I might tell you something interesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_20">
        <text>Even though the story ended with a bit of hope, it was still very depressing. All right, I got to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_21">
        <text>There are some people who have special talents and abilities out there. There was a stalker here who was totally immune to psy-emission. He could walk right through with out a scratch.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_22">
        <text>Let’s say that’s somehow poissble…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_23">
        <text>One might think that this stalker was some kind of zombie but that can’t be further from the truth. In reality, this stalker was actually were smart and used his gift well. He respected the Zone’s boundaries and he would never go to places he wasn’t supposed to. Sometimes he wouldn’t go past the scorcher at all despite being able to do that without any harm. He would bring unique artifacts from his raids which would earn him a lot of money. He never hesitated to help out a fellow stalker so most people respected him even though he had his share of enemies. But he was a good fighter and he always had good gear to boot so taking him down wasn’t easy and therefore most preferred not mess with him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_24">
        <text>Go on…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_25">
        <text>He was also really careful. Despite being well equipped he would rather stay away from conflict. That’s why he made camp in one of abandon hangers in Yantar. The psy-emissions there were on full throttle and anybody who would go there would turn into a zombie instantly, unless it was our guy of course. How did he protect himself from the mutants and zombies though, I do not know. But he lived there pretty quietly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_26">
        <text>Looks the guy was living the good life…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_27">
        <text>Everything would have been well and good except one time a controller came to those same hangers. Of course, try as it might, the controller couldn’t take control of the stalker but still it made his life miserable. Nobody knew for sure what went down there. He only mentioned his problem a few times, saying he tried to kill the controller a few times but that it got away. That’s not the main point of the story though…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_28">
        <text>What’s the point then? I’m dying to know…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_29">
        <text>One time a group of experienced stalker was moving through Yantar and they ran into that same controller. They were all good fighters so they decided to kill that creature for good. So then they carefully backed the controller into a corner and you know what happened then? That same stalker, who was living in Yantar, started shooting at the group from his sniper rifle. He managed to kill half them and the rest escaped. Who knows why he did it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_3">
        <text>All right, heres a bottle… Tell me something interesting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_30">
        <text>That stalker must’ve lost his mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_31">
        <text>The stalkers who travelled to Yantar have told stories about those two. They told that, even though the controller and that stalker were at each other’s throats all day, they would protect each other when there was an outside threat. Nobody could find an explanation to why this was happening and thus it was just considered another mystery in the Zone. After a while, the duo disappeared somewhere and nobody saw either one of them sense.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_32">
        <text>A mystery indeed, I don’t even know what to think.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_33">
        <text>Here’s what I think: If you have nemesis with whom you are at conflict for a very long time then you get used to them and then ending that relationship becomes very difficult.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_34">
        <text>I doubt that’s the case, but it’s possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_35">
        <text>I’ll tell you a story, if not necessarily scary then definitely creepy. I take it you heard about the “Concentration Camp” down in garbage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_36">
        <text>Yeah, I heard about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_37">
        <text>I’ll tell you what: Garbage was always a god awful place. Even back before the incident in ’86 the place was used as dump were all the unneeded radioactive waste was thrown and buried. Near every junk heap there was a work station where the workers would dump the trash. However, the only station that remind to this day is the one we call the junkyard. Many people died there due working accidents and those that didn’t were afraid to talk about it, fearing that would be killed for talking too much. That’s why you don’t really hear about it. Anyway, after the incident Garbage was just left like that with all the junk and tools intact…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_38">
        <text>Go on…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_39">
        <text>Even back then there were death traps on every corner, ammunition exploding, gasoline in cars catching fire even and sometimes huge metal parts falling on people from out nowhere and killing them. Nobody could explain what was happening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_4">
        <text>I’m not in the mood for stories.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_40">
        <text>Okay…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_41">
        <text>When the Zone emerged, everyone flocked to Garbage immediately, either just for artifacts or because it was a good place strategically. At first Duty tried to take over the place and make it safe for regular stalkers, getting rid of mutants and such. They would also deal with any stalker who was robbing and killing his fellow men.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_42">
        <text>Hey, its a decent thing to do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_43">
        <text>Only it didn’t last for long. Duty made a small base inside an old bunker and would hide there during blowouts. Only one time when a blowout was coming they all ran inside their bunker to wait it out, only to find out they were trapped. The blowout changed the positions of all the anomalies in such way that they would block off every entrance to the bunker. All the duty members there died of starvation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_44">
        <text>That’s a brutal way to die, wouldn’t wish it on my worst enemey.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_45">
        <text>What followed was no less brutal. At first, Freedom tried to make a base in Garbage but the constant mutant attacks at night prevented them from doing so. Regular loner stalkers also tried to establish something of a base for anyone who was coming back from a long trip to the Zone and needed to quickly resupply, get some sleep or to sell off some unneeded gear. But like everyone else they didn’t last for very long. One guy came back with a virus which he caught somewhere deep in the Zone and even though the stalkers figured out quickly that an infection was among them, the base still had to be turned into a quarantine area where no one could get in or out. As for the sick, they all died there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_46">
        <text>Fucking horrifc…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_47">
        <text>Yeah, you said it. No matter what happened or who came over to this to this giant dumpster it always ended badly. As of now, the bandits are occupying garbage and the junkyard they call the concentration camp. Little do they know that the ones who are going to die soon are not only the stalkers they are holding prisoners but they themselves as well. Even though they are total assholes I still for sorry for them, they are still people after all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_48">
        <text>Sure… All right, gotta go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_49">
        <text> Even though women aren’t exactly common in the Zone and most stalkers only catch glimpses of them in porn mags but from time to time you can encounter a woman here. Not that you can expect anything good from them coming here, only problems. I have a story about a woman stalker…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_50">
        <text>All right, lay it on me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_51">
        <text>Garbage which is now taken over bandits was once a place where experienced stalkers would go to get some rest after a long journey and resupply. The trader there was a chick named Matrona who would sell gear and food to those same stalkers, although her prices were through the roof but that only scared off the rookies. Other than that though, her business was doing very well and she would always cash out with a smile on her face. Also, she would drink a lot of vodka, she was a real alcoholic.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_52">
        <text>guilty conscience, perhaps?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_53">
        <text>Anyway, one time a guy was unlucky enough to fall in love with her! He ran after her all day and night bringing her gifts and shit. Sometimes he would even serenade her with his guitar during the evenings. Although, it annoyed everyone else so they made him wrap it up quickly. It was obvious the guy was totally obsessed with her.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_54">
        <text>Yeah, not the first time I’m hearing about a guy losing his head over a chick… What about Matrona?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_55">
        <text>She would only wink at him from time to time with her green eyes and milk him for all his goods. Everyone felt sick just watching it, even the bandits felt bad for the guy. But what can you do to help a guy in a situation like this? Not much. Everyone just shook their hands and waited until this mess would reach its awful conclusion.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_56">
        <text>So what was the conclusion?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_57">
        <text>Things ended badly. One time she was drunk as usual wondering around in garbage but thing was, that she was so drunk she couldn’t even see a vortex right in front of her. She couldn’t even realize what was going on before the anomaly ripped her to shreds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_58">
        <text>Can’t feel much sympathy for her… What about our Romeo? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_59">
        <text>He completely lost his mind. He wanted to find the wish granter and wish her back so he went passed the barrier. After a while a few freedomers saw his zombified ass marching back from the barrier alongside a few monolithians and zombies. All that was left of him was shell with animal like tendencies and all humanity from him drained, like anyone else who tried to go past the barrier before him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_6">
        <text>Hello, young man. If you share a bottle of vodka with me, I’ll tell you an interesting story. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_60">
        <text>Yeah, poor guy. All right, I’ll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_61">
        <text>I’ll tell you a story about two guys who met up in the concentration camp.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_62">
        <text>I’m all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_63">
        <text>The stalkers who, for the most, end up in concentration camp are those who had enough courage to visit Garbage but not enough money to pay the bandits. Because these stalkers can’t pay their “debt” for entering the bandit’s territory, they are forced to work their asses off looking for anything valuable in the junk heaps. This of course stops eventually when the bandits decide to kill their prisoners off. To this day that death prison is full of stalkers who didn’t have enough money to pay off the bandits.  However, one time two individuals met up inside that camp that if they were anywhere else, then would have been at each other’s throat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_64">
        <text>Go on…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_65">
        <text>The two dudes that I’m talking about were a dutyer and a freedomer!  Why nobody tried to rescue them, I don’t know. Perhaps, it was because everyone thought they were dead or something. It’s not that hard to believe considering how many people go missing in the Zone every day. But that’s not the gist of this story…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_66">
        <text>So what’s the gist?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_67">
        <text>Those two decided to put their differences a side and plan an escape. They were the only two capable stalkers in the camp and nobody was going to know that they helped each other. So the two decided to put their principles aside and form an alliance and a pretty strong one, I might add. So after a while the two managed to escape from the bandits, while they were doing another one of their archeological digs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_68">
        <text>So how did the manage to escape?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_69">
        <text>I don’t know for sure but I heard that they used an artifact as weapon. They found it in one of the junk piles and did something to it which turned it back into an anomaly.  They say that if you spin an artifact in your hand the right way and poke it in the right places, it will turn back in to an anomaly. I can’t say for sure because I have no idea how to do this but I do know people who are experts in this craft.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_7">
        <text>I have a cool story for you. It starts with two good friends going in to red forest to look for those high tier artifacts and to hunt some big game.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_70">
        <text>That’s too bad…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_71">
        <text>Anyway, both of them managed to escape and ran to the nearest Freedom outpost. They could see the light at the end of the tunnel but alas fate played a cruel trick on them. A Freedom sniper saw the dutyer and took him out with one shot, a real tragedy. The freedomer was devastated and instead of running further away from the bandits he just sat there crying about his dead friend while the bandits were getting closer and closer. But you know what happened then?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_72">
        <text>Stop making me guess, just tell me. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_73">
        <text>Everyone died except for the freedomer who was on the run. The bandits and the freedomers at the outpost started fighting until they killed each other while our escapee was weeping over his dead friend. When the smoke cleared everyone was dead expect for him, I guess the Zone spared him for some reason. After that he left Freedom and became a total hermit who now spends his time exploring caves and other abandoned places in the Zone. Who knew things would turn out this way…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_74">
        <text>Yeah… Anyway, I got to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_75">
        <text>Have you heard anything about duty’s zoo?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_76">
        <text>Not much, I know it exists but that’s about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_77">
        <text>It’s a really weird and creepy place. Stuffed mutant cracusses gawk at you with their empty eyes while being lined up one after the other. The guy who organized this zoo, Inquisitor is his name, isn’t exactly normal as well as one might guess. I don’t know how much you know about that zoo but I bet you don’t how and why that guy organized that zoo in the first place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_78">
        <text>All right then, tell me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_79">
        <text>Legend has it, that he had a very expensive old watch gifted to him either by his granddad or great granddad. I don’t know for sure how he got that watch and it’s not that important. What’s important is that this watch was very valuable and therefore the Inquisitor would carry his timepiece with him at all time so that no could steal it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_8">
        <text>Great start.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_80">
        <text>What does this have to do with the zoo exactly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_81">
        <text>If you would stop interrupting I could actually to that. So one time the guy ran into a blood sucker in some dark alley and he barely managed to fight it off. He survived but so did the bloodsucker. Though, not only did the bloodsucker survive but he also managed to drag away the Inquisitor’s watch in his teeth… Or rather his tentacles or perhaps even he swallowed them whole… Who knows? Either way the Inquisitor lost something really valuable that day. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_82">
        <text>That’s kind of funny…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_83">
        <text> Our hero got really pissed that time. He then spent a few good days with his shotgun searching for his lost watch. He was so angry he committed bloodsucker genocide in there by killing at least a dozen bloodsuckers and slicing them open in hope of finding his lost wristwatch. He couldn’t find anything though, no matter how hard he tried.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_84">
        <text>Shit happens.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_85">
        <text>However, sense then that guy had developed a knack for capturing and dissecting mutants. It’s like he found some kind of hidden talent. Some say that to this day his looking for his lost watch but no ones for sure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_86">
        <text>You know, if he would put out a decent reward for that watch, then people would find it in no time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_87">
        <text>I know one thing for sure, that sometimes the bad things in life are fate’s way of setting us on the right path. Just like the Inquisitor who after losing his watch, found his new talent.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_88">
        <text>I doubt that. Bad shit happens to me all the time and it hasn’t yielded any benefit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_89">
        <text>Have you ever been to duty’s zoo?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_9">
        <text>They got pretty far and they’ve collected a lot of good loot along the way but greed got the better of them and they decided to keep pushing further. So they kept pushing and inch by inch they wandered right into the brain scorcher area. You can be sure that those two were paralyzed from fear when they saw those antennas over the horizon…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_90">
        <text>I heard about it…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_91">
        <text>It doesn’t matter that much to be honest. The important part is that the zoo doesn’t have a controller’s stump in it and by the looks of it all, it never will. Obtaining an intact body of a controller is just way to dangerous and there’s no way the leader will allow for such thing after the last incident.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_92">
        <text>So what’s the point of this story?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_93">
        <text>The point is that once duty tried to obtain an intact carcass of a controller, the first one they could find. They wanted to shoot him with a sniper rifle between the eyes and thus leaving most of his body intact. They knew of a controller lair not far from their base in a nearby forest. The mutant was living in a small cave and it would only come out at night to hunt for food.  So the dutyers decide that it’s an easy target and sniping it from a far won’t be a problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_94">
        <text>Yeah, I hunted a few controllers for a few clients.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_95">
        <text>So then a squad of dutyers made camp on top of a helm not far from the controller’s lair. Their Plan was just to wait for the controller to come out of his cave and then snipe him. However, despite them waiting for a few days straight, the controller didn’t come out of his home, it’s like he knew they were there. Slowly but surely the squad was running out of food and water however the dutyers didn’t want get back to base empty handed so they continued waiting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_96">
        <text>Bad move.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_97">
        <text>That’s for sure. They couldn’t occupy their new position in time and the controller managed to fry up their brains. The controller turned out to be an experienced one and could easily sense that he was being watched by a group of stalkers. Everyone was zombifed expect for one guy who barely managed to escape and even he suffered some serious brain damage. Sense that hunting trip, that guy can’t even speak normally. He constantly stators, he cannot even finish a sentence.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_98">
        <text>Well, we all have our battle scars.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_storyman_tell_story_99">
        <text>The gist of this story is that one of the stalkers that were zombified in that hunting trip was the brother of Krilov, the leader of duty.  When Krilov found about this he strictly prohibited anybody from going anywhere in that lair. Thing is Krilov doesn’t want one anyone killing his brother because he is hoping that one day scientists can find the cure for zombification and save his sibling.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_0">
        <text>I’m here about the instruments.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_1">
        <text>What about them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_2">
        <text>I used to bring Wagon instruments.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_3">
        <text>Yeah, if you find anything, bring it here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_barkas_instr_4">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_0">
        <text>I brought some instruments.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_1">
        <text>Cool, which type?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_11">
        <text>For basic work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_111">
        <text>Excellent! Now if only you’d bring me tools for fine work and for calibration.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_12">
        <text>For fine work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_121">
        <text>Excellent! Now if only you would bring tools for basic work and for calibration.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_13">
        <text>Tools for calibrtion.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_131">
        <text>Excellent! Now if only you would bring tools for basic and fine work…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_14">
        <text>Nothing yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_141">
        <text>Awesome! Now if you’d bring tools for calibration and I’d be all set.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_151">
        <text>Awesome! Now if you’d bring tools for fine work and I’d be all set.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_161">
        <text>Awesome! Now if you’d bring tools for basic work and I’d be all set.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_171">
        <text>Nice! Where did you find them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_0">
        <text>If you need instruments then I can help you find them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_1">
        <text>That’d be great! It feels like I’m in the Stone Age with my current tools.  The only modern thing I have here is a soldering iron and even it isn’t that good. Now if you would bring the right tools then I could really start making some serious upgrades.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_11">
        <text>Okay, I’ll try to find something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_12">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tech_instruments_work_3">
        <text>All right, I need upgrades and you need tools so It’s a win win situation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_1">
        <text>Hey, you still need those tools?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_2">
        <text>Of course I do! Show me what you got.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_3">
        <text>I got tools for basic work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_4">
        <text>Great, now can start modifying weapons and arms.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_5">
        <text>I got tools for fine work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_6">
        <text>Great, now can start working on adavanced upgrades.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_7">
        <text>I got tools for calibration.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_8">
        <text>Excellent! Now can turn your gun into high powered killing machine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tex_instryments_9">
        <text>Nothing yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_off_0">
        <text>Sidorovich, turn off the radio.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_off_1">
        <text>All right, I’m sick of it myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_off_2">
        <text>Sure. What, you got a headache?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_off_3">
        <text>What, You don’t like my music? So be it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_on_0">
        <text>Sidorovich, Turn on the radio.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_on_1">
        <text>You want some music? Sure, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_on_2">
        <text>All right, I  am also in the mood for some music.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_radio_on_3">
        <text>Sure, here you go. Listen to your hearts content.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_0">
        <text>Anything interesting around here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_1">
        <text>Not really. This place is mostly for rookies and for people who came back from long trips looking to sell of their loot. There’s the army outpost south of here so beware of them. North of here there’s a road leading to Garbage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_11">
        <text>Tell me about the rookie village.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_111">
        <text>There’s not much to say. This is where most rookies end up but after gaining some money and experience they move further north. This place is sort of the starting point for stalkers and anybody who isn’t total wimp leaves this place after a short while. There are some idiots who stay here because they can’t handle themselves anywhere else in the Zone but that’s about it. From time to time you can see an experience stalker walking through here to sell their loot to Sidorovich and to get some rest in a quiet place for a few days.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_1111">
        <text>How about the military, do they bother you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_11111">
        <text>Not really. We sort of have a non-verbal agreement, we don’t bother them and they don’t bother us. They say themselves that they rather not risk their lives fighting with stalkers who will mostly likely die in anomalies any way. And it’s the same for us, we rather not get in their way. When the military is doing a raid or looking for something we move out of the way and let them do their job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_22">
        <text>Tell me about Sidorovich.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_around_222">
        <text>He is the go to trader in Cordon. His main clients are rookies who only recently got to the Zone.  He has lots of connections in and outside the Zone. They say he started trading in his youth and that He sold weed when he was in college. He’s highly respected by stalkers for his honest business but at the same time he’s disliked for his greed and selfishness. One thing’s for sure he gave a lot of stalkers an opportunity to survive and without him they would probably be dead. He also has the richest business in Zone. If Sidorovich doesn’t have something then you’re not going to find it anywhere else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_you_0">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_you_1">
        <text>I’m sort of a leader here. I teach the rookies how to live and survive in the Zone. As for me I had enough time to wonder around the Zone and I am sick of it. I came here to cordon, to leave the Zone a long time ago but sense then something has been holding me here, like I’m under a spell or something. Every time I try to leave something gets in the way, either the military is doing a raid or blowout starts at the wrong time. Sometimes I get offered a job so good you can’t pass it by.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_1">
        <text>Right now we are in Cordon, the Zone’s border. Down south there’s an army outpost which guarding the entrance to this place and further north there’s a road leading to Garbage. This place still somewhat resembles the outside world sense there are barely any artifacts or anomalies here. You can see some wild boars here once in a while but other than that it’s totally quiet. Well it’s quiet in comparison with the rest of the Zone that is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_about_zone_111">
        <text>This place is mostly for rookies and for people who came back from long trips looking to sell of their loot. There’s the army outpost south of here so beware of them. North of here there’s a road leading to Garbage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wolf_quest_insurance_dialog_8">
        <text>Lead the way.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
