<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_10">
        <text>That creature, Pseudo-flesh is its name, is not as easy to kill as a regular flesh. Many people tell stories about it and even though I don’t really care much for legends, when I saw the creature myself I knew then that most of the stories about it were true. I remember one time I was walking around garbage when I heard a cry for help. I crouched and slowly started to make my way towards those screams but then I noticed something was off... The speech was all slurred and I could barely understand what was being said. So anyway, I crawled up to that place and hid behind the hood of an old Kamaz. I looked out and you wouldn’t believe what I saw and heard... That Pseudo-Flesh was screaming like human being. I wanted to kill it as quickly as possible but I couldn’t get my gun out in time and it escaped.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_11">
        <text>Interesting... and you think this mutant is here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_12">
        <text>Yeah. I’m telling you its lair is somewhere there, I can tell by its calm behavior. In that area there is a small cave where even in very hot and sunny days it still remains moist. The Pseudo-Flesh is most likely in it. When we get closer, you should attack from the hill that’s located to the right while I attack from the left. When you see that awful creature make it run towards me and I will finish it off. But watch your back there might be other mutants there. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_13">
        <text>Got it, should we go now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_14">
        <text>Yes, we need to move quickly and get rid of this threat once and for all. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_15">
        <text>Show me the way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_17">
        <text>Yeah, we did it, we finally slayed this god awful creature. This is the creature, I am sure of it, just like I’ve seen it back then. Well, a deal’s a deal, you’ve helped me and in return I will help you. When I’ll be leaving the stronghold, I’ll take you with me. Also, here take this, extra payment for a good job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_18">
        <text>Don’t mention it. If you need anything else, you know where to find me. What are we gonna do now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_19">
        <text>I’ll keep that in mind. Well, you can go back to base, as for me I want to study this mutant a bit, maybe I can find take something off this mutant that’s worth selling. When I’ll be leaving the Stronghold, I’ll send you a message. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_2">
        <text>Hey, merc! I take it, you talked to Rasputin?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_20">
        <text>Alright, see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_22">
        <text>Listen, I can’t seem to find it... It’s hiding somewhere deep and finding it is going to take forever.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_23">
        <text>Maybe someone killed it already.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_24">
        <text>I doubt that. If someone would have managed to pull that off then we would be hearing about it nonstop. If there’s something hunters like doing is bragging about their kills. If one of them would have hunted the creature down then the entire Stronghold would have known about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_25">
        <text>Alright, so what are we going to do now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_26">
        <text>We need to inspect the other part of this dump. Let’s go to the place where I first saw it, maybe will find it there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_27">
        <text>Alright, let’s go then...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_29">
        <text>You can go back to base, when I’ll be leaving the Stronghold, I’ll message you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_3">
        <text>Yeah, I talked to him. Listen, Rasputin said that you along with some other stalker, Savage I think, tried to blow up the monolithian construction site. Did you manage to pull it off?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_31">
        <text>So Rasputin said that you and a stalker, Savage I think, tried to blow up the construction site that’s occupied by monolithans. Did you succeed?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_32">
        <text>No, I don’t want to talk about it. Can you we leave the Stronghold already?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_33">
        <text>Well yeah, that’s why I came here. I’m going to the bar, I have some business there. And after that I will head to Yantar, if you want you can come with. I’m heading out right now, are you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_34">
        <text>Yean, I’m ready, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_4">
        <text>Sure I can do that but not for free. Money is not what I need though, instead I need your help with a mission. If you help me with that then I will take you with me when I’ll be leaving the Stronghold. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_5">
        <text>Alright, what sort of help do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_6">
        <text>I need your help find and killing a certain mutant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_7">
        <text>Why won’t you ask any of the hunters? they have more experince in that sort of thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_8">
        <text>Well, the thing is that I’m hunting this mutant for the scientists, they’ve asked me to bring a piece of its flesh for further research. They promised to pay I hefty sum for a job well done but if I take the entire group then everyone would want a piece and there isn’t enough to go around for everyone. Taking only one person with me is also out of the question as it can create unnecessary conflict if you know what I mean. I rather take someone from outside our group and not tell them that I’m doing this in the first place, it’s better this way. So, are you with me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_hunter_9">
        <text>Sure, I’ll help you. First though, tell me what mutant are we hunting here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_11">
        <text>Hey Beast, what’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_12">
        <text>Not yet... Yeah and I doubt I’ll ever forget about it. Either way we made it out and that’s what’s important and now we can get back on with our lives. Soon, perhaps, I could see my family again. As for now though, I need some alone time, I’ll talk to you later...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_13">
        <text>Alright, I hope everything will turn out okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_2">
        <text>Finally you’re out, Beast. Man was that Saurel guy stubborn but I managed to convince him to free you. How are you feeling?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_3">
        <text>Not too bad... By the way, the guard told me that Marcus didn’t make it out of the anomaly what the hell happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_4">
        <text>Yeah, it’s true we couldn’t contact you or Marcus so Forester went back to look for you but he only found you. I hope everything’s alright with him. Being trapped alone inside the spatial anomaly must be maddening... Let’s hope that one Forester reach Red Forest he can send Marcus the coordinates and he can find his way out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_5">
        <text>Yeah, let’s all hope he can find his way out. So, how’s everyone else? Is anyone from our group still here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_6">
        <text>No, everyone left with the guide yesterday. You can’t blame them though, after what they’ve all been through. I won’t be surprised if most of them will leave the zone after this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_7">
        <text>Alright... And what about you, what plans do you have for the future?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_8">
        <text>I’m not planning to go anywhere any time soon, I’ve decided to stay in the Stronghold for a while and try to forget about that god forsaken anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_lutiy_9">
        <text>And have you managed to forget about it, even slightly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_0">
        <text>Looks like it’s over... Thanks merc, we wouldn’t have pulled it off alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_1">
        <text>You shouldn’t thank me just yet, there still a chance the bandits could attack again. Saurel told me that you found out about this attack by listening in on the bandits hidden radio frequency right? Do you have a radio tuned for said frequency?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_2">
        <text>Yeah totally, we should check if anyone was able to inform the bandits about our ambush.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_3">
        <text>Yeah, we need to know what the bandits are planning.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_end_0">
        <text>Damn it, they’ve sent another squad here, what should we do merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_marchuk_end_1">
        <text>Don’t panic, you two should get back to your position and prepare for our “guests”, as for me I’m going to back to my sniper spot in the attic.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_10">
        <text>Yeah-yeah, I know that already. Just listen till the end and then decide, okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_11">
        <text>Go on, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_12">
        <text>I bet you know about the big monolith platoon nearby right? Well, these assholes have been a thorn in everyone’s ass for a long time. Those assholes have killed five of my guys alone. But I doubt I need to tell you how these monolithians are a threat to everyone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_13">
        <text>And...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_14">
        <text>To make matters worse they are always receiving backup and ammunition from somewhere and their base is constantly growing. Soon there won’t be enough room for all of them and they will take over the whole Stronghold, killing all of us off in the process. It would seem as though the only option is to get out of here but not long ago we managed to find out who is in command of this platoon. Werewolf is his name but that’s not the only thing we know, we also know how to kill him without taking any casualties. And perhaps even wipe out some of his close friends while we are at it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_15">
        <text>Interesting... And how do you plan to pull it off?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_16">
        <text>Swift and quietly. Two days ago, one of my fighters pulled out a guy out of a Zharka and he turned out be a monolithian and not just any regular monolithian but one of high rank in Werewolf’s platoon. We managed to get some info out of him. It turns out that tomorrow Werewolf is heading for a meeting with some other high ranking officer in the monolith army. This meeting will take place in the factory with a minimal amount of security.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_17">
        <text>And you think that two important monolith officers won’t have good security with them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_18">
        <text>I never said that. Obviously, the people guarding the Werewolf and that other dude would be real professionals but the thing is that this meeting is so top secret that a regular monolith soldier won’t even know about it.  We need all the help we can get here. To tell the truth, at first I didn’t want any outside help but because these assholes have iced five of our best guys we have little to no chance of pulling off this operation now. That’s why we are taking all the help we can find and we could really use the help of a skilled fighter such as you. So what do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_19">
        <text>I need to think about it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_2">
        <text>No pasaran! Hey, Beast, it’s good to see you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_20">
        <text>Alright, Miklucha, I’m down with the job...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_21">
        <text>There’s no time to think. The meeting is going to take place soon and we need to use the remaining time to prepare for the assault. More than that though, we most likely won’t get another chance like this one seeing how the number of monolithian is only increasing and soon they will wipe us all out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_22">
        <text>I knew you were a good dude. Alright, if you’re in then we should get moving to the factory and prepare for the ambush as soon as we get there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_23">
        <text>Show me the way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_25">
        <text>I can’t talk now Beast, I’m too busy...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_3">
        <text>Do I know you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_4">
        <text>Oh yeah, I forgot to introduce myself. My name’s Miklucha, I am the commander of this freedom squad. As for you, there’s no need for an introduction, I’ve already heard all about you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_5">
        <text>And what have you heard about me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_6">
        <text>Nothing too good to be honest. However, I do know for a fact that you are a professional and I just so happen to need someone like you for a job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_7">
        <text>What’s the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_8">
        <text>I need someone really dangerous taken out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_miklucha_9">
        <text>Sorry, I can’t help you with that. I’m done being a hitman.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_0">
        <text>Greetings, monolith servant, what brings you here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_1">
        <text>We came here to strengthen you the monolith’s force on this earth.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_2">
        <text>We didn’t expect any backup today... Where do you come from and why is there only two of you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_3">
        <text>I and five others were sent here by our priest. We came here through Limansk and our path was full of tests and challenges which the monolith prepared for us. However not everyone withstood the monolith’s test and only two of us survived. We were supposed to get here a few days later but the monolith showed us a faster way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_4">
        <text>Bless the monolith, for he is the one who help you get here. As for your fallen brothers, don’t worry, all is for the good of the monolith.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_leader_5">
        <text>I’ll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_scene_0">
        <text>Thank the monolith, infidel, for he is the one who spared your life... If it was up to me, I would have killed you on the spot but the monolith forbids me to do so because he choice you for his trail. We are holding your friend hostage by the way, just in case you want to save him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_scene_1">
        <text>You have Savage? What the fuck kind of sick game are you playing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_scene_2">
        <text>Silence, infidel! I am the only one who is allowed to speak here. I’ve marked a place on your pda in which your friend is located. If you want to save him, I suggest you go there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_monolit_scene_3">
        <text>Yeah, I don’t need your suggestions, go fuck yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_11">
        <text>Alright, we’re here. I’m going to stay in the village for a while and if you need my services then I’ll be here in the neighboring house. Good luck, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_12">
        <text>Hey.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_14">
        <text>Hey, merc. You need to get somewhere?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_16">
        <text>Can you get me to the metal factory?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_17">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_18">
        <text>Sure I can. More than that, since you’re doing Saurel’s assignment I won’t charge you money for this trip. So, are you ready to move out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_19">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_2">
        <text>Hello, merc. Are you the one who iced these bandits? I was nearby and I heard some gunshots so I decided to check what’s what. I thought the bandits are attacking stalkers again and that I could lend a hand.  Needless to say, no help was needed. What about you? Are you looking for something or are you just passing through?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_20">
        <text>Well, we’re here. I’ll wait for you here for a while... When you decide to get back to the northern village come back here, just keep in mind that I won’t wait for you too long.  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_21">
        <text>Alirght then, I don’t think I’ll take long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_23">
        <text>So, merc, are you ready to get back the northern village?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_24">
        <text>Yeah, we need to tell Saurel that someone killed Lefty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_25">
        <text>Yeah, this is one hell of a situation... Lefty was a good dude even though he did kill his friend.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_26">
        <text>I doubt that Lefty is the one who killed Limp. Lefty also got killed which means there’s at the very least someone else involved in this mess. Mostly likely he’s trying to tie up any loose ends.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_27">
        <text>If you say so, it’s none of my business anyway. So are we heading back to the northern village or what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_28">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_3">
        <text>I was sent here by Saurel; that’s all you need to know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_30">
        <text>Hey merc, you need to get somewhere?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_31">
        <text>I need to get the metal factory again, will you get me there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_32">
        <text>Ofcourse. You helped us so I’ll help you... let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_33">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_35">
        <text>So are you ready to get back to the northern village.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_36">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_37">
        <text>I need to get to the anomalious grove, can you get me there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_38">
        <text>I’d be happy to get you there but the problem is that place is always filled with either boars or bandits. I much rather just get you to the village that’s nearby where it’s way safer and then you can continue on your own. I can also get you to the metal factory which is not that far off, if you like. So, what do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_39">
        <text>A freedomer by the name of Miklucha told me to come by; he gave me his coordinates. His location way far off and I need someone to show me a safe path. Can you do that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_4">
        <text>So you’re that mercenary who was trapped inside that spatial anomaly? In that case, I won’t ask too many questions. Just tell me one thing: are you heading to the northern village by any chance?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_40">
        <text>I need to get to the old school, can you lead me there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_41">
        <text>Alright, let’s go to that village.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_42">
        <text>Tell you what, lead me to the metal factory and from there I’ll go on my own.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_43">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_46">
        <text>Miklucha? Yeah, I know the guy. He organized a small base with his buds in the old school. We can head out right now, if you like. So, are you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_47">
        <text>Yeah, Let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_48">
        <text>Sorry merc, I can’t get you to the old school, seeing how freedom has abandoned it and I’ve heard that bandits have taken over that place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_49">
        <text>Fine, forget about it then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_5">
        <text>yeah, I’m going there; I need to talk to Saurel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_50">
        <text>Will you get me to the village near the anomalious grove?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_51">
        <text>Yeah, no problem. Are you ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_52">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_53">
        <text>Sure, no problem. Are you ready to move out now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_54">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_6">
        <text>Wanna go together? I know all the safe routes around these parts, plus it’s less boring this way</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_7">
        <text>Are you a guide? Can you get me out of the Stronghold?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_8">
        <text>No. I’m just a guy who knows the insides of this place but as for getting out of here, that’s a whole different story. The area around the Stronghold is filled with dangerous anomalous and only a real pro can lead you out of here safely. We have a guide who hangs in the northern village, I don’t know if he’s there right now though. So are you coming or what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_provodnik_9">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_11">
        <text>Hey Beast, What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_13">
        <text>Saurel told me that Lefty’s dead, is that true.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_14">
        <text>Afraid so. Rasputin, can you help me with something? You pretty much know every stalker in base right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_15">
        <text>May he rest in peace...  As for the stalkers here, Yeah, I know all of them, I’m the barman after all. Why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_16">
        <text>Can you tell to whom, this knife belongs to?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_17">
        <text>That’s Chemist’s knife, he was looking for it all over the place. He was really nervous he couldn’t find it, kept yelling and cursing while messing up the place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_18">
        <text>Where is he now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_19">
        <text>When he was looking for the knife, he said he remembered where he left and that was going there to take it. Give the knife to chemist when you can.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_2">
        <text>Hey, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_20">
        <text>Alright, I’ll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_22">
        <text>Hey, merc. You wanna buy something or what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_24">
        <text>You here on buisness, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_26">
        <text>So it turns out Chemist Killed Lefty? Damn, he had us all fooled... At least that asshole’s dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_27">
        <text>I made him pay for what he did. Listen, I still have his knife... Maybe you wanna buy it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_28">
        <text>I made him pay for what he did.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_29">
        <text>Hmm... It’s a good knife, so I’ll give you 3000 rubles for it, deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_3">
        <text>I’m not a mercenary anymore. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_30">
        <text>Deal, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_31">
        <text>Nah, I’ll keep it for myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_32">
        <text>Alright, here’s you cash. So are you in here on buisness or what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_33">
        <text>Man, why you gotta be like that? Fine, I’ll buy it for 4500 rubles, that’s the most I’m willing to pay for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_34">
        <text>Fine, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_35">
        <text>Money isn’t the problem here, It’s just that this knife might come in handy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_36">
        <text>Great! Here’s your cash. By the way, are you here on business or did you just come here to sell the knife?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_37">
        <text>Fine, if you don’t want to sell it, it’s your choice. I was wondering... Are you here on business or did you just come here for a drink? If it’s the former, I have some jobs I need taken care of. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_38">
        <text>Man, thanks for getting rid of that scumbag. I was wondering... Are you here on business or did you just come here for a drink? If it’s the former, I have some jobs I need taken care of.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_39">
        <text>Yeah, Saurel told me that you might have some jobs for me and seeing as how the guide won’t be here for a while, I might as well earn some extra cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_4">
        <text>Sure thing pal... There’s no such thing as an ex-mercenary. Everyone calls me Rasputin here by the way and you are Beast right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_40">
        <text>Yeah, I have a job for you, nothing too hard... So, one of my regulars spotted a rare artifact inside the anomalous grove near the metal factor. The artifact in question is a “Kolobok” and I want it. The guy who told me about, couldn’t get it. He told me that the artifact is located on the tallest tree there and when he tried to get he fell off the tree and almost broke his neck. Anyway, can you do this for me? All you have to do get the artifact and comeback.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_41">
        <text>Are you sure it’s still there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_42">
        <text>I doubt anyone managed to get their hands on it, it’s not like we have many rock climbers here.  I’ll even give you a “veles” detector so you can find what I need more easily. So, are you in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_43">
        <text>Alright, I’ll get you that artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_44">
        <text>Great! Here’s the detector and coordinates to that place in case you forgot where it is.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_45">
        <text>Got it. Alright, I’ll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_47">
        <text>Have you gotten that aritfact yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_48">
        <text>Yeah, I’ve got the artifact. It took some real effort getting that thing, what’s more is after I’ve got it, I was ambushed by bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_49">
        <text>You don’t say? And what did you do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_5">
        <text>Okay...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_50">
        <text>It doesn’t matter, the important thing is the artifact is with me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_51">
        <text>Nothing, I just ran off with the artifact, and they couldn’t catch up to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_52">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_53">
        <text>You did the right thing, they got what they deserved. The bandits have really gotten out of control and this isn’t the first time they are robbing someone here. Alright, give me the artifact. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_54">
        <text>Here you go..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_55">
        <text>Man, have these bandits gotten out of control; this isn’t the first time they pull this shit. Someone needs to tell Stravid about this shit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_56">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_57">
        <text>And here’s your reward, just like I promised. If you find anymore artifacts bring them here, I’ll buy them from you, I take them at price higher than anyone else around here, you can trust me on that.  By the way, Saurel said he wanted to see you. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_58">
        <text>Here’s your reward, pleasure doing business with you, merc. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_59">
        <text>Alright, I’ll go see what he wants.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_6">
        <text>Listen, Beast, I know that Saurel told you to deal with Lefty but I doubt he is the want who killed Limp. They were good friends and they could kill for one another. I’ve never seen friendship as tight as theirs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_61">
        <text>Welcome to my bar, Beast. Are you here on buisness or just to chill?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_62">
        <text>I had the artifact but it was stolen by bandits. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_63">
        <text>×What!? And you let them steal it? I know you quit being a mercenary but this is too much. How could you just let them take the artifact? Yeah, I never thought you’d pull some like this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_64">
        <text>I don’t really care what you thought... I’m not going to risk my life for your artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_65">
        <text>Whatever, no point in arguing over it now. I should have asked someone else to this job anyway. By the way Saurel told me he wants to see you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_66">
        <text>Okay, I’ll go talk to him, later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_68">
        <text>Greetings, Beast! Listen, a stalker who hunts mutants came to the Stronghold not too long ago. He said he needs a good marksman for a job so I instantly thought of you. This stalker is the leader of the group of hunters that hangs out near the wagon and his nickname is Hunter. Have you heard about him before?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_69">
        <text>No, I haven’t heard of him. That’s one stupid nickname by the way, a hunter named Hunter. Do you know anything about him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_7">
        <text>So what? They were both dead drunk. Moreover, I’ve seen something similar happen before.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_70">
        <text>Oh, yeah, I have plenty of stories about Hunter, I’ve known him for a long time. As a matter of fact everyone knows and respects him... and some even fear him. He’s a good friend and partner and a good fighter. He has been everywhere in the zone and has been in it since 2006. He said himself that the zone is the best place for him. He adapted to this place quickly because even before the zone’s emergence he was a hunter. After he came to the zone he started selling mutant parts to people who needed them in the outside world. For a while he also worked as a guide for tourists who wanted to see the zone and hunt a few small mutants for fun. There’s rich people who would pay for something like that. One guy, an American, came here to make a documentary film about the zone. It was the first and last tourist lead by Hunter who died. Since then, Hunter stopped working as a guide for tourists. It’s also from where Hunter got his nickname. The American kept calling him “Hunter”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_71">
        <text>What does he need done?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_72">
        <text>I didn’t ask. Why don’t you go talk to him and see what he wants?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_73">
        <text>Alright, I’ll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_75">
        <text>>Welcome to my bar, Beast. Are you here on buisness or just to chill?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_76">
        <text>I think that you’ll make the right choice... By the way, if you want to make some extra cash then bring some mutant parts, I can pay for them. It’s one of the easiest ways of making money here in the Stronghold if you know how to field dress a mutant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_77">
        <text>Alright, I’ll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_8">
        <text>Even drunk, Lefty is not the guy who would kill his best friend. Beast, I’m only asking to let Lefty explain himself before you ice him. Maybe he’ll be able to convince you otherwise. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_shaman_9">
        <text>Alright, We’ll see how things pan out. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_10">
        <text>Well, he couldn’t have gotten very far. More than that, He’s still here in the Stronghold. Although, I don’t know where exactly. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_11">
        <text>alright, I’ll try to find him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_13">
        <text>What’s up, merc?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_15">
        <text>So Beast, have you dealt with our problem?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_16">
        <text>We haven’t even found out who even is the "problem", so no.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_17">
        <text>What’s that supposed to mean?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_18">
        <text>Lefty didn’t kill Limp. I talked to him and I could tell he wasn’t lying. Lefty told me about how he and Limp got some good loot and that they were drinking to celebrate and when they were drinking they told a few other guys about their successful raid, hence Lefty isn’t the only one with the motive to kill Limp. Also, when Lefty left after fighting with Limp he was captured by bandits so that means he couldn’t have made it back to base. It’s very unlikely that Lefty is the one who killed Limp.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_19">
        <text>Alright, Tell you what, bring Lefty here and we will question everyone who drank with him that night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_2">
        <text>Listen up, merc. I’ve heard of your fine “work”, and if you try anything funny I will deal with you accordingly. Are we clear on that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_20">
        <text>Alright, I go get Lefty</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_22">
        <text>Beast, Where’s Lefty? Did you bring him to our base?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_23">
        <text>Lefty’s dead, somebody is "cleaning up" after themselves.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_24">
        <text>Man, what a scumbag... We got to find whoever did this as soon as possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_25">
        <text>Let’s not rush it, it’s not like we can revive the dead and if you we move to early more innocent people might get hurt. Don’t worry, I’ll find out who did this and I’ll deal with him, alright?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_26">
        <text>Yeah, okay. As long as you get it done. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_27">
        <text>By the way did you find out with whom the two were drinknig?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_28">
        <text>Yeah, Goreliye and Chemist.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_29">
        <text>I’ll find out soon enough.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_3">
        <text>Don’t worry, after what’ve been through in spatial anomaly, I’ve decided to stop being a mercenary.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_31">
        <text>Beast, get to Lefty, we wil talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_33">
        <text>So Beast, any luck finding the murderer?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_34">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_36">
        <text>>So Beast, any luck finding the murderer?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_37">
        <text>Yeah, it was chemist. He wanted the loot to himself so he iced both of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_38">
        <text>What? Are you sure? I never thought Chemist would be able to do something like this... He was one of my best and most trusted men, and what a piece of shit he turned out to be. Well... Maybe both Lefty and Limp rest in peace. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_39">
        <text>What’s done is done. The important thing is that Limp’s death was avenged.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_4">
        <text>Sure... And how are you feeling?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_40">
        <text>What is this world coming to? I still can’t believe Chemist pulled such a thing. I was ready to suspect anyone except for him; I even considered putting goreliye in the cage but after questioning him, I was convinced he wasn’t guilty. Here, take this, It’s your reward for helping us out. You helped us get rid of a huge menace and that’s worth a lot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_41">
        <text>Thank you and goodbye, this is probably the last time we see each other.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_42">
        <text>Hey, wait up, where are you going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_43">
        <text>I’m leaving the Stronghold; I don’t really like it here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_44">
        <text>Nobody told you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_45">
        <text>About what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_46">
        <text>There’s no way out of the Stronghold right now seeing as all the ways out are blocked off. One path has been taken over by Monolithians who are constantly patrolling it. The second path is covered by anomalies and only an experienced guide can lead through it safely and our guide is gone right now. He’s leading a group stalkers through the Red Forest and you’re going to have to wait until he comes back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_47">
        <text>Goddamn it... Alright then, guess I’ll have to be your guest for a while. Do you have any more jobs for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_48">
        <text>Not yet, but if you need work right now go talk to Rasputin, he always has work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_49">
        <text>I’ll go ask him and I’ll See you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_5">
        <text>Tanned and rested, your jail cells are like a beach...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_51">
        <text>What’s up Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_53">
        <text>It’s a good thing you came by, Beast. A few problems have popped up and I need your help to taking care of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_54">
        <text>What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_55">
        <text>We managed to find a hidden bandit radio frequency, so we set up a few radios tuned to it. One day, when we were listening in, we over heard that the bandits are getting ready to attack our base at night. They plan to free the bandits that are being held captive here.  I think we need to stop their plan from happening, will you give us a hand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_56">
        <text>Sure, I’ll help. What’s the plan?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_57">
        <text>The plan is that we occupy the village near the anomalous grove and when the bandits come three of us will take them at the front, one guy will take sniper position and the rest will shoot them from the abandoned buildings nearby. The bandits have no idea we are going to attack so that should give us a great advantage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_58">
        <text>I’ll take the sniper position, I’m a good sniper; I’ve done this before plenty.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_59">
        <text>Alright, I’ll give you all the needed gear. Anyway, I suggest you get ready because the ambush we are planning is going to take place tonight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_6">
        <text>Sorry about locking you up in the jail cell but you are a mercenary after all. However, Savage vouched for you and told me about how you helped everyone in the spatial anomaly so I decided to let you go. Even though we are in good shape we could still use the help of someone like you and what’s more you kind of owe to my guys see as they are the ones who saved you from those bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_60">
        <text>Alright, Stravid, I’ll go get ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_61">
        <text>Right, go get ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_63">
        <text>What’s up, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_65">
        <text>So, Beast any news? Did you manage to fight off the bandits?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_66">
        <text>Both of your guys are alive, we managed to fight off all of them off, including the backup that came after.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_67">
        <text>We fought off the bandits, including all of their backup that came after. However, not everyone of us survived, Tailor died.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_68">
        <text>Great news, Beast! I didn’t want to interfere with the eavesdropping so didn’t contact you through the radio. What is this backup you speak you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_69">
        <text>When we took out the first group, we over heard on the radio that the bandits were sending a second team to see what’s going on. They must’ve gotten spooked when the first team didn’t Answer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_7">
        <text>Aight, what’s the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_70">
        <text>Ah, I see... Anyway, I doubt those bandits will ever show their faces here again. Thank you, Beast, for helping us fight off those assholes. Here’s your reward... Oh yeah, and you can keep the sniper rifle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_71">
        <text>Thanks, man; See you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_72">
        <text>May he rest in peace, he was a good stalker. He would always put his neck on the line to save his fellow stalker.  We should give him a proper burial...  You said something about a second group of bandits?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_74">
        <text>Hey, what’s up, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_8">
        <text>Something awful has happened, about a day before you came here. Long story short, one stalker slit another stalker’s throat. They had an altercation that lead to a fight beforehand and after a while one of them was found dead.  The dead guy’s name is Limp and as for the other guy, his name is Lefty. Your job is to find Lefty and make him pay for what he did.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_9">
        <text>Where should I look for him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_0">
        <text>Can you Answer a few of my questions?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_1">
        <text>Ask away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_2">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_22">
        <text>Tell me about the zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_221">
        <text>Ask away, I’ll tell you what I know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_222">
        <text>Since my first day, I’ve been wondering is the zone really expanding or is that just a rumor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_223001">
        <text>What do you think? Of course, it’s the truth. Way back when, the zone was a lot smaller than it is now. When the zone only emerged, it borders where north of the rostok bar. I can’t tell you where exactly, I don’t know but what we do know is that the zone’s first border was somewhere around the Army Warehouses.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_223002">
        <text>How fast is it expanding? Right now there are plenty of anomalies here, were there really less of them here before?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_223003">
        <text>You can believe what you want but a year back this place was devoid of anomalies completely. Five years ago this place wasn’t even considered the zone and back then the army had an outpost in the northern part Garbage, but after the zone started to expand the military was forced to relocate. Why it’s expanding so rapidly, that’s not a question for me but rather for one of those eggheads in Yantar. The zone expands in bursts, usually after an emission. Back then the emission were a lot rarer, they would occur about once a month and they were a lot more powerful than they are right now. The zone would expand along with these powerful blowouts however with time the blowouts started to become less powerful. Though the frequency in which they occur has been increasing ever since. Nowadays, we have a blowout every few days but it wasn’t always like that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_223004">
        <text>What will happen to the zone’s barrier? from what I understand it’s not the first border the government has set up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_223005">
        <text>Well, you got that right. The barrier in Cordon is the third border they’ve set up until now.  They’ve started building it when the zone started to expand for the first time. Back then, a lot of people died near the perimeter, some died from the blowout but most of them died from mutant attacks. Nobody ever seen anything like it before, the amount of mutants that was coming from the center was enormous, there were thousands of them. The government in turn, sent everything they had at them; they turned this place into a warzone. Tanks, helicopters, artillery and everything in between were here to fight off this insane wave of mutants. At one point the wanted to carpet bomb the whole place but lucky for us the mutants stopped coming at that point. After that incident, the world started to take the zone a lot more seriously. Instead of restoring the old perimeter they’ve put a few pillboxes around Garbage and they didn’t stop there. In case a threat would get passed Garbage they would have a backup solution, the military outpost in cordon used to be that backup solution.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_223006">
        <text>Why does the Cordon outpost look so weird? What I mean is why does it look like a military warehouse more than anything? Same thing with the wall they built around the zone, why does it go over the perimeter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_223007">
        <text>That’s because that place was never supposed to be a military outpost but rather a warehouse where all sorts of military technology would be stored and repaired. It was also used to refuel and repair vehicles that would carry cargo in and out of the CNPP. And after that wave of mutants that mentioned early emerged, the military took over that warehouse and made it their base. As for the wall, they only started building it after the blowout struck and because the engineers worked in a hurry they’ve made some kind of calculation mistake and as result the wall was actually built south of the outpost. Then, however, they tried to rebuild it so that at least the wall would cover some of the outside buildings and that’s what they got as a result.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_223008">
        <text>Where are the gates though, when I was looking they weren’t there, just an open enterance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_223009">
        <text>They aren’t there anymore, they got rid of them. A few months ago a big flock of mutants smashed through those gates. The strange thing was that they were no blowouts that day. Out of nowhere a flock of boars and fleshed appeared and started breaking through the barrier, killing a few soldiers in the process. Then when the military called in a chopper something completely bizarre occurred, the mutants instantly ran away as if they knew a chopper was on the way. Instead of repairing the gates they decided to just get rid of them seeing as how they were going to build a second barrier anyway. Did you see it by the way? It looks amazing, a fine piece of work indeed. Everything there is as it should be: flamethrowers, mortars, fortified trenches and pillboxes, it’s all there. Hell, the minefield alone is a work of art, not a single rodent can get passed it. They must’ve spent billions on this new barrier, considering all the gear that’s located there. NATO takes its defense budget seriously it would seem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_2231">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_224">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_225">
        <text>Answer 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_2251">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_226">
        <text>Question 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_227">
        <text>Answer 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_2271">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_228">
        <text>Question 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_229">
        <text>Answer 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_2291">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_230">
        <text>Question 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_231">
        <text>Answer 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_2311">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3">
        <text>What do you need exactly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_33">
        <text>Know anything interesting?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_331">
        <text>Did you hear about the american spies?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_332">
        <text>Nope. What about them?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_333">
        <text>Well, a year ago Rasputin got a job off to escort three foreigners through the zone. He was promised really good cash, so he agreed. However, he is a smart guy, so he checked up through what they had in store for him. He found out through his sources that these foreigners were no regular tourists but rather CIA agents. Rasputin didn’t want to lose the cash he was promised but at the same time he didn’t want to screw over the stalker that would take the job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3330001">
        <text>So what did he do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3330002">
        <text>He told me about his situation and after a while we both came up with a solution. We picked someone who could really handle himself, Elijah Muromski. That guy was tough as nails, two meters tall, huge shoulders, and strong as hell. One time he broke a boar’s neck with his bare hands just for the hell of it. So if you something would go down, he could handle it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3330003">
        <text>So what happened then?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3330004">
        <text>Elijah arrived on time and met the tourists after which he led them to the designated places. The tourists wanted to inspect the mutants from a far and take a few pictures and maybe even hunt a few of them. But Elijah could barely speak any English and he couldn’t understand what his clients wanted from him. They only thing Elijah understood was that our guests wanted to hunt down some mutants and so that what he did for the entire trip.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3330005">
        <text>I think I’m starting to see where this is going...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3330006">
        <text>No you don’t, stop interrupting and listen. For three days Elijah escorted our American clients. He went everywhere with this guys and showed them everything. In the Agroprom Underground they were attacked by a bloodsucker that almost killed one of tourists. In Yantar Elijah "accidently" forgot to mention that they were zombies there so when one of the corpses stood up, one guy almost had a heart attack. When they were traveling between one location and another he would "accidently" run into flocks of boars and other small time mutants. On the third day Elijah suggested they would sleep in the construction site that was located in Dark Valley, he of course "forgot" to mention that there were burers there. I don’t even know who was more sacred, the burers at the sight of Elijah, or the Americans who were dead frightened of the burers. When Elijah told us about this, our stomachs almost burst from laughter. That’s not all though. The next morning the tourists wanted to go home so they went to Sidorovich so that he could smuggle them back across the border. However the same day this tourist planned to leave, a group of three guys came to the zone, they were escorted through the border by the military. It turned out that this was a CIA group sent in to the zones for some kind special preparation program. Sidorovich was dumbfounded, why send one CIA group and then another one right after? He asked the tourists why did the CIA do this to which they replayed in broken Russian that they weren’t CIA and had nothing to do with them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3330007">
        <text>So all this time, Elijah was just scarring a few American tourists... Ha-ha-ha. Damn, that’s too funny. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3330008">
        <text>Yeah, he almost gave them a heart attack. By the way, the real spies were also escorted by Elijah, in the same route. The burers were happy about it, ha!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3330009">
        <text>Thanks, I needed a good laugh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3331">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_334">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_335">
        <text>Answer 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3351">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_336">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_337">
        <text>Answer 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3371">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_338">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_339">
        <text>Answer 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3391">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_340">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_341">
        <text>Answer 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_3411">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_4">
        <text>Where are you from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_44">
        <text>I was born in the Russian region of Sakhalin, in Okha to be exact. You know where that is right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_44001">
        <text>Yeah, I know where it is, it’s an island in the far east of Russia, close to Japan. You sure travelled a long way here, what did you do there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_44002">
        <text>Well, the town’s main export was gas and oil and even wood and I could always find work in those area. But since childhood I had a need for adventure, I just couldn’t imagine myself being stuck in one place for the rest of my life. At the time I travelled through every forest in the nearby region. When I turned 18, I joined the military. For me, it was the only way to get out of that island and see the world. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_441">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_5">
        <text>How did you get here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_52001">
        <text>That’s a tough one... I don’t know whether it was a chain of coincidences or the zone itself choice me but here I am. Back in the army, I excelled in every aspect. I loved sports since I was a small kid so serving two years in a spetznaz wasn’t too bad. Even though, when I got recruited, the war in Afghanistan didn’t end yet but was nearing its end. I was barely sent to any warzones and didn’t get fight much. When the war finally ended, I was sent to military school where I got a military career.  While I was in school, I met a woman whom I married. I didn’t have any kids though; for the best as it turns out. After I finished school, I would travel from one garrison to another so I didn’t have time for kids. After that I was sent to Chechnya, so kids were once again out of the question.  When I was in Chechnya my wife decide to visit me at the base. The base was attacked by Chechen terrorists and my wife was killed. Man, was I an idiot for letting her set foot in such an awful place...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_52002">
        <text>Sorry, I don’t know... Didn’t mean to remind you...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_52003">
        <text>Forget about it, it’s my cross to bear and I’ll have to live with it for the rest of my life. Maybe, that’s why the zone lead me to here, what do you think? I’ve been through a lot after the first Chechen war, so much that I can’t tell it all right now. Nevertheless, I remember the day the zone emerged like it was yesterday. You just can’t forget such chaos. In the first few hours nobody could even understand what was going on, people weren’t sure whether the reactor exploded, a meteorite fell, or this was the beginning of a nuclear war. Moscow was just as riled up as Kiev was. And that was when we were sent to the zone, I’ll never forget that day.  I almost lost my entire team because of those bureaucratic rats. To them it was no big deal throwing soldiers’ lives away, considering they just had to know what those anomalies were capable of, bastards.  How I, Dima and Sergey made it out alive, I still don’t know, the zone must have been guiding us. Anyway, when we made to the HQ, I was ready to shoot the general who ordered this operation. I almost did it, I had the gun pointed between his eyes but I was captured in time. After that, I was thrown in jail. If it wasn’t for my friends who helped me escape, I would probably be stuck in some Russian prison right now. After I escaped the military camp, I had two choices: either live in the zone, or spend the rest of my life hiding in the outside world. I choose the former. I rather live freely in the zone, than be rotting in some shitty prison.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_52004">
        <text>Yeah, that’s one hell of a story. Do you ever miss your hometown? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_52005">
        <text>You know, at first I didn’t miss it at all; I was too busy trying to stay alive. Back then, the zone was a lot more dangerous than it is now and it was almost completely devoid of people to boot. Even though, I’m an experienced soldiers and I’ve seen all the horrors of war, none of them could compared to what I’ve seen in the zone. When your friend gets caught in an anomaly, flies up in the area and gets torn to shreds, you stop feeling anything but fear. Nevertheless, you can’t lose skill and so I managed to survive somehow. After sometime, when I gained some experience and got a bit more comfortable here, that’s when I started to feel a longing for home. Nowadays, I really want to go home. See my parents one last time, I don’t even know if they are alive or not. I’m even willing to go sit in prison if in the end I’ll get to return home.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_551">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_6">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_66">
        <text>Answer 3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_661">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_7">
        <text>Question 2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_77">
        <text>Answer 4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_771">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_777">
        <text>Answerå âñ¸, ÷òî çíàþ, óæå ðàññêàçàë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_8">
        <text>question 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_88">
        <text>Answer 5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_881">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_999">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_Saurel_about_9990">
        <text>text in default</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_10">
        <text>He caught this signal in the factory, in the same district where an exit from the spatial anomaly is located, that’s where we located you. I think that these messages are coming from people who, like you, got stuck inside the spatial anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_11">
        <text>I’ll be glad to help, perhaps I can even save Marcus. One question though, how exactly are you going to pull them out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_12">
        <text>It’s simple really, before leaving Forester give me the exact coordinates to exit that anomaly. We just have to send it the stalker trapped inside.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_13">
        <text>Sure, if you have the necessary transmitter, let’s go for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_14">
        <text>Excellent, I knew I could count on you. I’ll give you the transmitter and you’ll take it to the needed spot and send them the coordinates. Don’t worry, the device already has all the data recorded in its memory, all you have to do is send to the stalkers on the other side. If they get our signal then they should be able to find their way out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_15">
        <text>Alright, give me the transmitter. I’ll send them the coordinates</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_17">
        <text>So, did you do what I asked?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_18">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_2">
        <text>Greetings, merc! Need anything fixed?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_20">
        <text>You’re awake, Beast, Good. You scared everyone, what the hell happend to you in the factory?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_21">
        <text>I sent the coordinates, but the wrong people got their hands on it. I guess sending the coordinates wasn’t such a good idea, can’t do anything about it now though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_22">
        <text>Beast, what the hell are you talking about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_23">
        <text>There’s no time to get in to all the details, but it’s very likely that we are all in grave danger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_24">
        <text>I think we can easily fight off any attack considering the massive protection we have here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_25">
        <text>I hope that’s the case. Anyway, here’s your transmitter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_26">
        <text>Alright then... By the way, I unlocked the PDA you brought me here before. I read what’s in there and gave it to Saurel. I hope you don’t mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_27">
        <text>I don’t mind. What sort info was there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_28">
        <text>Go talk to Saurel, he’ll tell you everything in full detail. And in the meantime I have to get back to work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_29">
        <text>Fine, I’ll go to him then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_31">
        <text>Greetings, merc! You need anything repaired?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_33">
        <text>Hey, Beast, I take you’re here about the PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_34">
        <text>Yeah, that’s right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_35">
        <text>Just so you know Saurel is sending you on a very dangerous mission. But what can you right? We all have to risk our lives here all the time.  Alright, I reconfigured your PDA, now the Monolithians will think you are one of their own. By the way, you don’t have to worry about friendly fire since everyone in the base was warned you two were going undercover, we also told the hunter team nearby so there should be no problem with them either. Good luck out there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_36">
        <text>Thanks, see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_38">
        <text>Greetings, merc! You need anything repaired?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_4">
        <text>Hey, merc. Are you here on buisness?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_40">
        <text>Damn, you look like shit, Beast... Did you guys stop the Monolithians? Also, where’s Savage?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_41">
        <text>The Monolithians took Savage and hid him inside the laboratory, thinking I’d go after him. They must’ve prepared some kind of trap for me. I’m not going though, since his dead either way and I’m not going to throw my life away for nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_42">
        <text>Fuck man... Poor Savage. In any case though, you’ve made the right choice, in my opinion. For all we know Savage is already dead. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_43">
        <text>Can reconfigure back my PDA, Petrovich? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_44">
        <text>Sure thing. Lets see... Here you go, good as new. So where are you off to now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_45">
        <text>I’ll go talk to hunter, Saurel said he is ready to leave the Stronghold and I’m coming with...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_46">
        <text>In that case, goodbye, Beast. This might be the last time we see each other. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_47">
        <text>Goodbye, Petrovich.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_49">
        <text>Goodbye, Beast. This might be the last time we see each other. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_5">
        <text>Hey, Petrovich, can you hack you this pda?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_6">
        <text>I can try, I’ve done it before. Nevertheless, I can’t promise anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_7">
        <text>Alright, here’s the pda, give it a shot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_8">
        <text>Sure, I’ll have a look. Listen, Beast, I have a favor to ask you. I haven’t told this to anyone, not even to Saurel. I have been catching a help signal on my radio that was being transmitted on a hidden frequency. After a while, I stopped getting it but then a stalker came to me and said he has been catching that same signal when he was near the factory. At first I didn’t believe him but he brought me a recording which convinced me otherwise.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_from_tech_9">
        <text>And? Where are you going with this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_0">
        <text>Hey, Antibiotic, can you give me the Chimera figurine, the one on your table?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_1">
        <text>Sorry, but I’m not going to just give it away. Now if you are willing to place a bid on this thing then that’s a different story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_10">
        <text>A thousand? Don’t you think it’s a bit more than that? 1500 at the very least?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_11">
        <text>So be it, I’ll sell it to you for 1500.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_12">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_13">
        <text>And here’s your figurine, don’t lose it, it’s a unqiue peice. Only one in the enitre world.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_14">
        <text>Thanks, good day to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_15">
        <text>For 2000 it’s all yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_16">
        <text>Alright, here’s the cash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_2">
        <text>And how much do you want for it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_3">
        <text>How much will you give?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_4">
        <text>I’ll give you 500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_5">
        <text>I’ll give you 1000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_6">
        <text>I’ll give you 1500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_7">
        <text>I’ll give you 2000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_8">
      <text>Money’s tight right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_medic_about_toy_9">
        <text>That’s way to small of a sum, maybe you can a higher bid?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_0">
        <text>Do you need any help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_1">
        <text>It’s a good thing you asked, I have something I need taken care of, someone tried to help me with this before but he couldn’t find anything substantial.  The thing is, I need your help to complete a collection.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_2">
        <text>What sort of collection?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_3">
        <text>Way back when, we had a guy in the Stronghold who would make figurines, it was his hobby. One time, he got the idea to make a figurine out of every mutant in the zone and since he had such a good photographic memory, the statuettes he made were really accurate. After a while that guy disappeared somewhere but his figurines remained; he sold all of them to the local stalkers. I started to develop a liking for those figurines when I got my hands on the bloodsucker sculpture and after that I wanted to complete the entire collection. I think if you look around the stashes in the Stronghold and ask around the stalkers then perhaps you can find something. So what do you say, help me out here? I’ll give you a 1000 rubles for each figurine you find.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_4">
        <text>Alright, I’ll try and look for them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_5">
        <text>Sorry, I don’t have the time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_6">
        <text>If you want to help then help me complete my collection. You’ll help me out a lot if you find a few at least.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_7">
        <text>Alright, I’ll try and look for them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_8">
        <text>I’m still short on time. I’m not going to do that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_0">
        <text>About the figure collection…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_1">
        <text>Yeah? You find any figures?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_10">
        <text>I found a pseudogiant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_11">
        <text>I found a snork.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_12">
        <text>Excellent. Here’s your reward, merc, just as we agreed. Is that all, or have you found any other figure?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_13">
        <text>You already have all the mutant figures.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_14">
        <text>Oh? Oh. I didn’t notice you already found all the figures. Excellent work, merc. Thank you so much for your help. As a token of my gratitude, other than the money, I’ll give you a forty percent discount on all repairs and modifications.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_15">
        <text>Well, thanks for the discount. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_2">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_3">
        <text>I found a blind dog.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_4">
        <text>I found a pseudodog.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_5">
        <text>I found a boar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_6">
        <text>I found a flesh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_7">
        <text>I found a burer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_8">
        <text>I found a controller.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_petrovich_quest_start_9">
        <text>I found a chimera.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_0">
        <text>Rasputin, can you give me the pseudogiant figure that’s behind you on that shelf?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_1">
        <text>Why do you need that figure? It doesn’t just stand there. It’s part of my bar’s entourage, and I’ve gotten used to it being there for so long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_2">
        <text>Petrovich asked me to find figures of all mutants in the Zone. You have one of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_3">
        <text>I’ll give it to you for a thousand. No questions asked.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_4">
        <text>He’s been begging for it for quite a while. I was going to give it away, but he already sent you on a hunt for all the figures. So, if he really wants it, then take it. I’ll put something else in its place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_5">
        <text>Well, okay. If you need it so badly, take it. Was just curious why you needed it…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_6">
        <text>Thanks. You’ve helped me out good. See you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_actor_meet_shaman_about_toy_7">
        <text>Doesn’t matter to me much. Later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_11">
        <text>Yo, man! You wanna take a few shots at the ravens?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_111">
        <text>I do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_1111">
        <text>Great. I’ve got games for fun, for money, or for a record. Take your pick.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_112">
        <text>Nah. I don’t feel like it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_1121">
        <text>’Kay, man. I’m always here if you change your mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_21">
        <text>Here’s your stuff, like we agreed. All fair and square. So, you wanna go for some more?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_31">
        <text>That’s just the way it is sometimes. You wanna try again?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_41">
        <text>Where were you flailing that shooter, man? Shooting behind the fence is your own thing. Maybe you wanna have go by the rules this time?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_51">
        <text>Less talking, more shooting. You know your time’s running out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_511">
        <text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_hello_61">
        <text>You shoot like a real man! You should go for money. Want to try again?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_0">
        <text>For money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_1">
        <text>Now that’s what I like to hear! I don’t need to go over the rules with you, do I?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_11">
        <text>Yeah. Let’s start.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_111">
        <text>Not just yet, bro! So what do you think? How many of them birdies can you get in a minute?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_111111">
        <text>Sure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_1111111">
        <text>Well, I’ll be. All right, man, ready your gun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_11111111">
        <text>Yeah.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_111112">
        <text>I don’t have that much money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_1111121">
        <text>Well, can you choose something that’ll fit your pocket?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_11111211">
        <text>Yeah. I’ll pick a different amount of ravens.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_11111212">
        <text>No. Not interested.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_111112121">
        <text>Then you can play just for fun. Or for records… but that’ll drain your pockets dry. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_12">
        <text>Tell me the rules.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_121">
        <text>Money’s the most fun out of them. You tell me how many ravens you can take out in a minute, you place your bets, and you go forward. If you win your bet, you get double of what you bet. If you lose, the cash is mine. And keep in mind: the more birdies, the bigger the bet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_money_13">
        <text>Mmm… I don’t feel like playing anymore.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_questions_0">
        <text>Are there any general rules?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_questions_1">
        <text>Basically none. I keep the time, you get ready for the signal, then rain fire. If you manage to get as many as you’ve bet in a minute, you win. How you want to take the birds out is your own choice. Just remember that if you leave the fence, the game’s off. So what’ll it be: fun, money, or records?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_quit_0">
        <text>Eh. I don’t like it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_quit_1">
        <text>Okay, then. If anything, I’m always here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_0">
        <text>For a record.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_11">
        <text>Let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_1111">
        <text>Agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_11111">
        <text>Now, let’s see what skills you got!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_1112">
        <text>Agreed, but no money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_11121">
        <text>Then a few simpler choices: money or just for fun. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_1113">
        <text>I’ve changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_12">
        <text>Remind me of the rules.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_121">
        <text>This is for real men. If you feel you got the strength to take the highest record, you put a bet, and not a small one either. If you get it, I’ll give you back the money you bet with twice on top… and also the title of champion, which ain’t so fucking bad. If not, I keep your paper.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_record_13">
        <text>I’ve changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_0">
        <text>For fun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_1">
        <text>Some exercise, huh? You got the rules?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_11">
        <text>Yes. Let’s shoot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_111">
        <text>’Kay. How many ravens are you getting?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_11111">
        <text>Okay. Come on, then. Drop ’em.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_111111">
        <text>Yep.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_21">
        <text>No. Tell me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_211">
        <text>Well, for fun… that is, if you don’t wanna earn any cash. To train, or if you’re just feeling down. You choose how many ravens you drop within a minute, and you try to do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_31">
        <text>I’ve changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_bookmaker_training_311">
        <text>Not a question. Your choices are the same: for money or for a record. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_0">
        <text>Greetings, sir. What were you doing on the tree?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_1">
        <text>What? Got a problem?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_2">
        <text>No, God forbid. Everything is fine. If you give us the artifact you found in the grove, though, it’ll be even better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_3">
        <text>Oh, fuck off… You better leave the village before I leave a bullet in your head.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_4">
        <text>I’m not giving you anything. Go back to where you came from.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_5">
        <text>All right. Take the artifact and be on your way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_6">
        <text>That’s it! We’re feeling nice today, so be thankful that we don’t strip your clothes and make you walk around the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_gop_stop_7">
        <text>Uhuh…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_escape_0">
        <text>So, listen up: head to the old school in the morning. I’ll be waiting there with my bros. I see you there, you get your shooters. And remember: we never had this conversation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_escape_1">
        <text>And I know what to do without you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_escape_2">
        <text>Perfect. Take the key. Got no time to waste, so we’re off. We’ll be waiting for you at the agreed meeting point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_escape_3">
        <text>I’ll see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_2">
        <text>’Sup, merc! Thanks again for helping us out of that hole.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_3">
        <text>I’ll just cut the formalities: do you have my weapons?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_4">
        <text>Of course. I’m good to my word… These babies are brand new; haven’t even been adjusted yet. Everything’s just right. By the way, I hope nobody caught word of our deal yesterday?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_5">
        <text>No. Everything went fine. Give me the guns.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_6">
        <text>They’re all yours. Here. And, some more info for ya: go see Bookmaker in the yard. He can put together some fun for you, not to mention the money that’s in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_7">
        <text>Great. I’ll head there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_school_meet_9">
        <text>Look who showed up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_10">
        <text>Âàëèëêà åù¸ íå âûðîñëà, õåõ. So that means we have an agreement? I’ll wait for the key at nighttime.</text> <!-- fix -->
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_11">
        <text>We have an agreement.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_13">
        <text>So, did you retrieve the key?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_14">
        <text>Yes. I have the key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_15">
        <text>Still haven’t found it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_16">
        <text>Beautiful, merc. Give it to me. Time is short, and we still need to get out of here without a sound.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_17">
        <text>Hold your horses. How are we going to return the key back to where it was?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_18">
        <text>I know: we’ll meet by the house. You go now and wait for me there while I open this cell with my bro and sneak out in your direction. I’ll mark the exact place for you, which is where I’ll give you the key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_19">
        <text>And when will I get the gun?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_2">
        <text>Hey, merc: I heard you’re looking for a Vikhr gun. I could help you out with that, but I’m going to need a little something from you first.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_20">
        <text>We’ll talk everything out when we’re out of here. Need to get out before the stalkers notice anything. Wait for me at the place we agreed on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_21">
        <text>Okay. Here’s the key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_22">
        <text>Great. Now, you head off and wait for me at the meeting point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_23">
        <text>Got it. I’m heading out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_25">
        <text>Merc, go wait at the meeting point. Don’t waste any more time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_26">
        <text>I’ll think about your offer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_28">
        <text>What, merc? You gonna help us out of this shithole?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_29">
        <text>I haven’t decided yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_3">
        <text>And what kind of help do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_30">
        <text>I have the key.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_31">
        <text>Well, I’m glad you have the key, but the moon’s not up yet… and we need to get out at nighttime. Come back later, preferably after midnight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_32">
        <text>Okay. I’ll come back at nighttime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_4">
        <text>What do you think? I wanna get out of this hole. If you help, I could part with a nice shooter. Don’t worry: you won’t have to drop anyone. You just need to find the key for this cell.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_5">
        <text>And how do you suggest finding it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_6">
        <text>It won’t be that hard. There are two keys for this cage: one’s held by Saurel while the other is… or, was, guarded by Chemist. Chemist’s key, however, is held by Sologub right now. I heard from a stalker that Sologub just leaves his key on his nightstand at night while he’s out like a light. You just need to fetch the key while he’s asleep, and after we’re out of here, return the key back to where you took it from. If everything goes as planned, they won’t even know we’re gone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_7">
        <text>Sounds like a plan, but how can I trust your offer?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_8">
        <text>Trust? Hah. You can trust me. I gave you my word, and I always keep it. Especially since you have no way out of this place without a gun… and I have two of those. I’m not looking for any funny business. You won’t be getting any gun without my help. They’re guarded by quite a serious man, and he gives them only to me. If we get out of here, I’ll give them both to you. I swear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_bandit_shmiga_talk_quest_9">
        <text>Okay. Looks like I have no choice. Keep in mind, though, that we’re gonna have more problems if you try to ditch me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_off_0">
        <text>Rasputin, turn off the radio.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_off_1">
        <text>Yeah? Sure. Getting tired of it myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_off_2">
        <text>Done. Were you building up a headache there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_off_3">
        <text>You don’t like my repertoire? That’s fine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_on_0">
        <text>Rasputin, turn on the radio.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_on_1">
        <text>You want some music? Fine. I don’t mind that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_on_2">
        <text>Ýõ, ÿ è ñàì íå ïðî÷ü ïîñëóøàòü ÷òî-òî äóøåâíîå.</text> <!-- fix -->
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_barman_radio_on_3">
        <text>Done. Listen to your heart’s content. It’s the only thing that’s free of charge here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_chimik_killer_meet_0">
        <text>What the…?! Oh. It’s you, merc… Go back to where you came.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_chimik_killer_meet_1">
        <text>I just came here with the intent of helping you. Isn’t that a good thing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_chimik_killer_meet_2">
        <text>You’ve tired me already. What are you doing poking your nose into other people’s business? I should’ve ended you when you were doing time. Now hold on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_chimik_killer_meet_3">
        <text>Well, you said your last word…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_0">
        <text>Got any work?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_1">
        <text>À êàê òû äóìàåøü? Êîíå÷íî åñòü, ïðè ÷åì ðàáîòà íå ïûëüíàÿ. Íàì, äëÿ ñäà÷è ó÷¸íûì çàêàçà, íå õâàòàåò øåñòü õâîñòîâ ñëåïûõ ïñîâ. Áóäó î÷åíü ïðèçíàòåëåí åñëè ïîìîæåøü ñ õâîñòàìè. Âîçüìåøüñÿ?</text> <!-- fix -->
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_2">
        <text>Fine. I’ll help you with the tails.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_3">
        <text>Great. And don’t worry about the reward; you’ll get an honest sum for honest work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_4">
        <text>Got it. I’ll be off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_dop_quest_dialog_5">
        <text>Nothing so far.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_10">
        <text>Greetings, merc. Do you have any business here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_2">
        <text>Greetings, merc. Do you have any business here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_4">
        <text>You got the six blind dog tails?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_5">
        <text>Yes. I have the tails. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_6">
        <text>Nothing so far.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_7">
        <text>Great. You helped me good. Here’s your honest reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_hunter_quester_start_8">
        <text>Thank you. I’ll be going now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_10">
        <text>Well, anyone. Listen: we went to a raid with Limp not long ago, and the Zone gave us this gift. Basically, we came upon a load of artifacts and crammed it all into a container. We agreed to keep the container hidden, and you can guess what happened after that: we split up. Limp managed to return to the base before I did. All in all, we were feeling happy and generous, so we decided to have some drinks with another couple of stalkers. Then the dimwit tells me that he brought the container to the base. I didn’t stand that shit, so I gave him a smack. That’s when the conflict started. Rasputin messaged me thereafter, saying that he lost the container. Clearly, whoever plotted all of this wasn’t screwing around.</text> <!-- fix -->
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_11">
        <text>Who do you think is behind it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_12">
        <text>I have no idea. I know for sure that it couldn’t have been Rasputin, Skew, or Saurel, obviously. Beast, I beg you, explain everything to Saurel. I don’t want everything to keep going this way. I’m not scared to die, but I don’t want to die a rat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_13">
        <text>I’ll go talk to him and get back to you after that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_14">
        <text>You won’t be able to contact me; I lost my PDA somewhere while escaping the bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_15">
        <text>Then stay here and don’t move. I’ll come back to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_17">
        <text>Beast, I beg you, speak to Saurel about letting me back. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_18">
        <text>Fine. I’ll speak to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_2">
        <text>Hey. Who are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_3">
        <text>I’m Beast. I came here for you. I’ll give you the chance to say your last words.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_4">
        <text>Hot damn. Did Saurel send you here? Haven’t seen you around the base before.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_5">
        <text>I arrived here yesterday while you were slipping away.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_6">
        <text>Oh, I didn’t slip anywhere. I just went for a walk to calm my nerves, and then Rasputin sent me a message about Limp being killed. Everyone thought I was the killer, and then bandits went after me, and I couldn’t return back. And, no! I didn’t kill Limp! He was like a brother to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_7">
        <text>Only you had any reason to do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_8">
        <text>Well, yeah. We had a bit of an argument, but I wouldn’t go so far as to kill a man because of a trifle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_levsha_first_meet_9">
        <text>Then who could’ve done it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_0">
        <text>So, Beast, you ready to deal with these fanatics?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_1">
        <text>I’m ready, though why did you decide to get mixed up in all of this?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_2">
        <text>Çàõîòåë òåáå ïîìî÷ü, ïîáëàãîäàðèòü çà âñå òî, ÷òî òû äëÿ ìåíÿ ñäåëàë. Ýòî ìíîãîãî ñòîèò, äà è ó Ñîëîãóáà îïûòà ìàëî, ÷òîáû íà òàêèå çàäàíèÿ õîäèòü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_3">
        <text>Õì, íó òîãäà ëàäíî, ìîæåì èäòè?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_4">
        <text>Äà, Ïåòðîâè÷ óæå ïåðåíàñòðîèë ìîé ÊÏÊ, òàê ÷òî ìîæåì îòïðàâëÿòüñÿ ïðÿìî ñåé÷àñ. Ïðåäëàãàþ èäòè íå òîé äîðîãîé, ÷òî âîçëå øêîëû èäåò, òàì àíîìàëèé ìíîãî, ëó÷øå èäòè ïî äîðîãå, ÷òî îò çàâîäà òÿíåòñÿ, òàê õîòü ïóòü è äëèííåå, íî áåçîïàñíåé.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_lutiy_monolit_dialog_5">
        <text>Ïîääåðæèâàþ, ïîéäåì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_10">
        <text>Ñòðàííî âñ¸ ýòî...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_11">
        <text>Âîò æå, íåóæåëè ýòîò êîç¸ë íàâðàë è íèêàêîé âñòðå÷è íå áóäåò?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_12">
        <text>Âûõîäèò, ÷òî òàê…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_14">
        <text>Òâîþ ìàòü! Ýòî çàñàäà! Çâåðü, ñðî÷íî îòïðàâëÿéñÿ çà ïîäêðåïëåíèåì, ìû òåáÿ ïðèêðîåì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_15">
        <text>Î ÷åì òû ãîâîðèøü, ÿ îñòàþñü ñ âàìè.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_16">
        <text>Íåò! Çâåðü, íàñ ìàëî, â òàêîì êîëè÷åñòâå ìû è ïÿòè ìèíóò íå ïðîäåðæèìñÿ, ñåé÷àñ æå îòïðàâëÿéñÿ ê ñòàëêåðàì çà ïîìîùüþ, òîëüêî òû ñìîæåøü óáåäèòü èõ ïîìî÷ü íàì. Äàâàé æå, æèâåå, áåãè! Ó òåáÿ ìàëî âðåìåíè. Çà îòõîä íå áåñïîêîéñÿ, ìû òåáÿ ïðèêðîåì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_17">
        <text>ß ìèãîì, Ìèêëóõà! Âû òîëüêî äåðæèòåñü òóò, ÿ ïðèâåäó ëþäåé.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_2">
        <text>Òàê, ê âñòðå÷å ìîíîëèòîâöåâ îñòàëîñü ñîâñåì íåìíîãî âðåìåíè, òåïåðü îñòàëîñü äåëî çà ìàëûì, äîæäàòüñÿ íà÷àëà ñäåëêè è ïðèõëîïíóòü ýòîãî êîçëà. Ñàìîå ãëàâíîå çàâàëèòü âñåõ, è íå äàòü íèêîìó ñìûòüñÿ. Åñëè êòî-òî âûæèâåò è ñìîæåò óéòè òî… Â îáùåì çàäíèöà íàì áóäåò, ïîëíàÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_3">
        <text>Âñ¸ áóäåò íîðìàëüíî, ãëàâíîå íå ñóåòèòüñÿ ðàíüøå âðåìåíè.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_4">
        <text>Ñîãëàñåí. Íó êàê, íåðâíè÷àåøü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_5">
        <text>Íåò, íè êàïëè íå íåðâíè÷àþ. Íó, êîãäà íà÷èíàåì òî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_6">
        <text>Ïðÿìî ñåé÷àñ, Êèñëûé â îäíîì èç òåðìèíàëîâ çàñÿäåò, à ìû â öåõå ñïðÿ÷åìñÿ, òîëüêî íà çàâîä çàéäåì ÷åðåç ñåâåðíûé ïðîõîä, òàê áåçîïàñíåé áóäåò. Ïî ïóòè íóæíî î÷èñòèòü ýòó îêðåñòíîñòü îò ìóòàíòîâ, ÷òîáû íà çâóêè âûñòðåëîâ íå ñáåæàëèñü ïîòîì, ïîéäåøü ñî ìíîé, ïîìîæåøü ìíå ñ ýòèì è ñîâåòóþ âçÿòü ñòâîë ñ ãëóøèòåëåì, øóìåòü íàì ñåé÷àñ êðàéíå íå æåëàòåëüíî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_7">
        <text>Ïîíÿë òåáÿ, òîãäà âûäâèãàåìñÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_miklucha_zavod_quest_9">
        <text>×òî-òî çäåñü íå òàê, ñëèøêîì òèõî... Ôàíàòèêè óæå äîëæíû áûëè ðàññòàâèòü ñâîþ îõðàíó ïî ïåðèìåòðó, íî òóò ñîâñåì íèêîãî íåò.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_0">
        <text>Ðàññêàæè êàêóþ-íèáóäü èñòîðèþ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_1">
        <text>Áðàò, Ìîíîëèò ïðèçâàë ìåíÿ íî÷üþ. ß ãîâîðèë ñ íèì. Îí áûë ïðåêðàñåí â ñâî¸ì âåëè÷èè. ß åäâà íå îñëåï, íî åãî ñâåò íàïîëíèë ìåíÿ âåëèêîé ñèëîé! ß çíàþ, ÿ ÷óâñòâóþ, ÷òî åãî ñèëà ïðåáûâàåò ñî âñåìè íàìè! Îí ñêàçàë ìíå, ÷òî ïîáåäèòü çëî ñïîñîáíà ëèøü òâ¸ðäàÿ âåðà. Îí ñêàçàë, ÷òî åãî ñèëà íàïîëíèò òîëüêî âåðíûõ. Åù¸ îí îòêðûë ìíå, ÷òî íàøà ïîáåäà óæå áëèçêà!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_2">
        <text>Áðàò, òû ñëûøàë, ÷òî íåäàâíî íåñêîëüêî íåâåðíûõ ïîäîáðàëèñü ê àíòåííàì? Ìîíîëèò íàïðàâèë íàñ, è áðàòüÿ âîâðåìÿ èõ çàìåòèëè. Îäèí èç íèõ óïàë è èñïàðèëñÿ. Âòîðîãî ìû óíè÷òîæèëè, òðåòèé áðîñèëñÿ áåæàòü. Òðóñû. Âñå îíè òðóñû. Ëèøü èñòèííàÿ âåðà íå îñòàâëÿåò ìåñòà äëÿ ñòðàõà! Äâîå ñìîãëè óáåæàòü, íî Ìîíîëèò ìóäð è âñåâåäóù. Çíà÷èò, îíè íóæíû åìó æèâûìè.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_3">
        <text>Ïîìíþ, êàê ìû ïàòðóëèðîâàëè îêðàèíû Ðûæåãî Ëåñà è íàòêíóëèñü òàì íà íåâåðíîãî-îäèíî÷êó. Îí íà÷àë îáðàùàòüñÿ, ïîýòîìó ìû íå óáèëè åãî, íî îí åù¸ íàïîëîâèíó ïðåáûâàë, â ñâî¸ì æèâîòíîì ñîñòîÿíèè… ß çíàþ, ìóäðûé Ìîíîëèò ñäåëàë ýòî äëÿ âñåõ íàñ: îí ñíîâà ïîêàçàë íàì èñòèííîå ëèöî ñâîèõ âðàãîâ. Òåïåðü íàøà âåðà åù¸ áîëåå óêðåïèëàñü! Áëèçèòñÿ, áðàò!.. Áëèçèòñÿ ïîáåäà íàä íåâåðíûìè, è òîãäà Ìîíîëèò âûïîëíèò íàøå ñîêðîâåííîå æåëàíèå! Èñòèííî ïðåäàííûõ îí ïðèáëèçèò ê ñåáå, ê ñëàâå ñâîåé, âåëè÷èþ ñâîåìó! Ìû âå÷íî ïðåáóäåì â ñèÿíèè åãî!..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_4">
        <text>Íåäàâíî Ìîíîëèò èñïûòûâàë ìîþ âåðó, è ÿ ÷óòü áûëî íå ñîøåë ñ èñòèííîãî ïóòè. Íî ÿ âûñòîÿë! Õâàëà Ìîíîëèòó! Åãî èñïûòàíèÿ çàêàëÿþò íàñ! Ìû âîçâðàùàëèñü èç Òåìíîé Äîëèíû, è ÿ ÷óòü îòñòàë îò áðàòüåâ. Çëî âîñïîëüçîâàëîñü ýòèì è âíåçàïíî ñòàëî èãðàòü ñî ìíîé. È… ÿ óñîìíèëñÿ. Èñòèííûå îáðàçû èñêàçèëèñü: âðàã íàøåïòûâàë ìíå, ÷òî Ìîíîëèò èñïîëüçóåò íàñ êàê ðàáîâ. Íî ïîòîì ÿ ïîíÿë: ýòî èñïûòàíèå. ß âñïîìíèë î ìîãóùåñòâå è ñèÿíèè Ìîíîëèòà è òîãäà ìîÿ âîëÿ, è óâåðåííîñòü âåðíóëèñü êî ìíå. Ñ òåõ ïîð ÿ óæå íå áîþñü íèêàêèõ èñïûòàíèé è íå çíàþ ñîìíåíèé. Õâàëà Ìîíîëèòó!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_5">
        <text>ß áûë â Òåìíîé Äîëèíå. Òàì î÷åíü ìíîãî íåâåðíûõ, âåäü ñèëà Ìîíîëèòà åùå íå äîñòèãëà ýòèõ ìåñò. Ìû îõðàíÿëè. Íî÷üþ íà íàñ íàïàëè. Ìû ÿðîñòíî ñðàæàëèñü ñ ýòèìè æèâîòíûìè. Çàñëóãè áðàòüåâ áûëè âåëèêè: ñêîðî Ìîíîëèò ïðèçâàë èõ ê ñåáå. Äëÿ ìåíÿ îí ïðèãîòîâèë åùå îäíî èñïûòàíèå. Ìîå îðóæèå íå ñòðåëÿëî. Íî òóò Ìîíîëèò ñêàçàë ìíå: « Òû ñî ìíîé, à ìîÿ ñèëà — ñ òîáîé. Åñëè òû áóäåøü òâåðä â ñâîåé âåðå, òî ñîêðóøèøü ìîèõ âðàãîâ è ïðèáëèçèøüñÿ êî ìíå!». Òîãäà ÿ ñòàë òåíüþ. ß ïðèãíóëñÿ è îáîøåë èõ ñïðàâà. Ãëóïûå øïèîíû íè÷åãî íå çàìåòèëè. Îíè ïîäóìàëè, ÷òî ïîêîí÷èëè ñ íàìè è ñìåÿëèñü íàä ïóñòûìè òåëàìè íàøèõ áðàòüåâ. Íî ÿ óæå âèäåë èõ ñïèíû. À ïîòîì èç ìîèõ ðóê óäàðèëà ìîùü Ìîíîëèòà. Òàê îí óáèë èõ âñåõ. ß ñ÷àñòëèâ ñëóæèòü òåáå, Ñîâåðøåííûé!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_monolith_story_group_6">
        <text>Ó ìåíÿ áîëüøå íåò ðàññêàçîâ äëÿ òåáÿ, áðàò.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_0">
        <text>×å íàäî, ñèíèé? ß êåìàðíóòü ñîáèðàëñÿ, à òóò òû íàðèñîâàëñÿ...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_1">
        <text>Âûñïèøüñÿ åùå... Ëó÷øå ñêàæè êàê äîëãî ÿ çäåñü, è ÷òî ýòî çà ìåñòî âîîáùå?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_10">
        <text>Àãà, óäà÷è òåáå ñ ýòèì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_11">
        <text>Ëàäíî, áûâàé.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_2">
        <text>Òû ÷å áóðîâèøü? Èëè òåáå ñòàëêåðíÿ áàøêó íàõðåí îòáèëà?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_3">
        <text>Äåëî â òîì, ÷òî íå ïîìíþ ÿ êàê çäåñü îêàçàëñÿ...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_4">
        <text>Ìàëîé ìíå øåïíóë, ÷òî òû âìåñòå ñ ýòîé ñòàëêåðí¸é èç ïóçûðÿ âûáðàëñÿ... Õå, íó ïîçäðàâëÿþ, ñìåíèë îäíó êëåòêó íà äðóãóþ. Êîðî÷å, îáúÿñíÿþ äëÿ òóãèõ - ñåé÷àñ òû íà Çàñòàâå. Íà ñòàëêåðÿ÷åé áàçå òû íå áîëüøå ÷àñà, íå ññû, íè÷åãî èíòåðåñíîãî íå ïðîïóñòèë. Ãû-ãû.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_5">
        <text>À êàêîãî õðåíà ÿ â êëåòêå?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_6">
        <text>Íå ïîäôàðòèëî òåáå, êàê è íàì ñ áðàòêîì âïðî÷åì, Ñòàâðèä ìíîãî î òåáå ñëûøàë, âîò îí è ïîñåëèë òåáÿ â ëó÷øèé íîìåð, ÷òî çäåñü èìååòñÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_7">
        <text>×òî åùå çà Ñòàâðèä?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_8">
        <text>Îí òèïà ãëàâíûé â ýòîì ëàãåðå, ñóêà ðåäêàÿ. Åùå óñïååøü ñ íèì ïîáàçàðèòü, ïîêà âàëè ëó÷øå ñïàòü, à òî òû ìåíÿ ñâîèìè ðàññïðîñàìè çàêîëåáàë óæå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_prisoner_quest_line_meet_9">
        <text>Ëàäíî, âñå-ðàâíî ïðèäåòñÿ æäàòü ê óòðó, ìîæåò Ëþòîìó óäàñòñÿ äîãîâîðèòñÿ ñ ýòèì Ñòàâðèäîì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_0">
        <text>Ñëóøàé âíèìàòåëüíî, íà¸ìíèê, íå áóäó ïîâòîðÿòü äâà ðàçà, Ñòàâðèä îòïóñêàåò òåáÿ, íî ñäåëàåøü ìàëåéøóþ ãëóïîñòü è îòâåòèøü çà íåå ïî âñåé ñòðîãîñòè. Ñå÷åøü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_1">
        <text>Âàñ ïîíÿë, ãðàæäàíèí íà÷àëüíèê. Ìîãó ÿ ïîëó÷èòü îáðàòíî ñâîå ñíàðÿæåíèå?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_2">
        <text>Äà, êîíå÷íî. Âîò âñå, ÷òî áûëî ïðè òåáå, äåðæè.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_3">
        <text>Ïîíÿë. Ãäå ãðóïïà ñ êîòîðîé ÿ ïðèáûë?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_4">
        <text>Äà êòî ãäå, ÷àñòü íà áàçå, ÷àñòü åùå â÷åðà ñ ïðîâîäíèêîì Çàñòàâó ïîêèíóëà. È åùå îäèí, Ìàðêóñ êîòîðûé, âîîáùå ïðîïàë êóäà-òî, ýòîò Ëþòûé âàø ñêàçàë, ÷òî îí âðîäå êàê ñ àíîìàëèè è íå âûøåë, íî òû îá ýòîì ñ íèì ëè÷íî ïîãîâîðè, ìîæåò ÿ è íàïóòàë ÷òî-òî. Äà, åùå êîå-÷òî, òû ýòî, ñõîäè ñî Ñòàâðèäîì ïîãîâîðè, ó íåãî ê òåáå ñåðüåçíûé ðàçãîâîð èìååòñÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_5">
        <text>Ëàäíî, âûïóñêàé ìåíÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_6">
        <text>Äà êòî ãäå, ÷àñòü íà áàçå, ÷àñòü åùå â÷åðà ñ ïðîâîäíèêîì Çàñòàâó ïîêèíóëà. È åùå îäèí, Ìàðêóñ êîòîðûé, âîîáùå ïðîïàë êóäà-òî, ýòîò Ëþòûé âàø ñêàçàë, ÷òî îí âðîäå êàê ñ àíîìàëèè è íå âûøåë, íî òû îá ýòîì ñ íèì ëè÷íî ïîãîâîðè, ìîæåò ÿ è íàïóòàë ÷òî-òî. Äà, åùå êîå-÷òî, òû ýòî, ñõîäè ñî Ñòàâðèäîì ïîãîâîðè, ó íåãî ê òåáå ñåðüåçíûé ðàçãîâîð èìååòñÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_7">
        <text>Ëàäíî, âûïóñêàé ìåíÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_8">
        <text>×óòü íå çàáûë, òåáå òóò äîëãîâåö, ÷òî ñ âàìè áûë, ôëÿãó ñ âîäîé ïåðåäàë, äåðæè.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_security_talk_from_actor_9">
        <text>Ñïàñèáî, îòêðûâàé ðåøåòêó.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_0">
        <text>Ó ìåíÿ åñòü êîå-êàêèå âåùè, êóïèøü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_1">
        <text>Íó, ïîêàçûâàé, ÷òî òàì ó òåáÿ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_10">
        <text>Ýòî òîò, ÷òî ñ âàìè â Ïðîñòðàíñòâåííîì ïóçûðå áûë, äà? Ëþòûé ìíå î íåì ðàññêàçûâàë, äàþ òåáå 1500 ðóáëåé çà ýòîò ÊÏÊ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_11">
        <text>Íó, ìîæåò è ýòî ïðèãîäèòñÿ, äåðæè 1000 ðóáëåé çà ýòó ïèñàíèíó, áîëüøå íå äàì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_12">
        <text>Âîò è îòëè÷íî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_13">
        <text>Ïîêà íè÷åãî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_2">
        <text>Òðîôåéíûé íîæ Õèìèêà.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_3">
        <text>ÊÏÊ Õèìèêà.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_4">
        <text>ÊÏÊ áîéöà ãðóïïèðîâêè «Ïîñëåäíèé äåíü».</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_5">
        <text>Scavenger’s PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_6">
        <text>Çàïèñêà Ñåðîãî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_7">
        <text>Ðåøèë ïðîäàòü íàêîíåö-òî? Äåðæè çà íåãî 4500 ðóáëåé, êðàñèâûé íîæ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_8">
        <text>Õì... Èíòåðåñíî... Äåðæè 2000 ðóáëåé çà íåãî - èíôîðìàöèÿ ëèøíåé íå áûâàåò.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_sell_stuff_9">
        <text>Óõ òû!.. Òû ãäå åãî äîñòàë-òî, à ëàäíî, íå îòâå÷àé, êðåï÷å ñïàòü áóäó, äåðæè çà íåãî 7000 ðóáëåé.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_0">
        <text>Ó ìåíÿ âîäà çàêîí÷èëàñü, ìîæåøü íàïîëíèòü ìîþ ôëÿãó?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_1">
        <text>Íå âîïðîñ, íî ýòî áóäåò òåáå ñòîèòü 2000 ðóáëåé, âîäó î÷èñòèòü íå òàê ïðîñòî, ñàì ïîíèìàåøü. Íó, ÷òî ïî ðóêàì?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_2">
        <text>Ëàäíî, äåðæè 2000 ðóáëåé è ôëÿãó, ÿ ñîãëàñåí.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_3">
        <text>Íåò, ÿ ïåðåäóìàë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_4">
        <text>Îòëè÷íî, ïðèíèìàé çàêàç, ÿ êàê çíàë, ÷òî òû çà âîäîé ïðèäåøü, çàðàíåå íàïîëíèë íåñêîëüêî ôëÿã âîäîé. Ñåé÷àñ è â òó, ÷òî òû ïðèí¸ñ, òîæå âîäû íàáåðó. Ïðèõîäè åùå, êàê ôëÿãà îïóñòååò.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_shaman_water_full_5">
        <text>Õîðîøî, ïðèäó.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_10">
        <text>Íåò. ß áûë íåäàëåêî è íàáëþäàë çà òîáîé. Òû âîçèëñÿ ñíà÷àëà ñ êàêîé-òî øòóêîé, à ïîòîì âñòàë êàê âêîïàííûé è ñòàë ñàì ñ ñîáîé ðàçãîâàðèâàòü. ß óæ áûëî ïîäóìàë, ÷òî ìîæåò êîíòðîëåð òåáå ìîçãè âûïàëèë, à ïîòîì òû ïðîñòî ðóõíóë íà çåìëþ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_11">
        <text>×òî òû òàêîå ãîâîðèøü? Òû òî÷íî íè÷åãî íå ïåðåïóòàë?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_12">
        <text>Íåò, ÿ ïîêà åù¸ ïðè ñâî¸ì óìå. Òû ñëóøàé, ÷òî äàëüøå áûëî. Òû çíà÷èò óïàë, è òóò ðàçäàëñÿ ñìåõ, æóòêèé òàêîé… È ïîÿâèëñÿ êàêîé-òî òèï â ÷¸ðíîì ïëàùå è íàêëîíèëñÿ íàä òîáîé… Íó ÿ åùå íåìíîãî âûæäàë, à ïîòîì âûáåæàë è ïàëüíóë â ýòîãî òèïêà, à îí ñðàçó æå èñ÷åç, ïîñëå ýòîãî ÿ íà áàçó òåáÿ îòíåñ. Çà äâå õîäêè ïðàâäà, ñíà÷àëà òåáÿ, à ïîòîì âñ¸ òâî¸ áàðàõëî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_13">
        <text>Ñïàñèáî òåáå áîëüøîå, ìóæèê. Åñëè ÿ äëÿ òåáÿ ÷òî-òî ñäåëàòü ìîãó - ñêàæè ìíå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_14">
        <text>ß ó÷òó. Òû ìíå ëó÷øå ðàññêàæè, à ÷òî òû âèäåë? Òû äóìàë, ÷òî ñ êåì-òî ðàçãîâàðèâàåøü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_15">
        <text>Äà… Ïåòðîâè÷ äàë ìíå ïåðåäàò÷èê, ÷òîáû ÿ êîîðäèíàòû òî÷êè âûõîäà ïëåíåííûì â ïóçûðå îòïðàâèë, ïîñëå îòïðàâêè ìíîé êîîðäèíàò ñ ïóçûðÿ âûøëè ñòàëêåðû, ýòî áûë Ðûáà è åãî ãðóïïà.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_16">
        <text>×òî çà Ðûáà, òû çíàë åãî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_17">
        <text>Äà, êîãäà ÿ òîëüêî ïðèøåë â Çîíó, îí ñïàñ ìåíÿ, à ïîòîì è ê íà¸ìíèêàì ïðèñòðîèë. Íî ïîñëå Ðûáó âûãíàëè èç Ñèíäèêàòà, è îí ðåøèë, ÷òî ÿ îáÿçàí óéòè âìåñòå ñ íèì, íî ÿ òàê íå ñ÷èòàë. Ðûáà âèíèë ìåíÿ íåïîíÿòíî çà ÷òî, è îáåùàë, ÷òî ìû åù¸ âñòðåòèìñÿ. Äîëãîå âðåìÿ ÿ ïðî Ðûáó íè÷åãî íå ñëûøàë, à ïîòîì êòî-òî ñîîáùèë, ÷òî åãî ñàìîãî è åãî îòðÿä âèäåëè ìåðòâûìè íà ßíòàðå. È ÿ âñ¸ ýòî âðåìÿ äóìàë, ÷òî îí ïîãèá.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_18">
        <text>Ñêîðåå âñåãî îí è ïîãèá.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_19">
        <text>Íî ÿ âèäåë åãî ïåðåä ñîáîé.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_2">
        <text>Î÷íóëñÿ? Ýòî õîðîøî. Êàê ñàìî÷óâñòâèå?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_20">
        <text>Ïåðåä òîáîé íèêîãî íå áûëî, ýòî òî÷íî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_21">
        <text>Ëàäíî, ìîãó òåáå åùå êîå-÷òî ðàññêàçàòü, òîò òèï, êîòîðîãî òû âèäåë âîçëå ìåíÿ, ÿ âñòðå÷àë åãî äî ýòîãî â ïðîñòðàíñòâåííîì ïóçûðå, îí î÷åíü îïàñåí, õîðîøî, ÷òî òû îêàçàëñÿ íåïîäàëåêó è ñïàñ ìåíÿ. Ñïàñèáî åùå ðàç, à ñåé÷àñ èçâèíè, ìíå íóæíî ïîãîâîðèòü ñ Ïåòðîâè÷åì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_22">
        <text>Âîò îíî ÷òî... Ñëóøàé, ñîâåòóþ òåáå ïîêà íèêîìó íå ãîâîðèòü îá ýòîì ñóùåñòâå, ìîãóò íå ïðàâèëüíî ïîíÿòü, ÿ òîæå áóäó ìîë÷àòü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_23">
        <text>Ëàäíî, ïîæàëóé, ïîñëåäóþ òâîåìó ñîâåòó. Óâèäèìñÿ ïîçæå!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_25">
        <text>×åãî òåáå, íà¸ìíèê?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_3">
        <text>×-÷-÷¸ðò… Íå î÷åíü õîðîøî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_4">
        <text>Ìîãëî áûòü õóæå, ÿ òåáÿ ñïàñ, ìîæíî ñêàçàòü. Åñëè áû ÿ âîâðåìÿ íå ïîäîñïåë - òû áûë áû óæå ì¸ðòâ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_5">
        <text>Òàê ýòî òåáå ÿ æèçíüþ îáÿçàí?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_6">
        <text>Ìîæíî è òàê ñêàçàòü, õîðîøî, ÷òî ó ìåíÿ äóõó ýòî ñäåëàòü õâàòèëî, à íå òî íå çíàþ êàê áû âñå ñëîæèëîñü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_7">
        <text>Ìîæåøü ðàññêàçàòü, ÷òî ïðîèçîøëî? È êóäà äåëèñü òå òðîå, ÷òî ìåíÿ óáèòü ïûòàëèñü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_8">
        <text>Âîò êàê ðàç îá ýòîì ÿ è õîòåë ñ òîáîé ïîãîâîðèòü, íå áûëî ñ òîáîé íèêîãî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_sologub_help_meet_9">
        <text>Òû íàøåë ìåíÿ óæå â îòêëþ÷êå?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_0">
        <text>Òàê-òàê… Êòî òóò ó íàñ? Äà íèêàê ñàì Çâåðü? Ñêîëüêî ëåò, ñêîëüêî çèì…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_1">
        <text>Ïðèâåò, Ðûáà…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_2">
        <text>×òî íå îæèäàë óâèäåòü? Õå-õå, ÿ æå îáåùàë òåáå, ÷òî ìû óâèäèìñÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_3">
        <text>Íå îæèäàë, ÷òî òû óãîäèøü â «Ïóçûðü».</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_4">
        <text>À ñ ÷åãî òû âçÿë, ÷òî ìû â íåãî óãîäèëè? Ïîâåðü ìíå, ìû âåðíóëèñü èç ìåñòà, ïîõóæå ïðåèñïîäíåé. È êàê äóìàåøü äëÿ ÷åãî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_5">
        <text>Ïîíÿòèÿ íå èìåþ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_6">
        <text>Çà äîëãè íóæíî ïëàòèòü. È òû çà íèõ çàïëàòèøü - êðîâüþ!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_spatial_fish_meet_7">
        <text>Äàæå íå íà÷èíàé...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_10">
        <text>Ýò ïðàâèëüíî... À ÿ âûïüþ, ïîæàëóé...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_11">
        <text>Òû ñ ÷åãî ïèòü-òî òàê íà÷àë?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_12">
        <text>À ÷òî... Ðàçâå îáÿçàòåëüíî ïîâîä íóæåí?..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_13">
        <text>Íåò, íî â òâîåì ñëó÷àå, òî÷íî åñòü ïðè÷èíà òâîåãî ïüÿíñòâà. Äàâàé ðàññêàçûâàé, ÷òî ó òåáÿ ñëó÷èëîñü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_14">
        <text>Äà ãëóïî âñ¸, ýò… êàê-òî âûøëî. Ïðèøëè ìû ñþäà ñ Ñàøêîé äàâíî, äàâíî åùå. Îäíè èç ïåðâûõ. Ñàøêà âîîáùå, âñþ îêðóãó êàê ñâîè ïÿòü ïàëüöåâ çíàë. Ýõ…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_15">
        <text>È ÷òî äàëüøå áûëî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_16">
        <text>Êàê-òî ïîññîðèëèñü ìû ñ íèì, èç-çà ïóñòÿêà ïîññîðèëèñü òî. Íó îí è ýòî… Ðåøèë, êîðî÷å ñàì â ðåéä ïîéòè, à ÿ íà áàçå îñòàëñÿ… Òàê è íå âåðíóëñÿ Ñàøêà. ß åãî ïîòîì äîëãî-î-î èñêàë, íî íèãäå íàéòè íå ìîã. À íåäàâíî, ÿ åãî óâèäåë. Òî÷íåå, òî, ÷òî îò íåãî îñòàëîñü…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_17">
        <text>Óæå íè÷åãî íå âåðíóòü, à òåáå ëó÷øå áðîñèòü ïèòü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_18">
        <text>Äà ÿ ïîíèìàþ… Ìîæåøü ìíå ïîìî÷ü äðóæèùå? Ñàøêó-òî ÿ ñðåäè çîìáè âèäåë. Îí òîæå òàêèì ñòàë. Íàâåðíîå, ãäå-òî â ïîëå ýòîãî… êàê åãî? Â èçëó÷åíèå ýòî ãàäñêîå ïîïàë, âîò îíî åìó ìîçãè è ðàñïëàâèëî. Óïîêîé åãî äóøó, à? Íå ìîãó ÿ âèäåòü, êàê äðóã ìîé è äðóãèå õîðîøèå ïàðíè ñòðàäàþò. È ñàì èì ïîìî÷ü íå ìîãó, ðóêà íå ïîäíèìàåòñÿ…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_19">
        <text>Íå ïåðåæèâàé, ÿ âûïîëíþ òâîþ ïðîñüáó.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_2">
        <text>Àãà-à! ×-÷åãî? Òåáå ÷åãî íàäî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_20">
        <text>Âî-î-îò ñïàñèáî. ß òåáå ýòîãî íå çàáóäó. Çîìáèðîâàííûå íà êëàäáèùå, ýò íå äàëåêî îò áàçû... ß òåáå ìåòêó ñêèíó...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_21">
        <text>Ñêèäûâàé ìåòêó è ÿ ïîøåë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_23">
        <text>×-÷òî òàì? Êàêèå íîâîñòè?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_24">
        <text>ß èçáàâèë îò ñòðàäàíèé òâîåãî äðóãà è äðóãèõ çîìáèðîâàííûõ íà êëàäáèùå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_25">
        <text>Ýò õ-õîðîøî... Ñïàñèáî òåáå, ìóæèê... Â-â-âûðó÷èë... Äåðæè âîò îò ìåíÿ...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_26">
        <text>Çà ñòâîë ñïàñèáî. Äàì òåáå ñîâåò, áðîñàé ïèòü, Êîñîé, äðóãà òû ñâîèì ïüÿíñòâîì âñå-ðàâíî óæå íå âåðíåøü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_28">
        <text>×-÷-÷åãî òåáå?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_29">
        <text>Ïîêà íåò íîâîñòåé.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_3">
        <text>Òû ÷åãî ïüÿíûé òî òàêîé?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_4">
        <text>Ý-ý-ý… Òàê í-íàäî... Õå-õå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_5">
        <text>×åãî ñìååøüñÿ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_6">
        <text>Äà-à-à òàê, øóòêó âñïîìíèë. Ýõ, íàäîåëî âñ¸…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_7">
        <text>Ìîæåò òåáå ïîìî÷ü ÷åì?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_8">
        <text>Íó-ó ïîìîãè òîãäà. Ýò… Äàâàé âûïüåì...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_drunk_quest_9">
        <text>Íå ïüþ, áðîñèë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_0">
        <text>Òû Ëûñûé? Ìíå íóæíî ñ òîáîé ïîãîâîðèòü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_1">
        <text>Íó ÿ, ÷òî ñ òîãî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_10">
        <text>Íàçàä óæå íè÷åãî íå âåðíóòü, ëó÷øå èñïîëíè ïîñëåäíþþ âîëþ ñâîåãî äðóãà.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_11">
        <text>Ìåíÿ Ðÿáîé ïðîñèë òåáÿ íàéòè. Çíàåøü òàêîãî ñòàëêåðà?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_12">
        <text>Ðÿáîé? ×¸ðò, ÷òî ñ íèì? Òàê îí âñå-òàêè æèâ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_13">
        <text>Íåò, îí áûë íå â ñåáå, è ïîêîí÷èë ñ ñîáîé. Îí áûë â î÷åíü ïëîõîì ñîñòîÿíèè, íè÷åãî íå ñîîáðàæàë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_14">
        <text>Íåò, íåò, íåò! Ñ íèì áûë åù¸ êòî-òî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_15">
        <text>Íåò, îí áûë îäèí. Îí âñå áðåäèë ïðî «Âûæèãàòåëü» è êàêîãî-òî Ãîðáóíà...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_16">
        <text>Ýòî ìîÿ âèíà… Ýòî èç-çà ìåíÿ ïîãèá Ãîðáóí, à Ðÿáîìó äîñòàëîñü. Â ñàìûé òÿæ¸ëûé ìîìåíò ÿ èõ ïðåäàë è ñáåæàë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_17">
        <text>Ðàññêàæè ïîäðîáíåé, ÷òî ïðîèçîøëî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_18">
        <text>ß, Ãîðáóí è Ðÿáîé äàâíî ãîòîâèëèñü ïðîðûâàòüñÿ íà ñåâåð. Ó íàñ íå õâàòàëî òîëüêî âðåìåíè ñïàäà èçëó÷åíèÿ «Âûæèãàòåëÿ», è Ðÿáîé äîñòàë ýòó èíôîðìàöèþ, ó îäíîãî ñòàëêåðà èç «Ïîñëåäíåãî äíÿ». Ó Øâåäà êàæåòñÿ. Ìû ïðîøëè ïîë Ðàäàðà, êàê «Âûæèãàòåëü» íåîæèäàííî âêëþ÷èëñÿ. Ðÿáîìó ñíåñëî êðûøó, îí ïîòåðÿë ñîçíàíèå è ñâàëèëñÿ ñî ñêëîíà. À ïîñëå êóäà-òî èñ÷åç. Åãî íå áûëî íà òîì ìåñòå ãäå îí äîëæåí áûë óïàñòü. È ÏÄÀ åãî íå îòâå÷àë. ß çàïàíèêîâàë, ðåøèë âñ¸ áðîñèòü è âîçâðàùàòüñÿ. Ãîðáóí íàñòàèâàë íà òîì, ÷òîáû ìû îòïðàâèëèñü èñêàòü Ðÿáîãî, íî ýòî áûëî áû ÷èñòåéøèì ñàìîóáèéñòâîì. ß ñîãëàñèëñÿ ñ Ãîðáóíîì, è îí ïîëåç âíèç ïî ñêëîíó òóäà, ãäå äîëæåí áûë áûòü Ðÿáîé. È òóò î÷åðåäíîé âñïëåñê «Âûæèãàòåëÿ» íàêðûë íàñ. ß îïîìíèëñÿ óæå âîçëå âîåííîé áàçû, äî ýòîãî âðåìåíè ÿ ñ÷èòàë, ÷òî îíè ïîãèáëè…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_19">
        <text>Íàçàä óæå íè÷åãî íå âåðíóòü, Ëûñûé. Íå êîðè ñåáÿ çà ñîäåÿííîå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_2">
        <text>Ðÿáîé ïîïðîñèë ìåíÿ íàéòè òåáÿ. È ïåðåäàòü ýòîò àðòåôàêò.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_3">
        <text>Ðÿáîé? ×¸ðò, ÷òî ñ íèì? Òàê îí âñå-òàêè æèâ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_4">
        <text>Íåò, îí áûë íå â ñåáå, è ïîêîí÷èë ñ ñîáîé. Îí áûë â î÷åíü ïëîõîì ñîñòîÿíèè, íè÷åãî íå ñîîáðàæàë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_5">
        <text>Íåò, íåò, íåò! Ñ íèì áûë åù¸ êòî-òî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_6">
        <text>Íåò, îí áûë îäèí. Îí âñå áðåäèë ïðî «Âûæèãàòåëü» è êàêîãî-òî Ãîðáóíà. Ïîòîì ïîïðîñèë îòäàòü òåáå àðòåôàêò, îí ñêàçàë, ÷òîáû òû ïåðåäàë ýòîò àðòåôàêò åãî æåíå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_7">
        <text>Ýòî ìîÿ âèíà… Ýòî èç-çà ìåíÿ ïîãèá Ãîðáóí, à Ðÿáîìó äîñòàëîñü. Â ñàìûé òÿæ¸ëûé ìîìåíò ÿ èõ ïðåäàë è ñáåæàë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_8">
        <text>Ðàññêàæè ïîäðîáíåé, ÷òî ïðîèçîøëî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_meet_9">
        <text>ß, Ãîðáóí è Ðÿáîé äàâíî ãîòîâèëèñü ïðîðûâàòüñÿ íà ñåâåð. Ó íàñ íå õâàòàëî òîëüêî âðåìåíè ñïàäà èçëó÷åíèÿ «Âûæèãàòåëÿ», è Ðÿáîé äîñòàë ýòó èíôîðìàöèþ, ó îäíîãî ñòàëêåðà èç «Ïîñëåäíåãî äíÿ». Ó Øâåäà êàæåòñÿ. Ìû ïðîøëè ïîë Ðàäàðà, êàê «Âûæèãàòåëü» íåîæèäàííî âêëþ÷èëñÿ. Ðÿáîìó ñíåñëî êðûøó, îí ïîòåðÿë ñîçíàíèå è ñâàëèëñÿ ñî ñêëîíà. À ïîñëå êóäà-òî èñ÷åç. Åãî íå áûëî íà òîì ìåñòå ãäå îí äîëæåí áûë óïàñòü. È ÏÄÀ åãî íå îòâå÷àë. ß çàïàíèêîâàë, ðåøèë âñ¸ áðîñèòü è âîçâðàùàòüñÿ. Ãîðáóí íàñòàèâàë íà òîì, ÷òîáû ìû îòïðàâèëèñü èñêàòü Ðÿáîãî, íî ýòî áûëî áû ÷èñòåéøèì ñàìîóáèéñòâîì. ß ñîãëàñèëñÿ ñ Ãîðáóíîì, è îí ïîëåç âíèç ïî ñêëîíó òóäà, ãäå äîëæåí áûë áûòü Ðÿáîé. È òóò î÷åðåäíîé âñïëåñê «Âûæèãàòåëÿ» íàêðûë íàñ. ß îïîìíèëñÿ óæå âîçëå âîåííîé áàçû, äî ýòîãî âðåìåíè ÿ ñ÷èòàë, ÷òî îíè ïîãèáëè…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_stalker_in_bar_start_2">
        <text>×åãî õî÷åøü, íà¸ìíèê? ß íå â íàñòðîåíèè ãîâîðèòü...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_11">
        <text>ß ðàä, ÷òî òû â ïîðÿäêå, íà¸ìíèê. Íà ñ÷åò ñëó÷èâøåãîñÿ ñ òîáîé íà çàâîäå, ñ ðàññïðîñàìè ëåçòü ê òåáå íå áóäó, åñëè åñòü ÷åì ïîäåëèòñÿ, òî ïîäåëèñü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_12">
        <text>Âñ¸ õîðîøî, íå çàáèâàé ãîëîâó. ×òî òàì çà èíôîðìàöèÿ â ÊÏÊ Ìèêëóõè?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_13">
        <text>Ëàäíî, òîãäà ïåðåéäåì ïîæàëóé ê çàïèñÿì â ÊÏÊ, Ïåòðîâè÷ó íå óäàëîñü ðàñøèôðîâàòü âñå çàïèñè, íî âñå æå ìû ñìîãëè íàéòè ïîëåçíóþ èíôîðìàöèþ, ó Ìèêëóõè áûë çàïàñíîé ïëàí êàê âûáèòü ìîíîëèòîâöåâ ñ Çàñòàâû. Ïëàí äîâîëüíî òàêè ïðîñò, íóæíî çàìàñêèðîâàòüñÿ ïîä ìîíîëèòîâöåâ, ïðîíèêíóòü íà èõ áàçó è ñ ïîìîùüþ âçðûâ÷àòêè ïîäîðâàòü çäàíèå. ß äóìàþ, ÷òî äàííûé ïëàí íóæíî îïðîáîâàòü, íî â ïåðâó î÷åðåäü, íóæíî äîñòàòü êîñòþì ìîíîëèòîâöåâ è ÊÏÊ îäíîãî èç íèõ. Çàòåì òû è Ñîëîãóá, ïåðåîäåâøèñü, ïðîáåðåòåñü ê íèì íà áàçó, óñòàíîâèòå çàðÿä âçðûâ÷àòêè, çàïóñòèòå åãî è òóò æå âåðíåòåñü îáðàòíî. Òàêîé âîò ïëàí.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_14">
        <text>Íåïëîõîé ïëàí, íî ãäå äîñòàòü äâà êîñòþìà ìîíîëèòîâöåâ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_15">
        <text>ß ïðîáèë ïî ñâîèì êàíàëàì, îäèí òîðãîâåö ãîòîâ ïðåäîñòàâèòü íàì äâà ìîíîëèòîâñêèõ êîñòþìà, íî â îáìåí íà êîñòþìû îí ïðîñèò ñòâîë SR-3 Vikhr, ãäå äîñòàòü òàêîé ñòâîë ÿ íå çíàþ, ïîñòàâùèêè Ðàñïóòèíà òîæå íå ñìîãóò åãî äîñòàòü. Ìîæåò òû ïî ñâîèì êàíàëàì ïðîáúåøü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_16">
        <text>Ìîè êàíàëû íå ñòàíóò ìíå ïîìîãàòü, ëó÷øå âîîáùå íå ñâÿçûâàòüñÿ ñåé÷àñ ñ Ñèíäèêàòîì, ïîñëå ñëó÷èâøåãîñÿ â ïðîñòðàíñòâåííîì ïóçûðå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_17">
        <text>Ïëîõî, íî âñå æå, ïîñïðàøèâàé ëþäåé ïî ýòîìó ïîâîäó, ìîæåò è íàéäåì òàêîé ñòâîë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_18">
        <text>Ëàäíî, ÿ ïîïûòàþñü ðàçäîáûòü ýòîò ñòâîë. Ïîãîâîðèì ïîçæå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_2">
        <text>Ñ ÷åì ïîæàëîâàë, íà¸ìíèê?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_20">
        <text>Ñ ÷åì ïîæàëîâàë, íà¸ìíèê?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_22">
        <text>Çâåðü, òû ãäå áûë? Ó íàñ òóò òàêîå ïðîèçîøëî, òå äâîå áàíäèòîâ, ÷òî â êëåòêå ñèäåëè, îíè ñáåæàëè ýòîé íî÷üþ. Ãëàâíîå, ÷òî íåïîíÿòíî, êàê âîîáùå îíè îñâîáîäèòñÿ ñìîãëè, äóìàþ, ÷òî èì ïîìîã êòî-òî èç ìîèõ. Òû íè÷åãî ïîäîçðèòåëüíîãî íå çàìå÷àë â ïîñëåäíåå âðåìÿ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_23">
        <text>Íåò, âðîäå áû íè÷åãî ïîäîçðèòåëüíîãî íå çàìåòèë... Êñòàòè, ÿ ðàçäîáûë íóæíûé ñòâîë äëÿ òîãî òîðãîâöà.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_24">
        <text>Ëàäíî, ñ ïîáåãîì ÿ ïîçæå ðàçáåðóñü, ãäå òû äîáûë ýòîò ñòâîë?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_25">
        <text>Íó... Ñòàðûå ñâÿçè âñ¸ æå ïðèãîäèëèñü...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_26">
        <text>Ýòî î÷åíü õîðîøî, òåïåðü ìû ñìîæåì âîïëîòèòü â æèçíü ïëàí Ìèêëóõè è íàêîíåö-òî óíè÷òîæèòü ýòèõ ìîíîëèòîâöåâ. Àõ äà, ìû ðàñøèôðîâàëè åùå îäèí èç ôàéëîâ â ÊÏÊ Ìèêëóõè, îêàçûâàåòñÿ, ÷òî ïîä Çàñòàâîé åñòü ëàáîðàòîðèÿ è ìîíîëèòîâöàì ïîñòàâëÿþò îðóæèå è íîâûõ áîéöîâ èìåííî ÷åðåç íåå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_27">
        <text>Ìäà, ÷åì äàëüøå â ëåñ... Òàê, äëÿ íà÷àëà íóæíî èõ áàçó íà ñòðîéêå óíè÷òîæèòü, à òàì ïîñìîòðèì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_28">
        <text>Âñ¸ íè÷åãî, íî íóæíî áóäåò äîæäàòüñÿ äîñòàâêè êîñòþìîâ, íå çíàþ ñêîëüêî âðåìåíè ýòî ìîæåò çàíÿòü. Äàâàé ñþäà ñòâîë, ÿ îòïðàâëþ åãî òîðãîâöó è áóäåì îæèäàòü îò íåãî ïîñûëêó.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_29">
        <text>Ëàäíî, äåðæè ñòâîë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_3">
        <text>Ñâîáîäîâöåâ íà çàâîäå çàæàëè ìîíîëèòîâöû, íóæíà òâîÿ ïîìîùü, Ñòàâðèä, äàé ìíå íåñêîëüêèõ áîéöîâ, íóæíî îñâîáîäèòü ãðóïïó Ìèêëóõè.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_30">
        <text>Àãà, ìîæåøü èäòè, ÿ ïîçîâó òåáÿ ñðàçó æå, êàê ïîñûëêà ñ êîñòþìàìè áóäåò ó ìåíÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_31">
        <text>Ïîíÿë, äî âñòðå÷è.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_33">
        <text>Çâåðü, êîñòþìû ïîêà íå ïðèáûëè, çàéäè ïîçæå, ëàäíî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_35">
        <text>Õîðîøèå íîâîñòè, Çâåðü! Ïðèáûëà íàøà ïîñûëêà ñ êîìáèíåçîíàìè, òåïåðü ìîæíî è çà âûïîëíåíèå ïëàíà ïî óíè÷òîæåíèþ ìîíîëèòîâöåâ âçÿòüñÿ. Òû êàê ãîòîâ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_36">
        <text>Íó, ìîæíî ñêàçàòü, ÷òî ãîòîâ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_37">
        <text>Äà, ÿ ïîíèìàþ, ÷òî ïëàí íå èäåàëåí è îñòàåòñÿ øàíñ, ÷òî âàñ ðàñêîëÿò, íî ýòîò øàíñ ÷åðòîâñêè ìàë. Ìîíîëèòîâöû áåç ìîçãîâ ñîâñåì, îíè íå ñìîãóò ïîíÿòü, ÷òî ýòî ïîäñòàâà.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_38">
        <text>Ëàäíî, ãäå Ñîëîãóá ñåé÷àñ, îí ãîòîâ èäòè?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_39">
        <text>Àõ äà, íà ñ÷åò Ñîëîãóáà, ñ òîáîé ïîéäåò íå îí... Ëþòûé î÷åíü ðâàëñÿ èäòè ñ òîáîé, ÿ ñíà÷àëà íå õîòåë ñîãëàøàòüñÿ, íî âñå æå ðåøèë, ÷òî òåáå ñ íèì áóäåò ñïîêîéíåå. Îí óæå îäåë ñâîé êîìáèíåçîí è æäåò òåáÿ âíèçó, íî ñíà÷àëà ñõîäè ê Ïåòðîâè÷ó, îí ïåðåíàñòðîèò òâîé ÊÏÊ, òàê æå êàê è ÊÏÊ Ëþòîãî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_4">
        <text>Ïðîñòè, íî ÿ íå ìîãó ðèñêîâàòü ñâîèìè ïàðíÿìè, òû âûáðàëñÿ è ýòî ãëàâíîå, îñòàëüíîå íåâàæíî. Ìû ñî ñâîáîäîâöàìè íå òàê ñèëüíî äðóæèì, ÷òîáû çà èõ ñïàñåíèå óìèðàòü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_40">
        <text>Ïîíÿë, ñõîæó ê Ïåòðîâè÷ó. Íî ñíà÷àëà, äàâàé åùå ðàç ïî ïëàíó ïðîáåæèìñÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_41">
        <text>Çíà÷èò òàê, âû ñ Ëþòûì ïðîáèðàåòåñü íà áàçó ìîíîëèòîâöåâ, òâîåé çàäà÷åé áóäåò - çàëîæèòü âçðûâ÷àòêó, ïðèêðåïèâ å¸ ê êîëîíå íà âòîðîì ýòàæå çäàíèÿ, Ëþòûé â ñâîþ î÷åðåäü ïîïûòàåòñÿ îòâëå÷ü âíèìàíèå ìîíîëèòîâöåâ. Ïîñëå òîãî, êàê òû çàëîæèøü âçðûâ÷àòêó, áåãîì âîçâðàùàåòåñü íà áàçó, ÷òîáû âàñ âìåñòå ñ ìîíîëèòîâöàìè íå çàâàëèëî, âîò òàêîé ïëàí. Òàê, äåðæè ñâîé ìîíîëèòîâñêèé êîìáèíåçîí è âçðûâ÷àòêó. Íè ïóõà, íè ïåðà âàì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_42">
        <text>Ê ÷åðòó.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_44">
        <text>Çâåðü, êîñòþìû ïîêà íå ïðèáûëè, çàéäè ïîçæå, ëàäíî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_46">
        <text>×òî òàì ó âàñ ñëó÷èëîñü, Çâåðü? Ãäå Ëþòûé?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_47">
        <text>Íàñ ðàñêðûëè... Ñêîðåå âñåãî, ìîíîëèòîâöû óâåëè Ëþòîãî â ëàáîðàòîðèþ, îíè æäóò, ÷òî ÿ ïîéäó åìó íà âûðó÷êó. Íå çíàþ, ÷òî îíè çàäóìàëè, íî èì íóæíî äëÿ ÷åãî-òî çàìàíèòü ìåíÿ â ëàáîðàòîðèþ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_48">
        <text>Âîò æå, òàêîé õîðîøèé ïëàí ïðîâàëèëñÿ... Òàê, ÿ îäíîãî íå ìîãó ïîíÿòü, êàê òû óçíàë, ÷òî îíè óâåëè Ëþòîãî â ëàáîðàòîðèþ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_49">
        <text>Ìåíÿ âûðóáèëè, à êîãäà ÿ î÷íóëñÿ, òî â ëàãåðå ìîíîëèòîâöåâ óæå ïî÷òè íèêîãî íå áûëî, áûë òîëüêî îäèí ìîíîëèòîâåö, îí è ðàññêàçàë ìíå îáî âñåì ýòîì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_5">
        <text>Äà êàê òû ìîæåøü òàê ãîâîðèòü? Åñëè íå ïîìî÷ü èì ñåé÷àñ - îíè ïîãèáíóò.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_50">
        <text>Çíà÷èò âûõîäèò, ÷òî ìîíîëèòîâöåâ íà áàçå áîëüøå íåò, îíè âñå óøëè?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_51">
        <text>Äà, íî ñîìíåâàþñü, ÷òî îíè óøëè íàñîâñåì...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_52">
        <text>Íàñêîëüêî ÿ ïîíÿë, òû ñîáèðàåøüñÿ ïîéòè íà ïîäìîãó Ëþòîìó, íå òàê ëè? Äóìàþ, ÷òî òåáå íå ñòîèò ýòîãî äåëàòü, ýòî ÷èñòîé âîäû ñàìîóáèéñòâî. Ïðîñòî çàáóäü îá ýòîé çàòåå, òåì áîëåå Õàíòåð âîí ÷àñà ïîë íàçàä ïðèøåë íà õóòîð, òåáÿ èñêàë, ãîâîðèë, ÷òî îí ãîòîâ âûâåñòè òåáÿ èç Çàñòàâû. Ïðîñòî óõîäè, Ëþòîãî òû óæå íå ñïàñåøü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_53">
        <text>ß äîëæåí ñïàñòè Ëþòîãî, íåëüçÿ ïðîñòî òàê âñ¸ îñòàâèòü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_55">
        <text>Ìîæåò âñå æå òû îòêàæåøüñÿ îò ýòîé ãëóïîé ìûñëè? Åñëè ñïóñòèøüñÿ â ëàáîðàòîðèþ ñåé÷àñ, òû òðóï...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_56">
        <text>ß äîëæåí ñïàñòè Ëþòîãî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_57">
        <text>Ìîæåò áûòü òû è ïðàâ, íåò ãàðàíòèé, ÷òî Ëþòûé âñ¸ åùå æèâ...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_58">
        <text>Âîò èìåííî! Ìîé òåáå ñîâåò, ñõîäè ê Ïåòðîâè÷ó, îí îáðàòíî ïåðåíàñòðîèò òâîé ÊÏÊ, èçáàâñÿ îò ýòîãî ãðåáàííîãî ìîíîëèòîâñêîãî êîìáèíåçîíà è ñ Õàíòåðîì ïîãîâîðè, ãëàâíîå íå ëåçü â ýòó ëàáîðàòîðèþ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_59">
        <text>Ëàäíî, òàê è áûòü, ïîéäó ê Ïåòðîâè÷ó, à çàòåì ê Õàíòåðó ñõîæó.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_6">
        <text>Ñêîðåå âñåãî îíè óæå ïîãèáëè, ÿ íå ìîãó ðèñêîâàòü ñâîèìè ëþäüìè.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_61">
        <text>Óäà÷è, Çâåðü! Íàäåþñü, ÷òî åùå ñâèäåìñÿ...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_63">
        <text>Çäðàâñòâóé, Çâåðü. Óäàëîñü ðàçäîáûòü õîòü êàêèå-òî ñâåäåíüÿ î òîì, ãäå íàì äîñòàòü ýòîò SR-3 Vikhr?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_64">
        <text>Âðîäå áû äà, îäèí èç òåõ áàíäèòîâ, ÷òî â êëåòêå íà õóòîðå ñèäÿò, ñêàçàë, ÷òî åñëè ÿ îñâîáîæó èõ, òî âçàìåí îí ïîäãîíèò ýòîò ñàìûé Vikhr.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_65">
        <text>Âîò ñêîòû... Ìîæåò èì ïðîñòî èãîëêè ïîä íîãòè çàãíàòü è ñèëîé çàñòàâèòü ðàññêàçàòü î ñõðîíå ñî ñòâîëîì?..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_66">
        <text>Ïîïðîñèë ñòàùèòü êëþ÷ ó Ñîëîãóáà íî÷üþ è ïåðåäàòü åãî èì, çà ýòî è îáåùàë ñòâîë. Òàêæå îáåùàëè íå ñòðåëÿòü, áàíäèò ñêàçàë, ÷òî îíè ïðîñòî ñâàëÿò ïî-òèõîìó.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_67">
        <text>Ìäà, ñèòóàöèÿ... Êàê äóìàåøü, ìîæíî âåðèòü, ÷òî îíè âûïîëíÿò ñâîè îáåùàíèÿ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_68">
        <text>Äóìàþ, ÷òî èì ìîæíî âåðèòü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_69">
        <text>Íå óâåðåí, ÷òî ñòîèò âåðèòü áàíäèòàì, íî äðóãîãî âûõîäà ïîêà ó íàñ íåò.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_7">
        <text>Ýõ òû... Ëàäíî, ÿ ñàì ïîïûòàþñü èõ ñïàñòè.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_70">
        <text>Äîæèëè... Íà ïîâîäó ó áàíäèòîâ ïðèõîäèòñÿ èäòè, õîòÿ... Åñòü îäíà èäåÿ, ìîæíî ïîäûãðàòü áàíäèòàì, ÿ äàì òåáå êëþ÷ îò êëåòêè, òû ïåðåäàøü åãî èì, ðåáÿò íà õóòîðå ïðåäóïðåæó, ÷òîáû òå áûëè ãîòîâû ê ëþáûì äåéñòâèÿì ñî ñòîðîíû áàíäþêîâ. Åñëè âñ¸ ïðîéäåò ãëàäêî è áàíäèòû ñäåðæàò ñâî¸ ñëîâî, òî ïóñòü æèâóò, íî ìíå è ìîèì ðåáÿòàì èì íà ãëàçà ëó÷øå áîëüøå íå ïîïàäàòüñÿ. Êàê òåáå òàêîé ïëàí, Çâåðü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_71">
        <text>Äóìàþ, ÷òî ïëàí ìîæåò ïðîêàòèòü, â ëþáîì ñëó÷àå, ýòî ëó÷øå, ÷åì ïðîñòî óêðàñòü êëþ÷ äëÿ áàíäèòîâ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_72">
        <text>Ñîìíåâàþñü, ÷òî ýòî ïðîêàòèò, áàíäèò ñêàçàë, ÷òî ñòâîëû ó êàêîãî-òî òðåòüåãî ëèöà è îòäàñò îí èõ òîëüêî çà ñâîáîäó áàíäèòîâ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_73">
        <text>×åðò è êàêîé æå ïëàí ïî îñâîáîæäåíèþ ýòîò áàíäèò òåáå ïðåäëîæèë?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_74">
        <text>Òàê, ëàäíî, íàâåðíîå òàê è ïîñòóïèì, äåðæè êëþ÷, ñêàæåøü, ÷òî ñòàùèë êëþ÷ ó Ñîëîãóáà, ïîñëå ýòîãî "ïîáåãà" ïîäíèìåøüñÿ êî ìíå, ðàññêàæåøü êàê âñ¸ ïðîøëî, ëàäû?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_75">
        <text>Äîãîâîðèëèñü, ÿ ïîøåë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_79">
        <text>Êàê âñ¸ ïðîøëî, Çâåðü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_80">
        <text>Áàíäèòû ñâàëèëè áåç øóìó è ïûëè, ñêàçàëè óòðîì çàéòè çà Vikhr â ñòàðóþ øêîëó. Âîò, âîçâðàùàþ êëþ÷ îáðàòíî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_81">
        <text>Íó, ÷òî æå, ïîñìîòðèì ñäåðæàò ëè îíè ñâî¸ ñëîâî...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_82">
        <text>Óòðîì è ïðîâåðèì, ñåé÷àñ ãàäàòü áåç ïîëüçû.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_84">
        <text>Íó, Çâåðü. Áàíäèòû ñäåðæàëè ñâî¸ ñëîâî, óäàëîñü äîáûòü ñòâîë?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_85">
        <text>Äà, óäèâèòåëüíî, íî ñâî¸ ñëîâî îíè ñäåðæàëè, SR-3 Vikhr óæå ó ìåíÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_86">
        <text>Ýòî î÷åíü õîðîøî, òåïåðü ìû ñìîæåì âîïëîòèòü â æèçíü ïëàí Ìèêëóõè è íàêîíåö-òî óíè÷òîæèòü ýòèõ ìîíîëèòîâöåâ. Àõ äà, êñòàòè, ìû ðàñøèôðîâàëè åùå îäèí ôàéë â ÊÏÊ Ìèêëóõè, îêàçûâàåòñÿ, ÷òî ïîä Çàñòàâîé åñòü ëàáîðàòîðèÿ è ìîíîëèòîâöàì ïîñòàâëÿþò îðóæèå è íîâûõ áîéöîâ èìåííî ÷åðåç íåå.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_87">
        <text>Ìäà, ÷åì äàëüøå â ëåñ... Òàê, äëÿ íà÷àëà íóæíî èõ áàçó íà ñòðîéêå óíè÷òîæèòü, à òàì ïîñìîòðèì.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_88">
        <text>Áàíäèòû ñâàëèëè áåç øóìó è ïûëè, ñêàçàëè óòðîì çàéòè çà Vikhr â ñòàðóþ øêîëó. Âîò, âîçâðàùàþ òâîé êëþ÷ è êëþ÷ Ñîëîãóáà îáðàòíî çàîäíî.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_9">
        <text>Ñ ÷åì ïîæàëîâàë, íà¸ìíèê?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_91">
        <text>Ñ ÷åì ïîæàëîâàë, Çâåðü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_92">
        <text>Äàâàé ïîãîâîðèì ïîñëå ïåðåäà÷è êëþ÷à áàíäèòàì, ëàäíî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_Saurel_zavod_zasada_93">
        <text>Õîðîøî, ÿ ïîøåë.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_1_0">
        <text>Ñëóøàé, Ðàñïóòèí, ÿ èùó ñòâîë îäèí, SR-3 Vikhr íàçûâàåòñÿ, òû íå ìîæåøü òàêîé ïîäîãíàòü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_1_1">
        <text>ß óæå ãîâîðèë ñî Ñòàâðèäîì ïî ýòîìó ïîâîäó, ñêàæó è òåáå òîæå ñàìîå, ìîè ïîñòàâùèêè íå â ñèëàõ ïîäîãíàòü ýòîò ñòâîë, îí î÷åíü ðåäêèé.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_1_2">
        <text>Ëàäíî, ñïàñèáî çà îòâåò.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_1_3">
        <text>Äà íå çà ÷òî, êàê áóäåò íóæíà ïîìîùü - îáðàùàéñÿ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_2_0">
        <text>ß èùó ñòâîë SR-3 Vikhr, íå çíàåøü ãäå òàêîé ìîæíî ðàçäîáûòü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_2_1">
        <text>Ýòî òû äëÿ òîãî òîðãîâöà, ÷òî ìîíîëèòîâñêèå êîñòþìû íà ýòîò ñòâîë ñîãëàñèëñÿ ïîìåíÿòü? Íåò, íå çíàþ, íî êîå-÷òî ìîãó òî÷íî ñêàçàòü, åñëè ýòîò ñòâîë íå ìîæåò äîñòàòü Ðàñïóòèí, òî íèêòî åãî íàâåðíîå íå ñìîæåò äîñòàòü. Âîò òàê.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_3_0">
        <text>Ïðèâåò, Êîñîé, ìíå íóæåí ñòâîë SR-3 Vikhr, íå ïîäñêàæåøü ãäå òàêîé íàéòè?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_3_1">
        <text>Í-íåò, ñ ýòèì íå êî ìíå... Ìíå òâîè ï-ïðîáëåìû íå í-íóæíû, ó ìåíÿ è ñ-ñâîèõ õâàòàåò...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_4_0">
        <text>ß èùó àâòîìàò SR-3 Vikhr, íå çíàåøü ãäå òàêîé íàéòè ìîæíî?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_4_1">
        <text>À áåç ïîíÿòèÿ, åñëè Ðàñïóòèí íå çíàåò, òî ñõîäè ê Ïåòðîâè÷ó, ìîæåò îí ñìîæåò åãî äîñòàòü.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_5_0">
        <text>Ïðèâåò, Ïåòðîâè÷, ÿ èùó îäèí óíèêàëüíûé ñòâîë SR-3 Vikhr, ìîæåò õîòü òû ñìîæåøü åãî äîñòàòü?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="blck_val_vihr_meet_5_1">
        <text>Õì, íåò, äîñòàòü ÿ åãî íå ñìîãó, äà è ñîìíåâàþñü, ÷òî íà Çàñòàâå íàéäåòñÿ ÷åëîâåê, êîòîðûé ñìîæåò.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
