<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_0">
        <text>Damn! You scared me, Beast! You were out for a long-ass time. Wait. Hold on. We’ve got more important things to deal with right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_1">
        <text>What the hell? What happened, Markus?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_2">
        <text>I’m not sure, but that creature’s gotta be messing with us. We shouldn’t have gone there. The second I sent you that message, something knocked me out, and then I woke up here. I think this might be its den. I was a little bit glad I was finally out of that damn anomaly at first, but according to my PDA, we’re still in it. Just underground.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_3">
        <text>Damn. I would kill to be back at the Cordon. But more importantly, what kind of creature are you talking about? A new species of mutant?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_4">
        <text>I’m not sure. I saw it a few times, but it’s not like I could tell the others. There’s no way they would believe me. Physically, it kind of looks like a bloodsucker, but it acts and talks like a normal human, and it even wears clothes! It’s got a straight posture, and it looks like it understands simple mechanisms. Also, when it was close to me, my PDA’s nearby contacts list updated with an entry named “Stronglav.” But that’s not even the weirdest part: I took a few potshots at it, and it just straight up vanished! The damn thing even laughed at me, Beast… I just don’t even know what to do!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_5">
        <text>Hmm… I think I saw it too. I just thought it was some kind of hallucination, though. This place is weird after all. Don’t worry, though, Markus. There has to be a way out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_6">
        <text>I’ve already tried looking for an exit! The only thing I could think of is either killing that monster or going up the ladder further into the cave. I’ve already tried the ladder; when you hit a certain point during the climb, it just teleports you back here. Wait… Holy shit. Did you hear that?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_7">
        <text>No? Are you okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_8">
        <text>That sound… and this strange feeling. And that god awful smell! Like something’s being roasted alive… Wait. I remember this! That same stench hung around in the air whenever I saw that mutant!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_9">
        <text>Fantastic.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_0">
        <text>What the fuck, Beast?! You blew our cover! Now those mutants are gonna come straight for us!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_1">
        <text>I was just trying to kill that thing! What the hell happened?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_2">
        <text>How the hell should I know? Wait. We’ve got to focus. We have to get out of here, right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_3">
        <text>Yeah. I agree. We’re done for if we just sit here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_4">
        <text>I feel like shit, though. I’m not in any condition to go exploring. You go look for the exit, and I’ll cover this area in case it comes back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_5">
        <text>Sounds good to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_6">
        <text>All right. Keep an eye out for the exit or anything we can use, and message me on my PDA if you find anything. Now hurry!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_bad_7">
        <text>Okay, just try not to push yourself too much while I’m gone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_0">
        <text>Beast, what the hell WAS that?! What’s going on?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_1">
        <text>I… don’t know. I can’t quite think straight right now… but that monster’s going to be back here any second.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_2">
        <text>It laughed again! God, it’s so… discordant. I think it saw us, though. We’ve gotta hurry!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_3">
        <text>Yeah. We can’t waste any time finding a way out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_4">
        <text>Urgh… Beast, I’m not feeling too good right now. Can you look for the exit while I cover this area? I just… need to sit down and get my shit together.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_5">
        <text>All right. Take it easy, Markus. I’ll find it myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_6">
        <text>Okay. Look around for an exit or any valuables, including stuff we can use. Remember: we don’t have a lot of time, so act fast!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="digst_markus_talk_to_actor_good_7">
        <text>You got it. I’ll find it in no time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_0">
        <text>Hey, Knucklehead, how are you feeling?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_1">
        <text>Not the best. Feels like the morning after I found that bottle of bacardi, a few months back… Wait. What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_10">
        <text>Unfortunately, I have two doses of medicine left but three patients to treat. I figured I may as well give one dose to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_11">
        <text>Beast, no. Don’t give it to me. Those two have their whole lives ahead of them… I’ve already lived mine. Please. Let them enjoy their youth.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_12">
        <text>I could try to find some more. We still have time left before it gets fatal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_13">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. It means a lot to me. But… we may as well say our goodbyes here in case you don’t make it back in time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_14">
        <text>No. I can’t… It’s too early for that! Trust me. I can do this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_2">
        <text>I’ve found some more of that medicine, but it’s not enough for a full dose.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_3">
        <text>Sorry, Knucklehead, but I’ve already given it to someone else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_4">
        <text>We’ve both got more important things to do right now. Let’s talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_5">
        <text>Beast, don’t worry too much about it. If this is my fate… At least I get to die here with you. You can’t blame yourself for it; it’s just out of your hands.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_6">
        <text>I’ll find it; have some faith. Just don’t push yourself too much. Relax.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_7">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. Thank you for everything. But… I think we should say our final goodbyes here. Just in case you don’t make it back in time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_8">
        <text>No. Don’t say that. There’s still time left. I’ll find it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_dubolom_medicament_9">
        <text>Oh, that’s wonderful! There’s enough for everyone, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_0">
        <text>How are you feeling, Markus?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_1">
        <text>I wish I could make a joke, but the pain’s hitting me so hard, I can’t even think of one. I feel like I could die any minute… Did you bring back any of that special medicine?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_2">
        <text>Yeah. I’ve got some. I hope it helps.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_3">
        <text>We’ve both got stuff to do right now. Let’s talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_4">
        <text>Well, at least I have a fighting chance now. I hope we didn’t wait too long…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_5">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_6">
        <text>Thank you so much, Beast. This means a lot to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_markus_medicament_7">
        <text>I wish I could do more to help, but I still feel like I’m gonna croak any minute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_0">
        <text>How are you feeling, Cutter?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_1">
        <text>Not too good… What’s up, though?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_2">
        <text>I’ve got some medicine that should help you feel better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_3">
        <text>Uh… Nevermind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_4">
        <text>Oh, Jesus, that’s music to my ears. How much?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_5">
        <text>Only two doses. I’m giving one of them to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_6">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. Maybe I can finally feel my hands again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_actor_give_rezak_medicament_7">
        <text>We’re all rooting for you, man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_10">
        <text>There’s not a lot of choices around here. There aren’t exactly grocery stores at every corner. There are boars at every corner, though. They’re similar to normal boars, so I suggest hunting a couple of them and taking some nice juicy cuts of meat. I would also suggest cooking it at a campfire, as it kills the bacteria in it and gets rid of some radiation. I doubt you’d want to eat raw, unseasoned meat, anyway.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_11">
        <text>What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_12">
        <text>Well, there’s nothing we can really do about that. Is there anything else you wanted to tell me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_13">
        <text>Supplies are running low, and Savage said you’d be able to help me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_14">
        <text>Well, we’re actually fresh out of food. We’ve had to resort to eating the local wildlife again. Boars and pseudodogs are kind of abundant around here, and they taste pretty good if you cook ’em up right. One of the other guys brought a container of adobo, the one with pepper in it… Makes me drool just thinking about it. They’re not the healthiest, though. The radiation gets to you after a while if you don’t drink alcohol with it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_15">
        <text>It’s just like when I used to go camping with my family, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_16">
        <text>So how do I prepare the meat properly? So that I kill the bacteria and all that, I mean.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_17">
        <text>Well, it’s hard to describe. I’m sure you’ll learn better hands-on, so try roasting a piece and bring it here. I’ll check it out myself and tell you what you did wrong, if you didn’t do it properly. Also, keep some of the boar fat. It’s one of the tastiest parts from the animal, and some people around here use it in place of oil for gun maintenance. It’s useful stuff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_18">
        <text>Okay. You got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_2">
        <text>Wait a second… You’re that mercenary, right? The one that helped me hunt down that psy-dog?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_20">
        <text>You got the meat yet, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_21">
        <text>Yup. I’m kind of proud of this one, actually.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_22">
        <text>Uh… Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_23">
        <text>Hmm… Whoa. Holy shit. You did it perfectly. The sear lines are perfect, the meat isn’t pink on the inside, and the geiger counter isn’t even crackling. Maybe you should have become a chef instead of a mercenary.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_24">
        <text>Heh. Thanks. Cooking’s always been one of my hobbies. So this meat’s perfectly safe to eat, then?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_25">
        <text>Yeah. Love the way you seasoned it too… but more importantly, you’ve gotten all the radiation out somehow. How’d you do that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_26">
        <text>Some advanced basting technique I picked up during high school. I used vodka, since you said strong alcohol helps neutralize it. I’ll show you guys later. Right now, I’ve gotta go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_28">
        <text>You need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_3">
        <text>Yup. Small world, huh?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_30">
        <text>Uh, do you need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_4">
        <text>Yeah. I agree. You guys sure caused some mayhem back there. My lips are sealed, though, so don’t worry about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_5">
        <text>Mayhem is just a part of the job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_6">
        <text>You sure seem good at your job, then. Well, anyways, I’ve got some stuff to do right now. I’ll talk to you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_7">
        <text>Hey.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_meet_after_dialog_9">
        <text>Did you need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_0">
        <text>I’m all ready for that hunt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_1">
        <text>Excellent. We can finally move out. The chimera should be hanging around that old bunker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_2">
        <text>Chimeras are nocturnal, so you should know that you’re here way too early. Come back around two in the morning, and we’ll check if it’s there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_3">
        <text>Let’s go, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_is_time_4">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_10">
        <text>Okay. That’s all I needed to know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_11">
        <text>The chimera’s only there at night, so we may as well just go now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_12">
        <text>All right. The chimera tends to be there around two a.m., so come back here around that time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_13">
        <text>Hey, Beast. What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_14">
        <text>Let’s get going, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_15">
        <text>Shit. Okay. I’ll be back here around that time, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_17">
        <text>God, what a relief. We can finally stop worrying about that thing sneaking into our base. Thanks for the help, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_18">
        <text>Another dead mutant is good for all of us. You can be sure I’ll be sleeping easier tonight too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_19">
        <text>Yeah. By the way, I bet you’ve noticed that our food sources are running out fast. I’ve been trying something new lately, though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_2">
        <text>Hey, Beast. I heard you found Scavenger. Sucks that he was such a piece of shit, but at least that’s over with. Anyway, I needed to talk to you about something important.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_20">
        <text>I’d love to know about a new food source.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_21">
        <text>I lived out in the sticks as a kid, so my parents used to hunt for food sometimes. That’s why my aim is so good, but the important thing is that I’ve been hunting the local wildlife. It seemed like a waste to kill some of these animals and just let them rot, so I’ve been skinning and field dressing the boars and pseudodogs. If you cook the meat the right way, you can get rid of the bacteria and some of the radiation.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_22">
        <text>Nothing wrong with that. I’d say it’s not exactly gourmet, but, well, that depends on the chef. I will admit, I’ve tried some cooked boar before and it was pretty good.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_23">
        <text>I had a feeling you’d get me, Beast. I’ve been trying the dog meat lately, it’s a little bit more tender. It gets rubbery if you overcook it, though. While we’re on the topic, do you mind hunting some boars for me? I’m pretty hungry right now, and one of the other guys brought some barbecue sauce that would accent the boar chops really well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_24">
        <text>Yeah, sure. I was getting hungry anyways.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_25">
        <text>You mind bringing me a piece as well? All this hunting’s got me feeling pretty hungry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_26">
        <text>Sure thing, Knucklehead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_28">
        <text>You bring some of those cuts of boar meat yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_29">
        <text>Yeah. Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_3">
        <text>I’m all ears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_30">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_31">
        <text>Whoa! You cooked it perfectly! We got a real gourmand over here, using that fancy vodka sauce technique. But enough of the banter; thanks, Beast. This tastes better than the food back at home!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_32">
        <text>He he. Thanks. Cooking’s a hidden passion of mine. Good to know we’ve got a replenishable food supply out here too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_33">
        <text>Oh, uh, Markus told me to tell you to see him whenever you can. It was about something important.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_34">
        <text>All right. I’ll go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_36">
        <text>Hey, Beast. What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_37">
        <text>By the way, before I forget: Markus said he wants to talk to you about something. Go see him once you’ve got some free time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_38">
        <text>Okay. Thanks for the heads-up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_4">
        <text>Well, we’ve got a serious problem on our hands. Last night, I saw a chimera close to our base; maybe a hundred feet. I was coming back from hunting for dinner, so I was carrying a lot and I didn’t have that much ammo left to deal with it myself. But anyways, if I tell you where I spotted it, can you deal with it? I would rather not have one of the most dangerous mutants in the Zone wandering into our camp in the middle of the night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_5">
        <text>Hmm… Okay. But hunting a chimera requires a different strategy from normal mutants. Do you have any suggestions for how I should do it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_6">
        <text>I think we should wait until it goes to sleep. After a long night of hunting, it should pass right out, and if it wakes up, it’ll be groggy. Besides, two guys can handle one sleeping beast, I should think.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_7">
        <text>I dunno. It would be good to have backup in case it’s stronger than expected. The more the merrier, after all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_dubolom_night_hunting_start_8">
        <text>We’re the only people with enough ammo, I think. The other guys used most of theirs after a boar herd tried coming in through the main entrance. But we’re enough, I think. It’s going to be sleeping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_0">
        <text>About your gun…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_1">
        <text>So, did you find it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_2">
        <text>Yeah. Here it is. That bloodsucker was still hanging around that area; gave me a nasty shock.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_3">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_4">
        <text>N-nah, man… I just, uh… ran out of ammo. I’m not keen on f-fighting a bloodsucker with just my boot knife, after all. Haha…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_5">
        <text>Uh, okay. I mean, bloodsuckers are horrifying. You don’t have to puff out your chest and all that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_6">
        <text>Well, if you say so… but thank you. I can finally go on raids again. Here’s your reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_give_weapon_7">
        <text>It’s no big deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_0">
        <text>So, where did you lose your gun? Can you at least give me a general area?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_1">
        <text>I can tell you its exact location, actually.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_2">
        <text>So, what’s the problem, then?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_3">
        <text>I didn’t… lose… it. It jammed, but with a barrel blockage that would have destroyed the gun if I didn’t clear it. It’s pretty hard to pull out your ramrod and clear it when a bloodsucker’s got it’s eyes on you, though, so I threw it at him and ran. The only thing I have left is this tiny PM, and taking one of those things on with it is suicide. Do you think you could get it back for me, please?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_quest_weapon_4">
        <text>Murphy’s law, huh? I’ll handle it for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Halt. Stow your weapons, keep your hands in clear sight, and state your name, faction, and reason for coming here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_1">
        <text>Take it easy, lieutenant. I’m a mercenary—callsign Beast—sent here to help you reactivate your transformer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hmm… How did you open the cage door?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Someone helped me open it. What about you, though? How long have you been stuck here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Oh, okay. I’m not really sure if I’m allowed to tell you about that. Go talk to the general, he’ll sort out what to tell you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_bunchuk_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_0">
        <text>Stalker… Please… Give me some water. I haven’t drank water for almost a week… I won’t last long without your help…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_1">
        <text>Okay, just hold on!… Wait, what the fuck? I can’t walk up to you? It’s like I’m being teleported backwards…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_2">
        <text>It might be an anomaly… I’m not sure myself. I was in here with some of my squad members as we went on a routine artifact hunting trip, and… we just got stuck here. Major Chepurny couldn’t handle being trapped in here for so long, he just… lost it. Shot Zakharchuk and Bunchuk and then himself. And then Kosmach died of dehydration. My PDA died a few hours ago, so I thought I was done for.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_3">
        <text>Jesus Christ… That’s brutal. Wait, how did all of this happen so quickly? Didn’t you just send me a message?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_4">
        <text>It’s been roughly a week since I sent you that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_5">
        <text>A whole week?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_6">
        <text>Yeah… My vision’s starting to blur. I think I’m… gonna pass out soon. Please, try to find a way to help me…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_final_dialog_7">
        <text>I’ll try. Just hang in there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_11">
        <text>Well, hello there, stalker. This might sound weird, but do you have any extra food you could spare?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_12">
        <text>Uh, no. I would kill for some real food, to be honest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_13">
        <text>Yeah, I thought so… Well, listen: we were on an artifact hunting trip before we ended up here. We ended up finding some good stuff, but it’s not like we have any traders to sell them to here. Unfortunately, we didn’t find any that help eliminate radiation, so we can’t actually use them ourselves. We really need some good food though, so if you find any canned or fresh goods, we’ll give you the artifacts we found in exchange. We need around eight pieces of food. Deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_14">
        <text>Sounds good to me. I’ll see what I can find.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_15">
        <text>I’m a little bit busy right now, ask me again later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_17">
        <text>So are you gonna help us or what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_19">
        <text>So, got anything good?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey, stalker! What the hell is going on in here? Where are we?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_20">
        <text>Here you go. It was *not* easy finding this stuff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_21">
        <text>Yeah, I’ll bet it wasn’t. Here’s your reward, you can make some pretty good profit off them once we finally get out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_22">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_23">
        <text>Wonderful. Thank you. I’m sure we’ll find a way out somehow.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_24">
        <text>Oh, wait! Hold on, can you do us another favor?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_25">
        <text>Sure.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_26">
        <text>One of our guys, Tug, dropped his gun near the bunker. Do you think you could find it for him? He ought to know where he left it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_27">
        <text>Okay. I’ll go ask him for the details.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_29">
        <text>Hey, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_3">
        <text>I’d love to know that myself. Looks like we’re trapped in some sort of anomaly… do you remember how you got here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_4">
        <text>We were walking through the Agroprom, looking for some artifacts. We saw a bright light, and then I guess we must’ve passed out since we woke up here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Hmm… It seems like some kind of… spatial anomaly. The Zone must be warping space-time? Well, the other stalker group must know more about it than us. They’ve been here for almost two months now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Another gift from the Zone…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Okay, well, I’ve gotta go find a way to turn the electricity back on around here. I’ll talk to you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_duty_tachenko_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Hey, merc.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_0">
        <text>Finally starting to see how grave your situation is, are we? I’m only gonna ask you one more fucking time: where is the compass?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_1">
        <text>You fucking know me. I don’t lie, especially not about things like this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_2">
        <text>People change. You were unpredictable before your time in that anomaly, so who knows how crazy you are now. I told you I was only going to ask one more time, though, and Obscurant said to take you outside if you didn’t want to be cooperative.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_agres_3">
        <text>Wait! No-no! Hold on! Hold on!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_0">
        <text>Good morning, dickhead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_1">
        <text>Where… the fuck am I?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_10">
        <text>Oh, that’s convenient. You really think they would risk getting “accidentally” killed and someone looting their special new artifact? Think with your goddamn brain on for just a second; really think about the consequences of lying to us. We won’t hesitate to splatter your tiny brain all across this room. Give us the location of the Compass, or you’ll pay for it with your life.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_11">
        <text>I don’t have any fucking Compass, okay?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_2">
        <text>I came here to check up on you. Jackal was beginning to worry where you’d gone off to.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_3">
        <text>Wait, you willingly came in here? Do you even know what you just got yourself into?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_4">
        <text>Oh, yes. This place is pretty nice, I’ve gotta say. We might stay a while. But if we don’t, we’ve always got this handy scanner to lead us right out. Oh, before I forget, I’ll nab yours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_5">
        <text>Why the hell did you even come here? To save me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_6">
        <text>You think too highly of yourself, Beast. Think: why would we save you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_7">
        <text>Jesus Christ. If I knew, I wouldn’t be playing games with a piece of shit like you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_8">
        <text>This place—the spatial anomaly—is very rare. It’s unlike any other anomaly in the Zone. Space-time is warped and bent in ways humans a million years from now aren’t going to be able to understand. And it creates an artifact that makes even less sense; the Compass. Looks like a blueberry the size of your fist with white rebar sticking out of it like a mace head. You’ve got it, and you’re going to give it to us, or we’ll stick a grenade in your mouth and rip out the pin.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_killer_leader_group_meet_9">
        <text>I don’t. I’ve never heard of a Compass, or this place. None of the other stalkers have either, because they would be talking about a special new type of artifact nonstop. You’ve got the wrong person.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_0">
        <text>Hey, uh, you need any help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_1">
        <text>Yes, holy shit, yes. We need fuel for our generators or we won’t have electricity for our base. We’ll be putting up our PDAs like floodlights to spot mutants if we can’t get any. We’ll give you some supplies, medkits, whatever you want. You can take your pick, we don’t really care. Just get us that fuel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_2">
        <text>Uh, you got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_3">
        <text>I’ll try later. I’ve got some important stuff to handle right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_4">
        <text>Our jerry cans are almost empty, and we really need fuel in order to keep the generators going. We won’t have any light, the food in our storage fridges will spoil, and we won’t be able to charge our PDAs or use our loudspeaker systems. It’ll be bad news, and we’ll give you some good stuff in exchange for some gas.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_5">
        <text>Sounds pretty serious. I’ll keep an eye out for any gas while I’m out there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_6">
        <text>I’m really busy right now. Maybe later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_from_work_7">
        <text>I don’t really need anything right now, but thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_10">
        <text>If you can make befriend a Dutyer, you can probably befriend anyone in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_11">
        <text>Snake’s a good guy, and places like this force you to work together with whoever’s around. Faction wars don’t matter when there’s nothing to earn.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_13">
        <text>Hey, merc. I’m listening…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_15">
        <text>Did you find the fuel yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_16">
        <text>Yup, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_17">
        <text>Not yet. Fuel is a little bit hard to find around these parts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_18">
        <text>Best news I’ve heard all week. I can finally stop worrying about strapping our PDAs to our fortifications just to see monsters. How much did you bring?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_19">
        <text>Enough, I should think. Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_2">
        <text>Focus on the zombies. We’ll talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_20">
        <text>Whew, thanks. That’s more than enough. You saved us big time. Here’s your reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_21">
        <text>No need to thank me. We’re all helping each other out here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_23">
        <text>I’m listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_24">
        <text>All right. See ya.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_3">
        <text>Okay. I’ll be on my way, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_5">
        <text>Go get some sleep or something. I’m not really in the mood to talk.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_7">
        <text>Hello. Let me introduce myself: the others call me Sledgehammer. I was a high-ranking member of Freedom before I got stuck here, and have since decided to switch factions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_8">
        <text>Ah. Well, my name is Beast, but I assume you already know that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_kuvalda_dialog_start_9">
        <text>Yes. I’m not going to lie, I’m not exactly enthusiastic about you being here despite my faction change. People like you used to kill my friends.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_0">
        <text>Where the hell were you, man? I’ve been waiting for you too damn long!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_1">
        <text>Uh, I had stuff to take care of. Where are the others?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_2">
        <text>They left early, said they’d meet you there. I stayed behind to fill you in. Where are those Duty members you told us about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_3">
        <text>Something happened. They, uh… died. Where are we headed?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_4">
        <text>Shit. Rest in peace. We don’t know where the exit’s going to drop us; this is pretty unpredictable stuff here. We could die instantly or get put right into the northern Klondike. Are you ready to leave?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_5">
        <text>As ready as ever.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_6">
        <text>Just as a heads-up: people tend to pass out when they leave these things. I haven’t myself, but you might. Also, you have to keep moving. Don’t stop or it’ll literally tear you apart. Follow my path exactly and everything should be fine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_end_line_meet_7">
        <text>Jesus Christ. I guess I won’t mess around, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_0">
        <text>Thank you, young’un. I’m getting too old for this shit… but more importantly, wildlife in the Zone has been going absolutely crazy. It’s like they’ve got sensory overload but for every sense at the same time. Be careful when you’re out there, keep your aim steady as they like to jump and zig zag.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_1">
        <text>Don’t mention it. Who are you, by the way?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_2">
        <text>I’m the Forester. I used to be the local park ranger and forester of the Red Forest, back before the Chernobyl reactor meltdown. The forest called to me; guaranteed my safety in exchange for my continued watch over it. I know it like the back of my hand, and I often rescue people trapped or stuck there. My radio caught a strange distress signal, so I came out here to save you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_3">
        <text>Oh, thank God. How do we get out of here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_4">
        <text>By using a special artifact known only as the Compass. I found it while I was stuck in one of these myself, and it felt like the forest gave me a way out. Its barbs resonate a certain way as you approach the exit of these special anomalies, and I’m very attuned to it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_5">
        <text>Wait, I’m not the only person stuck here! There’s a base full of stalkers nearby, and a small squad of Duty members stuck underground. Can we save them too, please?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_6">
        <text>Of course. Show me the way to the base so I can explain this to them as well.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lesnik_first_meet_start_7">
        <text>Sure. Follow me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_10">
        <text>All right. Enough about that. We’ve gotta bury the bodies from the bunker and pay our respects to Sledgehammer after everything he’s done for us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_11">
        <text>Yeah. Let’s get going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_13">
        <text>Hey, Beast! Who’d you bring this time?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_14">
        <text>This is Forester. He’s going to guide us out of this anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_15">
        <text>Holy shit! We’re saved! But I just got another distress signal; I don’t think we should leave without them. Can you investigate it for us while we get ready to leave?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_16">
        <text>Another one? I guess so. Send me the coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_17">
        <text>It’s around the same place you were before. It sounds strange, like it’s being warped.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_18">
        <text>Their PDA’s probably just damaged. I’ll be right on it, but this Forester guy is pretty cool. He’s been here since the original reactor meltdown, and he’s still alive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_19">
        <text>Holy shit, man! That’s ridiculous! And this special artifact he’s got… We really are saved, huh?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_2">
        <text>Excellent work, Beast! How did everything go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_20">
        <text>Yeah, he’ll explain it. Right now, I’ve gotta check out that distress signal, though. Later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_22">
        <text>Uh, go get that last guy from the signal location. We’ve got stuff to do back here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_24">
        <text>Hey, Beast, did you find any medicine? Those two guys aren’t going to last very long without it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_25">
        <text>Yeah, but only one dose. I’m sorry, man…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_26">
        <text>The important thing right now is not to give up. Right now, more than ever, we have to keep fighting. I just… I could never choose who gets to live and who gets to die. You pick, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_27">
        <text>Urf, that’s quite a tough decision… but I guess I’ll do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_28">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. Having to choose between Knucklehead, Markus, and Cutter would destroy me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_29">
        <text>It weighs pretty heavy on all of us… but anyways, I’ve gotta go. I’ll see you later, man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_3">
        <text>Well, when I was in the underground tunnels, I found a squad of Duty members. Five guys. Not a whole lot of supplies left.</text>
    </string>
 <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_31">
        <text>Did you give them the medicine yet?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_32">
        <text>Not quite yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_34">
        <text>You’ve been gone for almost a week, man. Where the hell were you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_35">
        <text>I’ve been looking for a cure the whole time. I even slept in the barn just in case I found more survivors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_36">
        <text>Well… While you were gone, Knucklehead died. We paid our respects and buried him last night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_37">
        <text>And I never even told him goodbye…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_38">
        <text>Nobody did… He died in his sleep unexpectedly. Markus and Cutter have been doing a little bit better, though. I think it’s working. Oh, before I forget, Knucklehead left this in his bag for you. We found a note next to it that said, “For Beast—just in case.” when we went through his stuff. I cried a little bit reading it, to be honest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_39">
        <text>Nothing wrong with that. I might myself, honestly. We all cope in our own ways.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_4">
        <text>Jesus Christ… Do you know how long they’ve been down there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_40">
        <text>Yeah, true… Thanks for everything, Beast. You always work so hard for us. You should go get some rest after all that searching.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_41">
        <text>Yeah. See you around, Savage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_5">
        <text>No. They only got there pretty recently.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_6">
        <text>Did you tell them about us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_7">
        <text>I did, but they weren’t very interested in joining us. I think they want to work alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_8">
        <text>Ah. That’s fine, I guess. As long as they don’t start trouble. We should let them know they can come here if they run out of supplies.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_after_quest_9">
        <text>I’ll try to text them on my PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_0">
        <text>Hey, Beast, did you find Screw?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_1">
        <text>Yeah. Everything’s all right. There were a bunch of mercenaries in the barn; I had to kill them. They went crazy. I got Screw out safe, though; he’s with me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_2">
        <text>Sucks that Dagger got away. I think they already got out of the anomaly. We’re gonna track that motherfucker down and make him pay for what happened to Sledgehammer, though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_3">
        <text>Yeah. He got my scanner too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_4">
        <text>Hmm… God, that sucks! Nothing you could really do about that one, though. On another note, now that we have access to the bunker, we’ve been thinking about moving into it. What did you think?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_5">
        <text>Yeah, this place is much better than that old barn. We should definitely do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_6">
        <text>Glad we’re all on the same page. By the way, those mercenaries from earlier tried to escape. They almost got away, but we cleaned them up right at the end. Had to kill them once they tried to grab our knives out of the sheath with their teeth. Some real crazy motherfuckers.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_7">
        <text>Fucking hell… Oh, did you hear that Markus found the key to that storage room? He said there was a lot of ammo in there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_8">
        <text>Yeah, that’s like music to my ears. We have something more important to talk about, though; the power’s not working properly. Cutter found some blueprints of this place while he was examining some of the wires that connect to the light system; Screw said you must have blown out one of the transformers underground when you turned the power off at the barn. I guess they shared the same transformer. You know how these old Soviet designs are.\n \nAnyways, Screw said he found a service entrance that connects to the underground; it’s for servicing the transformers. Lucky, huh? Anyways, I need you to go down there and find a way to fix it. You think you can do that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_lutiy_scene_final_base_meet_9">
        <text>Sure. I’ll get right on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_0">
        <text>What the hell happened, Markus?! Did you ice those guys?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_1">
        <text>No, no! It was that Stronglav thing. It made them kill themselves…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_2">
        <text>Fuck, man. We’re lucky to be alive. We have to free the other guys and get out of here. I think I have a plan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_3">
        <text>What were you thinking?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_4">
        <text>The mercenaries captured a few of our guys, and they’re holding them in the barn. If we free them, they can turn on the mercenaries, and we’ll outnumber them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_5">
        <text>Sounds good to me. Wait, how did you get out of that cave?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_6">
        <text>I followed you and just kept moving. Listen: we’ve got to focus, we don’t have a lot of time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_7">
        <text>Yeah, that’s true. Let’s get going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_2">
        <text>All right, this place is an old army weapon stockpile. It should have plenty of firepower. I just don’t know how long these weapons have been stored here. Let’s hope they all work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_3">
        <text>How are you gonna open that door?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_4">
        <text>Stronglav’s lair had a few things lying around in one of the other chambers; it must have been scraps its victims left. Go ahead and take whatever you need. I’ll wait out here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_5">
        <text>Sounds good to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_7">
        <text>Get a move on, Beast. I don’t wait to wait out here alone for too long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_end_8">
        <text>All right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_0">
        <text>You ready?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_1">
        <text>Yeah.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_2">
        <text>Okay, so, most of the mercs are at the bunker. There’s a small squad still at the barn watching Screw; they have him as a hostage. We’ve gotta save him. I think the best option we have right now is to cut the power to the barn and kill them in the darkness, since they don’t have night vision goggles. But, there’s another variable at play here that you have to lock down, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_3">
        <text>That’s a pretty solid plan. What do you need me to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_4">
        <text>Well, it’s not something you can do right now. But these are Syndicate guys; they have direct ties to your old employers. If you kill them, you have to make sure none of them survive, or you’ll never be able to work for the Syndicate again. But more importantly, they’ll send out warnings to the other members and your reputation among them will be ruined. Finally, there’s a chance you could run into an old squad member of friend among them. You’ll have to be pretty good at convincing them or not hesitate killing them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_5">
        <text>I didn’t make friends in the Syndicate. Those guys are cold-blooded killers. I could never value a relationship with people like that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_6">
        <text>Hmm, that’s true… but I’ll have to do what must be done. I have a silver tongue, after all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_7">
        <text>That’s true. There’s a reason the other factions hate those mercenaries after all. Well, we’d better get going. I’ll go help the rest, you tackle that barn problem.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_8">
        <text>You sure do. Now, let’s head out. I’ll handle the others and you get Screw back from the barn.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_alive_talk_to_actor_final_9">
        <text>You got it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_10">
        <text>When you’re ready, talk to Snake. He’ll text you the coordinates on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_11">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_13">
        <text>Beast, let’s focus on these mutants.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_15">
        <text>Hey, Beast, I’ve noticed you’re quite the detective. Your work with the chimera and Scavenger was top-notch.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_16">
        <text>Haha, thank you. The chimera hunt was easier than Knucklehead let on, but, you know, gotta puff out your chest once in a while.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_17">
        <text>Ah, haha… yeah. But anyways, we need your help. Before Savage, we had a leader whose callsign was Shell. He disappeared about a month ago, and we looked for him for a long ass time. However, I caught him as a contact on my PDA a few days ago for like, literally a split second. It was near that old abandoned basement, and I looked everywhere for him, but there wasn’t a single trace of him there. I kind of have an idea what he might’ve been doing, though…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_18">
        <text>What were you thinking?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_19">
        <text>Maybe he was using specialized teleport locations inside this place like how Scavenger was, but got stuck. It would explain how he was close to me but only for a fraction of a second.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey, this is important shit! Those zombies are closing in! Kill ’em and we’ll talk afterwards!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_20">
        <text>Hmm… And you think he’s just been chilling ever since?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_21">
        <text>Maybe. He was the toughest guy we had, with top notch equipment. One of those fancy fourth-generation exoskeletons and a big PKM on his back. He had plenty of supplies with him on the trip he disappeared on, too. Shell had a silver tongue and a knack for getting people to put their differences aside and work on the task at hand. He helped us found our group, an impressive feat considering most of us were from opposing factions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_22">
        <text>Well, it seems like if anyone were to go missing, he’d be the most likely to survive. I’ll keep an eye out for him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_24">
        <text>Hey, dude! My name’s Markus, and we’re really glad you helped us out. We haven’t met yet, but it sure is nice to finally see you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_25">
        <text>It was no big deal. The people around here call me Beast. It’s my old callsign.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_26">
        <text>Well, you sure seem like a beast. This place we’re stuck in… It’s gotta be one of those spatial anomalies the scientists have been real interested in lately. They say there’s always supposed to be a way out of them, s’ we should be good. Anyways, if you’re not too busy right now, do you think you could help me with something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_27">
        <text>Uh, sure. What did you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_28">
        <text>Sorry, ask me later. I’ve got a lot on my plate right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_29">
        <text>Well, we’re all out of those special anti-radiation drugs. I was wondering if you could try to find an artifact called a Wrenched. It cleanses radiation from nearby areas, so it would be a pretty good alternative to those drugs. It comes from gravitational anomalies, which there are a lot of nearby. I’m almost out of ammo, though, so I don’t want to tempt fate. I have another artifact here I found before I got stuck in this place I can give to you as a reward, if you want. In case you find two? Or maybe a better radiation cleansing artifact. I don’t really need any fancy ones like a Bubble or Moonlight; the Wrenched should be good enough for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_30">
        <text>All right. I’ll go look for one.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_32">
        <text>Hey, Beast. You still busy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_33">
        <text>Not any more. What did you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_34">
        <text>Yup.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_36">
        <text>So, how’s the artifact hunting been?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_37">
        <text>I found it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_38">
        <text>I haven’t found one yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_39">
        <text>Whew, that’s a relief. I was starting to think I was just gonna have to hit the vodka every time the Geiger counter started crackling. Thanks, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Me and a few of the other guys were gonna go looking for some food later. You wanna come?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_40">
        <text>It’s cool.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_41">
        <text>Here’s your reward, by the way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_42">
        <text>Whoa, sick! Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_44">
        <text>Hey, Beast! Any news?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_46">
        <text>Hey, dude. You get any leads on where Shell’s been?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_47">
        <text>Yeah, I followed them right to him. He was zombified, though. Sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_48">
        <text>Not quite yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_49">
        <text>God… If only he had brought someone else with him. Did he have anything special on him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_5">
        <text>So, what did you need me for again?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_50">
        <text>That big machine gun you were telling me about, some spoiled food, and a dogtag he kept in a hidden part of his backpack.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_51">
        <text>Ah, god damn it. That was his old faction tag he kept as a reminder that our past ties didn’t matter now that we were here. I’ll take that. We’ll keep it as a memento of him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_52">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_53">
        <text>Yup. That’s it, all right… Thank you for your help, Beast. This means a lot to us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_54">
        <text>I try to help out whenever I can. Don’t be afraid to ask for help again if you need it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_56">
        <text>Hey, dude. What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Well, Cutter told me you saw a herd of flesh nearby. Since we’re out of food, I thought we might hunt them and cook them. They’re just mutated pigs, after all. You want in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_60">
        <text>All right. We’ll talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_7">
        <text>All right. We’ll talk later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_8">
        <text>Snake and Sledgehammer are going with you. I’ve gotta go handle something else, but I’ll meet up with you in time for the hunt. Make sure they don’t kill each other in the meantime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_markus_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Okay. Just make sure you text me the coordinates before you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_10">
        <text>Oh, right. Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_11">
        <text>So, Beast, have you found that special SVD ammo I told you about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_12">
        <text>Yup. 7.62x54 7N14. Sniper cartridges with a boat-tail for increased accuracy and material penetration. Here they are.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_13">
        <text>No. Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_14">
        <text>Whoa! Jesus Christ! These are special-made rounds the army reserves for important missions. Thanks, man! Where the hell did you even find these?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_15">
        <text>That’s not really important, but I had a feeling you’d like them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_16">
        <text>More than like… But anyways, here’s your reward. Thanks for your help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_17">
        <text>Ha ha. Just doing my part. I’ve gotta go catch up with someone else right now, though. I’ll see you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_19">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Did you need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Yo, Beast, thank you for clearing out those zombies. But, uh, are you busy right now? I kind of need your help with something.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_4">
        <text>I’m free right now. What’s the situation?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Managed to clear your schedule yet, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Yup. What needs doin’?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Well, I found an SVD while I was scavenging around earlier. I’ve got it stashed away, but it’s unloaded. It didn’t have any ammo with it when I found it either, and I’ve been looking around with no luck. If you find any, do you think you could give it to me? I’ll trade you some 5.45 ammo for it and make it worth your while.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_8">
        <text>I’m a little busy right now, but I’ll keep an eye out for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_moskit_start_dialog_9">
        <text>Sorry. I’m too busy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_0">
        <text>Well, look who it is! What the fuck are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_1">
        <text>I could say the same god damn thing to you. Do you even know where you are? Do you know just how much you’ve fucked up by coming here? And do you know how hard I’m going to paint these walls with your gray matter if you don’t get the fuck out of my way?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_2">
        <text>Whoa ho ho! Someone’s acting tough, saying all this hard shit. You don’t scare me with your shitty threats, vague or otherwise, punk. Oh, and before I forget, the Syndicate says hello.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_mrakobes_talk_3">
        <text>I’m gonna… rip… y-your…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_0">
        <text>Thanks for saving my ass as usual. Are these guys really here just for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_1">
        <text>No. They’re here for some special artifact called the Compass. This place is an anomaly, and like normal anomalies, it can make artifacts. Because of how hard they are to find, they’re extremely valuable, and the syndicate’s going to try to use it to blackmail the ecologists into doing whatever they want. But more importantly, those motherfuckers killed Sledgehammer. We’ve gotta get out of here and make sure they pay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_2">
        <text>Fuck this, man… Wait, where’s Markus?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_3">
        <text>He’s setting up for a plan to free the other guys from the rest of the mercenaries.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_4">
        <text>Hmm… you better go help him with that then. Those guys fucked up the tendons on one of my legs; cut it clean through. I’m gonna have to limp around if I can’t make some sort of cane or crutch or something. You go help Markus set that plan up and I’ll figure out what to do with my leg.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_prison_meet_5">
        <text>Shit, man. I should have made their deaths a little more painful then. You’re right, though; I’ll go see what Markus needs help with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_0">
        <text>Oh, you’re finally here. Did Savage fill you in on what you need to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_1">
        <text>Yeah.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_2">
        <text>Then let’s get started. I’ll open the door for you, but I’ve gotta go do something important afterwards, so I can’t go in with you. I’ll meet you back at the bunker, okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_door_talk_3">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_10">
        <text>They told me to find a battery for their radio, so I’ll see if they can use this. Let me see it, please?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_12">
        <text>Hey, did you need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_13">
        <text>You may as well deliver it to him yourself, then. I’m gonna stay here, catch my breath and chill. Then I’ll clear my head and figure out what to do next.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_14">
        <text>All right. I’m off, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_2">
        <text>T-thank you. I guess you really are just here to help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_3">
        <text>Yeah. Do you want me to help you with those mercenaries too? Can you tell me why they were here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_4">
        <text>The scientists gave me an assignment to try out a new experimental transceiver. A simple job: “Just test it out and see if you pick up anything.” I messed around with it and picked up a mercenary channel. They were having some serious, heavy negotiations. Stuff about deposing certain squad leaders, strongarming the Ecologists, shady contacts they can use, paths they were using to move weapons and men without the Syndicate knowing, etc. They even worked out a whole arms deal for some kind of special new “modular assault rifle,” right then and there! I heard every single word of it, didn’t make a sound or even move.\n \nJust as they were wrapping everything up, one of them realized their radio thing said it was a “conference call.” He thought about it for a few seconds; stunned, I guess. Then he realized it was supposed to be a solo call and cursed up a god damn storm. Sent just about every man he had to sweep the area, armed to the teeth. Ordered ’em to kill me on sight at any cost… Started quite a shitstorm over it, and two squads found me within minutes. I tried to sprint away and ended up in a narrow corridor with a clear-ish anomaly blocking the way and fifteen mercenaries in tow, just around the corner. I did some wall-kick shit I saw in a movie when I was a kid and thought I had cleared it, but I guess I didn’t. Now I’m here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_5">
        <text>Hmm… Do you still have the transceiver?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_6">
        <text>Yeah, but it’s busted. One of the mercenaries landed a shot; hit my backpack and grazed the love handles. Went straight through it, but the parts are still in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_7">
        <text>Are the parts salvagable?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_8">
        <text>I’ll take the battery, just in case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_end_dialog_9">
        <text>Uh, maybe? The only people who really know this thing well are the scientists who gave it to me. I think the microchips are toasted, but there’s a fancy battery in here that I could give you, if you really needed it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Stop! Stay right there and keep that gun holstered, or I’ll blast your head clean off. Tell me who you are, why you’re here, and how you found me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_1">
        <text>I’m Beast. I’m just here to help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_10">
        <text>Relax. Calm down or I’ll put you down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_11">
        <text>You fucking idiot! You and your dickhead mercenary friends are all dead!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_12">
        <text>Wait—</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Here to help my ass! You and the other mercs just want information I don’t have. I already told you guys I don’t know shit, so just leave me alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Other mercs? I’m the only mercenary in here. I’m alone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Uh huh. Wait… “In here”? Do you know what this place is?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Well, you sure are unlucky. This is a spatial anomaly. You’re stuck in here unless we can find an exit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Jesus Christ. I have to get out of here… Those mercenaries are gonna come back. Do you know the way out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_7">
        <text>Don’t panic. There’s a base nearby full of neutral stalkers. It’s a safe space; everyone drops their faction beef before they come in.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_8">
        <text>How far is it? Are they okay with me staying there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_murad_quest_start_dialog_9">
        <text>It’s not too far away. They’re fine with everyone staying there as long as you don’t start any trouble.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_0">
        <text>Mercenary, you are quite lucky to have survived that. Phantoms with trials often kill you if you fail. You must try your hardest to stay away from them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_1">
        <text>Phantasma?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_2">
        <text>Yes. These ghosts are extremely dangerous. Interacting with them is tempting fate.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_3">
        <text>What are they, physically?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_4">
        <text>What you saw here last night was a phantom. They don’t often have physical forms, but they can materialize and possess items. Even animals and humans if they are strong enough. They are the souls of dead people or animals; trapped here in the physical world. You can consider it a form of immortality. The Zone’s power is so strong that it even tampers with souls and the afterlife. These ghosts often appear at the site of their death or close to their remains, as that’s when their power is of’en the strongest. They normally aren’t dangerous, as the dead have no temptations, but the phantom you saw was made specifically to lure people into a trap…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_5">
        <text>The other guy must have… failed, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_6">
        <text>Fortune favors you, mercenary, but fate has its eye on you now. You must be vigilant and rely on your skills and intuition more than your luck.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_7">
        <text>H-how do you know all of this…?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_8">
        <text>I know many things. Heed my advice, as you are already in danger. Stay alert.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_otshelnik_puzir_talk_9">
        <text>What?! Hey, wait! Where are you going?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_0">
        <text>I… I can… do it… This th-iiing…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_1">
        <text>Hey, are you all right? What’s going on?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_10">
        <text>I can’t remember much… The Radar, scary. Scary place, so we took a shortcut through the Red F-Forest… Hole in one of the fences let us sneak past the Monolith patrols. First went Savage; next, good old Spotty; and finally, Hunchback, God bless him. Wait, wait, Hunch, can you get through?! Wait, can you…?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_11">
        <text>What?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_12">
        <text>I-I don’t… remember… The voice! The voice, it it it spoke to me! It got right in my head! A terrible voice spoke directly to my brain, saying stuff… Hot voice. Scorching all of my brain. Terrible… Terrible… Terrible! You cannot go there! A wild pain reminds me, sounds like that bastard at the bar… yYou can’t go there! I go where I want…! But you, you can’t. The wild pain will crush your skull and squeeze your b-brains out like lemonade…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_13">
        <text>All right, all right. I won’t. You’re safe here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_14">
        <text>Whispers, whispers, creak of swings… It’s in my head, over and over… the voice w-w-wants me to become… one of those… monsters! *I won’t!* I… can’t… please. Take this. B-before I… lose it… give it to Baldy. Make sure it… gets to my wife and my kids. My beautiful kids… Tell them I love them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_15">
        <text>I will. Rest easy, Spots.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_2">
        <text>I-I’m fiiiiine… I can hold it together… Right…?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_3">
        <text>Hey, can you hear me? Is everything okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_4">
        <text>No! NO! I won’t let it be with me!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_5">
        <text>Jesus Christ…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_6">
        <text>My skull! It’s being ripped out of my fucking head! Ahhh!… Sp-Spotty… That’s what… They called me. Spotty. Hunchback! HUNCHBACK! He died! The radiation finally got to him…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_7">
        <text>Hunchback? Who was that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_8">
        <text>A stalker… A friend. Savage, Hunchback, and good o-ol’ Spotty went near the Scorcher. Scientists told us about cert-aiiIIINNN!!… times… we could pass through… AH! SKULL! S-Skull…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_paskhalka_stalker_meet_9">
        <text>What did you do there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_10">
        <text>Wait, shit, shit! Right now, we’ve really gotta focus on clearing out those zombies. Do you have any rifle ammo?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_11">
        <text>Uh, yeah. Not a whole lot though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_12">
        <text>Please, just give us two mags. Mosquito’s a professional marksman, he’ll put it to good use.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_13">
        <text>Okay, okay. Here. Make it count.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_14">
        <text>All right, all right. Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_15">
        <text>Quick, we have to find Scavenger. We won’t last long here without him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_17">
        <text>Back from your nap, are you? I hope you’re feeling well-rested after four whole days of sleep. Well, maybe not, since that blowout looked like it fucked you up. But hey, you’re alive! That’s a good thing, probably. But your mercenary past clouds our judgement on you. Whose side are you on?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_18">
        <text>Yours now, I guess. My callsign used to be Beast, and I’m not really a mercenary any more. Where am I?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_19">
        <text>Ah, well, that’s fair. We’re all in this shit together now anyways. But personally, I don’t quite know how to answer your question. It’s some sort of anomaly that traps you here, from what we can tell. I’m Savage, and I’m with a small group of stalkers that have also gotten stuck here. The others probably aren’t going to be keen on letting you in, though, so try hard to make a good impression on them and don’t start any trouble, please. The other guys tend to react unpredictably when they think about the reality of the situation so be tactful. We all try to get along so we can make it out of here in one piece.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_2">
        <text>Hey, you! There’s a big wave of zombies headed straight for our base and our ammo stock is dwindling! Do you think you can help us out, please?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_20">
        <text>A new anomaly, huh? How long are we gonna be stuck here for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_21">
        <text>We don’t know. No matter where you go, you always end up back here at this fucking barn. We try to make ends meet around here, fighting malnutrition and mutants at the same time. We’ve spent a lot of amm’ fighting them off, but they just keep coming somehow.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_22">
        <text>Damn. Wait, how long have you been here? Did you take the stuff I had with me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_23">
        <text>The guy I originally came in here with has been with me for about seven months, according to our PDAs. The rest of ’em, no more than three months. Most of them sit at one. As for your equipment, we’re not quite sure. Around four days ago, one of our scouts was scavenging for supplies and found you conked out, spread out across a living room in one of the nearby houses. No backpack; just your ragged suit, with a pistol and some ammo in your pockets. Oh, and a medkit, but we needed that. Sorry.\n \nBut anyways, we can’t really make you follow orders, I guess. We’re not really a faction, just a bunch of guys trying to survive. But I think you know that real strength tends to lie in numbers, so you’ll probably last longer with us than without us. Speaking for everyone else in the group, though, mercenary past or not we’d love to have someone with your skillset with us. Just, uh, play things smart around here. Use your brain and try to make friends with the other guys if you can.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_24">
        <text>Sure. I may as well join up with you guys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_3">
        <text>Is nobody else around to help?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_4">
        <text>No, you’re the only other guy around here! One of our guys, Cutter, is out there. We need you to find him and bring him back alive. He’s a valuable asset to our group. Also, I noticed a few rifle mags in your suit. Are those 5.45?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_5">
        <text>Uh, yeah. Here, you can have them if you need them. Not like I have a rifle to use them with, anyways.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_6">
        <text>Damn this place… We’re running dangerously low on ammo and food. Usually, there’s a good influx of stalkers; they often die from anomalies or mutants and we live off whatever they had. But unfortunately, there haven’t been any new people here for almost two weeks, and on top of that, Scavenger’s gone! He’s our top scout and looter, and he always manages to bring back the good shit whenever he goes out. What are we gonna do…?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_7">
        <text>We’ll figure something out. Don’t worry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_8">
        <text>Can you tell me a little more about Scavenger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_start_9">
        <text>He’s, uh, normal build, brown hair and brown eyes. Around five foot six, and he’s got this big backpack with a bunch of guns strapped to it, usually looted off guys he finds. He up and left camp about two days ago and hasn’t returned since. Can you keep an eye out for him while you’re out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_1">
        <text>Yeah, I think so. The worst has come to pass; his wounds don’t look fatal any more. He should be able to move soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_10">
        <text>Beast, we need to find Scavenger. He was a vital part of our food economy and enabled us to survive here without relying on mutant meat. Do you think you could keep an eye out for him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_11">
        <text>Yeah, I guess so. Anyways, I’ll go check out the area, hopefully I’ll find a lead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_12">
        <text>Sure. I’ll go check out his last known location, maybe I’ll catch a trace of him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_13">
        <text>Thanks, man. It would mean a lot to us; Scavenger really managed to make a difference for us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_14">
        <text>Yeah, he sure seems important. I’ll text you on my PDA if I find anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_15">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. It means a lot to us; our two provisional looters can’t even scratch half of what he could find in a single day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_16">
        <text>That’s pretty impressive. But, anyways… I’ll text you on my PDA if I get any leads.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_17">
        <text>Oh, and before you leave, speak to Knucklehead. He was interested in looking for Scavenger too. Oh, and Snake wanted to see you about something important. When you’re done with all of that, come back. I had something else I wanted to talk to you about, but I’ve gotta confirm something first.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_19">
        <text>Jesus Christ… This was supposed to be our ticket out of here. It’s like this place doesn’t want us to leave!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_2">
        <text>Oh, thank God. I think this used to be some sort of military complex before the anomaly. We’ll have to ask that army dude for details.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_20">
        <text>All right. I’ll get on that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_22">
        <text>Hey there, Beast. Did you need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_24">
        <text>Hey, uh, I need your help with a little something. We had a stalker called Scavenger; he was really important to us. He went missing around two days ago. Do you think you could keep an eye out for him while you’re out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_26">
        <text>Hey, dude. What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_28">
        <text>’Sup, Beast? Everything good?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_3">
        <text>Yeah. We should wait until he’s rested up, though. I don’t want to push him too hard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_4">
        <text>If only we had some actual trained medics. Maybe we could stretch our medicine farther. But hey, you finally sound coherent. Got your shit together after a good night’s sleep?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_5">
        <text>Yeah. I feel human again. Twelve hours of sleep and a big meal do wonders.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_6">
        <text>They sure do… Hey, do you remember when I told you about that guy called Scavenger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_7">
        <text>The looter? Yeah, I remember him. Why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_8">
        <text>What about him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_after_heli_crash_9">
        <text>Well, around two days ago he went on an assignment and hasn’t returned. He found a strange PDA signal and triangulated coordinates based off of where it was broadcasting from and went to go check it out. I sent out the other scouts to find him, and they found you instead. Apparently, they found you pretty close to a mutant lair, too. Bunch of snorks nearby and somehow they didn’t notice you. Lucky, huh?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_0">
        <text>Ah, so *that’s* where the zombies came from. Well, we can finally stop worrying about them at least. Thanks for your help, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_1">
        <text>I scratch your back…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_10">
        <text>It’ll mean a lot if you find him. Scavenger was a good stalker. He"s been a great help to us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_11">
        <text>If I find anything, I’ll shoot a message.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_2">
        <text>Yeah, yeah. We’ll keep that in mind. But we’ve gotta get out of here unless we want to fight that pseudogiant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_3">
        <text>We’ll figure something out. There has to be an exit somewhere.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_4">
        <text>Yeah, true. Oh, before I forget, do you remember that guy we called Scavenger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_5">
        <text>The looter dude? Yeah, why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_6">
        <text>I heard a few stories about him from the other guys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_7">
        <text>Yeah. He was one of our scouts and he had a backpack with a special suspension system that let him carry *a lot* of stuff. He was our lifeline, since he would loot some of the less fortunate stalkers that came in here, and we’d have a semi-steady source of medicine and ammo. The problem is that he left about two days to go check out some sort of distress signal, but never came back. We sent two of our other scouts out to look for him the other day, Cutter and Mosquito, but they found you instead. Do you think you could look for him, please?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_8">
        <text>Yeah, he was popular among our group. He combed the nearby areas for unfortunate stalkers that died after they entered the anomaly and looted them, which essentially gave us a semi-steady supply of medicine and ammo. He went to go check out a strange distress signal near the base about two or three days ago and never came back. We sent out Cutter and Mosquito, our other two scouts, to go and find him. All they found was you, though. Can you maybe look around for him the next time you’re out, please?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_controller_kill_9">
        <text>Sure. I’ll go look around for him. Hopefully, I’ll find a lead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_0">
        <text>So whatcha find there, Beast? Did you clear out all of the zombies?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_1">
        <text>Yes. I found Mosquito there, and he got out safe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_10">
        <text>Ah. Did they have any information on a possible exit?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_11">
        <text>No… but they sure looked long and hard for one. What I really want to know is how they became zombies after they entered the anomaly. There’s no psy-emitters to fry them here from what we know, so what the hell happened to those guys?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_2">
        <text>I cleaned out the zombies, but they got to Mosquito before I got there. There was nothing I could do about him. Sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_3">
        <text>Thank God… Did you find any interesting info on those other guys while you were there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_4">
        <text>Jesus Christ… Rest in peace, Mosquito…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_5">
        <text>Yeah, they were a Duty squad. One of them had a hardcover journal with their faction code written on the first page, as well as some notes on this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_6">
        <text>Mmm… Also, the zombies were the remnants of a Duty squad. Their leader had a hardcover journal on him with their faction code written on the first page, and had some notes on this place in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_7">
        <text>Was there anything in it that we didn’t know?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_8">
        <text>Any new info in it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_dead_zombied_9">
        <text>Not really. Just some observations on what happens to items as they hit the outer boundaries of the anomaly and the obvious stuff about it being space-related.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_0">
        <text>Fucking h-hell… My head is killing me… What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_1">
        <text>A controller attacked us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_2">
        <text>Well, that’s not good. It explains the zombies, but I really don’t like that we had a controller snooping around under our noses. If the zombies had been wandering so close to the barn, that must mean the controller must have been, too, which is a scary thought. We’ve really gotta beef up our security in this place…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_3">
        <text>Yeah. I think we need to find the other guys some ammo, though, in case they run into trouble.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_4">
        <text>As important as that is, I think the key issue here is that we’re almost out of potable water. Our drinking water supplies are getting dangerously low, and our food supplies are dwindling too. Morale is dropping lower and lower every day because of it, and some of the guys are starting to get pessimistic about the future.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_5">
        <text>I’ll do everything I can to make sure things start getting better around here, Savage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_6">
        <text>Yeah… I just wish fate didn’t decide to supremely fuck me like it did, though. I need to get back to my family. I have a wife and two kids waiting back at home. If only I could get out of here…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_7">
        <text>We’re going to get out of this alive, man. This is us we’re talking about. We’ve lived through every other “gift from the Zone” we’ve received, even when it felt like it was fucking Christmas. You’ll get back to your family a rich man with a fat bank account from all the information you’ll sell to the scientists and use that like a cushion to find a better job. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_8">
        <text>Yeah… Yeah! We’re getting so much first-hand, practical information on this new anomaly that we’re worth our weight in gold to them. Why didn’t I think of that?! We’re all gonna be rich as hell when we get out of here. Thank you, Beast. You’re a good man. I think you should take a breather and go to sleep for tonight; you don’t look too good after taking a controller head-on. The other guys will field dress that controller and see if we can get any good parts from it to sell to the scientists.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_lutiy_talk_to_go_sleep_9">
        <text>Yeah… I think some sleep will help ground me. Good night, bro.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_10">
        <text>Yeah… Okay, there. It’s right around that marker right there. Good hunting, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_12">
        <text>Hey, Beast. You need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_13">
        <text>Let’s go, then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_14">
        <text>I’m listening, man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_15">
        <text>Hey, uh, did you need anything?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_16">
        <text>Yeah, Beast. We’re running really low on ammo and food, and our stock of potable drinking water is almost empty. It’s hard to purify water here since the sunlight isn’t harsh enough to make a solar distiller, not to mention there aren’t even any natural water sources nearby. The only thing I can think of is the well outside the barn, but that’s practically groundwater, and it’s been there since before the Chernobyl incident. The Geiger counter would explode if we dropped it down there, since soil absorbs radiation like a sponge. Not to mention all the bacteria in it… Crazy mutant bacteria from the god damn Zone.\n \nBut there is one way I’ve been thinking about that would definitely make safe drinking water. This anomaly has a strange effect on life inside of it, flora and fauna alike. Way back when, my squad got assigned to help the scientists at Yantar with some stuff. This was right around when they had just discovered these kinds of anomalies, and because I was the equivalent of an errand boy for my squad, I was an errand boy for them too. They had me doing simple stuff, some of it was actually kind of fun. Especially the telescope stuff.\n \nBut anyways, one of their exploration squads into one of the spatial anomalies found some weird-looking anomalous plant that the anomaly had made. The scientists had me helping them figure out what it did, and I essentially made tea out of it because I had no clue what the hell to expect from it. Turns out it clears out every god damn thing in water when you boil it just short of the hydrogen and the oxygen. It creates perfectly pure distilled water when you boil it in water, and boy, were those scientists surprised… But anyways, the plant’s a cool-looking red and white flower. Looks like a lily, except the petals are paired on two ends of it, kind of like a butterfly’s wings. I’m sure you’ll be able to spot it from a mile away, since it glows kind of red against the gray and green muck of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_17">
        <text>You… want me to go flower picking? I never thought I would hear that in a place like this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_18">
        <text>Well, uhh…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_19">
        <text>Haha, chill. I’m just teasing you; I love flowers. I used to help my sister with her gardens, and I have a natural knack for flower arrangements. You should have seen my mom’s face every Mother’s day…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_2">
        <text>We can talk later, Beast. Right now you really need to focus on clearing out those zombies.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_20">
        <text>Man, how did someone like you end up as a merc in the Zone…? Anyways… Cutter found a location near a tower that has a lot of them. They tend to grow in clusters; they’re inflorescences. I know exactly what they look like, but I don’t want to miss any. There’s also a *lot* of mutants near the location, and I’m running low on ammo. I was wondering if you could come with me and cover me, keeping an eye out of any of these special flowers to make sure I don’t miss them as well as helping me clear out the mutants there in case more grow in the same place. Do you think you could help me out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_21">
        <text>Sure, Snake. Let’s head out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_22">
        <text>In a second, there was something up with my gear. I’ll go after I fix it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_24">
        <text>I’m listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_26">
        <text>Thank you, Beast. These plants should last us for a week or two; I got a *lot* of them. If you need more drinking water, come see mee and I’ll make you some.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_28">
        <text>You ready to pick some flowers, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_29">
        <text>Sure am. Let’s get going.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_3">
        <text>Right. I’ll talk to you when I’m done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_30">
        <text>Uh, in a little bit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_31">
        <text>Thank you. I’ll keep that in mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_33">
        <text>Hey, Beast. Need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_34">
        <text>Yeah, my canteen is empty. Can I get some water?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_35">
        <text>Yeah, lemme see it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_36">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_37">
        <text>Right now, I’m busy purifying that water for you. The plant’s still dissolving… I’ll let you know when I’m done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_38">
        <text>All right. Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_40">
        <text>Here you go. It’s bitter ’cause that flower got rid of the minerals that make water taste like… well, water. It’ll beat the hell out of your thirst, though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_41">
        <text>Thanks, Snake.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_42">
        <text>The water’s not done yet. It wouldn’t be good to go out hunting without some water on hand to put out fires and make sure we don’t get dehydrated out there and all that. It would be bad to just drop in the middle of a hunt, you know? Anyways, we’ll deal with the flesh after we’ve got some spare water to bring.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_44">
        <text>The water’s not done; it’s not even heated up yet. Come back later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_46">
        <text>All right, I’m ready. Here’s your flask; I added some drink powder I’ve been saving. It’s grape flavored.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_47">
        <text>Thanks. Whoa… Add some bread to this mixture and you could make some kvass.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_48">
        <text>It was vaccuum sealed. I got it from Suslov’s special imported section of his stock. Anyways, let’s go hunt some flesh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_49">
        <text>Yeah, let’s head out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_50">
        <text>Uh, all right. The flesh are waiting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_51">
        <text>I’ll go later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_53">
        <text>Here you go. The water’s been cooling down so it should be under room temperature by now. You can chug it or whatever if you’re really thirsty; I’ll make another pot for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_54">
        <text>Whew, thanks bro. I’ve been thirsty all day long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_6">
        <text>Oh, hey, you’re finally here. You ready to hunt those weird-looking pigs?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_7">
        <text>Yeah, let’s go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_8">
        <text>All right. I’m marking the location of a nearby herd of ’em on your PDA for you. They’ve been pretty active lately. Something riled them up, and they were going wild trying to calm down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_start_9">
        <text>That’s good. I’d rather hunt them while they’re tired out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_0">
        <text>Hey, I’m out of water. Do you think you could purify some more for me, please?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_1">
        <text>Sure. Let me see your canteen, and I’ll get to work on a fresh pot of water.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_2">
        <text>Here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_3">
        <text>The water’s not done yet, Beast. It’s gotta cool down and all that… I’ll text you on your PDA when it’s done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_line_snake_water_clean_4">
        <text>Oh, okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_0">
        <text>Tell me about your group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_1">
        <text>Well, who do you want to know about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_10">
        <text>Uh, nevermind, actually.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_11">
        <text>Cutter’s a principled man. He can be narrow-minded, but he knows when to give up and when he’s wrong. He helps keep things going smoothly in the group with his stark knowledge-based approach. He’s been here for about two months, and struggled to adapt to the way this place works at first. He’s gotten used to it now, and his primary role here is reconnaissance. Bone is strongest where it’s mended, after all. He has clinical depression, though, and he hasn’t been able to get any of his normal imported meds lately. It’s not that severe, but he’s been feeling pretty down lately; mental illness and slim chances of escape are a pretty bad cocktail. I think he’ll be able to shake the hopelessness in a day or two, though. In the meantime, he’s been trying alternative treatment; twelve hours of sleep a night, drinking plenty of water, and… jacking off twice a day.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_12">
        <text>Hmm… I see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_13">
        <text>Sledge? He’s not even a man; he’s a god damn force of nature. Built like a tank and sturdy like steel. I’ve known him for a long ass time. He was part of Freedom’s new military warehouses offensive, clearing it out for a new front base to make progress on the Scorcher. He was just about everyone’s favorite person back then; wits sharp like knives and a knack for strategy. Still does, too. When he came here, things changed, though. He analyzed his ideals and lifestyle closely, and I think he became a better person. He’s been here for about two and a half months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_14">
        <text>Hm. So this place has… *some* kind of use. Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_15">
        <text>Young dude who used to be with Duty. He came to the Zone to prove himself and earn some money for his family, joining Duty to gain some discipline. His dad was a real piece of shit… Gave him an inferiority complex. He has a lot of natural talents that would be a shame to go to waste… I genuinely hope he leaves the Zone and goes to a good university when we get out of here. He’s also quite close with Sledge, despite having a lot of conflicts with him, with the Duty–Freedom stuff and all. He’ll be here for a month in about five days.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_16">
        <text>Markus is a musician and intellectual, and my right hand man. I trust him with everything. He was part of the original group that ended up in here. We had a third guy, but that’s a long story. We “settled” the areas around here, paving the way for future stalkers like you to survive in a place like this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_17">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_18">
        <text>Thanks for the info, Savage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_19">
        <text>Mosquito was a professional sniper for a PMC group based in the United States. His accuracy is practically supernatural; he can predict wind pressure and other influences on shot placement manually, and he doesn’t need a spotter. His favorite trick is to read the wind’s influence and miss intentionally, letting the bullet curve to hit the target. He’s kindhearted and quite talkative… and he’s got an iron will. He doesn’t let the anomaly faze him. He’s been with us for about three months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_2">
        <text>Tell me about Cutter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_20">
        <text>Mosquito used to be a professional sniper for a PMC group based out of the United States. His accuracy was practically supernatural; his favorite trick is to read the wind’s influence on his shots to make the bullet look like it curved to hit the target… He would have been stuck here for around three months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_21">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_22">
        <text>Knucklehead is a godsend; he has practical experience field dressing animals. He used to live in a rural area, near the Carpathians. His family hunted for meat in the wilderness, grew their own vegetables, and tried very hard to put him through school. He came to the Zone to make large amounts of money in order to pay tuition costs for his dream university. As for his role here, he’s a hunter. He keeps us supplied with mutant meat so we don’t starve, showed us how to properly field dress animals, and taught us this crazy sharpening trick for knives that he used steel wool for. Things around here just wouldn’t work without him. He’s been with us for three and a half months.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_23">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_24">
        <text>Screw’s an integral part of our group. He’s a technician used to building gold from trash; his friends outside the Zone used to call him “the alchemist.” The guys give him all sorts of random stuff that he repurposes in the craziest ways, mostly to fix up and improve our gear. He doesn’t exactly do it for free, but his rates are pretty good considering there’s a finite amount of money between us. He got here about a week ago or two after us, and since then, he’s been a steady helping hand.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_25">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_26">
        <text>I’m the smartest person in the whole wide world and I eat pussy every day of my life. Haha, but for real, I’m the local genius. I got stuck here with my squad during the Clear Sky Limansk offensive. Our detachment got split up fighting a monolith ambush, and some of us accidentally stepped into a portal to this anomaly. Only Markus, Shell, and myself seem to have made it in here. Shell was the leader of the detachment, so naturally, he became the leader here too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_27">
        <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_28">
        <text>Not at all. If you want me to share more about anyone else, just ask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_3">
        <text>Tell me about Sledgehammer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_4">
        <text>Tell me about Snake.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_5">
        <text>Tell me about Markus.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_6">
        <text>Tell me about Mosquito.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_7">
        <text>Tell me about Knucklehead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_8">
        <text>Tell me about Screw.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_all_9">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_0">
        <text>Hi there, Beast. Did you need anything?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_1">
        <text>Yeah, have you seen Markus around? He should have been back by now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_2">
        <text>Hmm… No. We can try pinging his PDA signal, though. Maybe we can triangulate his location?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_3">
        <text>Yeah, that sounds like a pretty good idea.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_end_2">
        <text>All right… I’ve got it. Something’s not right, though; it’s not moving, and it’s in a place where you normally wouldn’t stop and set up camp. Something’s not right. Please, check out his location ASAP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_end_3">
        <text>All right, I’ll go check it out right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_markus_end_5">
        <text>Beast, please, focus on finding out if Markus is okay or not.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_0">
        <text>I have info on that SOS signal incident.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_1">
        <text>I’m listening. Did you talk to the person who sent it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_10">
        <text>A little bit of ammo and a day’s worth of food, but that’s about it. Sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_2">
        <text>Yup. I led him here and recruited him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_3">
        <text>That’s good. Does he know about this place?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_4">
        <text>Yeah. He told me he was being pursued by a mercenary group, though. I thought that would be important for you to know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_5">
        <text>Fuck. That’s not good… but I doubt the Syndicate is reckless enough to jump head first into a spatial anomaly. Can you ask him for more information about himself? We need to know if he can be trusted.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_6">
        <text>Sure thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_7">
        <text>I’m listening. What happened there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_8">
        <text>The sender was dead on arrival. Nothing I could really do about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_meet_to_murad_9">
        <text>Fucking hell… Did he have anything good on him, at least?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_0">
        <text>I found Scavenger. He’s dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_1">
        <text>Dead?! What the hell happened to him?!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_10">
        <text>Hmm… Well, I’ll have to take a look around some of the areas the teleporter brings you to. There was also a daily journal on his PDA that detailed just about everything of importance that he did every day. Turns out Scavenger wasn’t really a scavenger at all; more like a hunter. He’d find stalkers that had just gotten into the anomaly, lead them somewhere secluded, and murder them in cold blood. He’d loot them and toss their corpse into an anomaly or a local flesh herd, which is why the flesh in this place were so much fatter than normal ones. They were well fed, and Scavenger took just about everything he could; he even took the suits right off their back. Pretty bone chilling stuff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_11">
        <text>Jesus Christ… I always thought something was off about how much stuff he was able to “find.” Think of how many innocents he killed! Think of how many of them could have been saved… could have been recruited. What a piece of shit… but what’s important here is that we *have* to find that device. Do you think you could do a sweep around that place you were talking about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_12">
        <text>The problem is that the teleporters can bring you to multiple locations. It looks like it can be random, according to Scavenger’s PDA, but there are two locations they almost always bring you to. The “ninety-five percent” of the pie chart, if you will. It’ll take a while for me to search the normal locations too, so I dunno. I’ll put some work in, though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_13">
        <text>Well, just keep trying. It’s our only lead on a way out of here right now, so it should be our top priority. If you make any progress or find any info on a lead, let me know, okay? And was there anything else of value on Scavenger’s PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_14">
        <text>Well, that’s very much like him. At least he *tried* to help us… if you find any more info on his stash, let me know. We’ll figure out what to do with it. Did his PDA have anything else on it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_15">
        <text>Oh, so that piece of shit took all the good stuff and let us use the grimy ammo and eat mutant meat. Wonderful. If you find that stash, bring it back here; we really need those extra supplies. We’ll put it to good use, unlike that bastard scavenger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_16">
        <text>Are you serious?! That motherfucker! I swear to God, the things I would do to him… The crucifix would look merciful. A shame he’s already dead. He deserved worse.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_17">
        <text>Well, not much we can do about him now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_18">
        <text>God damn it… And we all trusted him, too… Did that rat bastard have anything else on his PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_19">
        <text>A few bits here and there. You can have it if you want. He practically wrote half an essay on how flesh chew their food. Guess he watched them eat the stalkers, too. What a sick freak.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_2">
        <text>By the far fence. He was using one of the northern teleporters to get around; that’s how I found him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_20">
        <text>Jesus fucking Christ… We have to focus on finding that device, though. It’s our only lead on a way out of here. Do you think you could try looking for it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_21">
        <text>I can try, but it would take a while. The teleporters are weird; they act up sometimes. It’s a big area to look through too, so…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_22">
        <text>Keep me updated if you find anything on it; leads *or* general information. Was there anything else on his PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_23">
        <text>Well, this is very much like him… if you find that stash of his, let us know. We’ll certainly put it to better use than a dead man. Did his PDA have anything else of value on it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_24">
        <text>Well, I’ve already found it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_25">
        <text>Oh? Good work, Beast. What was in it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_26">
        <text>Ammo, medical supplies, food, and a funky-looking locked box with no key nearby. His PDA has no info on any keys for it, either.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_27">
        <text>Can I see it?… Well, I can’t recall him mentioning a lockbox or a key for one, and it’s got me stumped. Screw will probably find a way to crack it though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_28">
        <text>Yeah, that guy is pretty good. If anyone can, it’s him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_29">
        <text>Yup. He’s kind of a legend around here. Did that scavenger’s PDA have anything else on it, though?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_3">
        <text>Fuck, that guy was sharp as hell, too… What are we gonna do without him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_30">
        <text>I guess we didn’t know as much about that scavenger bastard as we thought we did… Oh, before I forget! Knucklehead wanted to talk to you, and that army guy also wanted to see you. Said he had some important info. Can you talk to him for me? I really need some time to sort this stuff out mentally.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_31">
        <text>Leave it to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_4">
        <text>He’s not God or anything. We can survive without him. Here’s his PDA, by the way. I found it in his backpack.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_5">
        <text>Does it have anything important on it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_6">
        <text>Yeah. A looot of interesting stuff…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_7">
        <text>Like… what…?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_8">
        <text>He found remains of some kind of device that shows you the exit of the anomaly. It was stashed away somewhere, but there’s no information on where.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_after_foundet_padalshik_9">
        <text>Scavenger had a lot of stashes, but there was one main central one where he kept all of his big stuff. The real valuables as well as a whole supply kit that would last for about three days, just in case shit hit the fan. He mentioned it once after drinking half a bottle of vodka; said it was in a place where *nobody* could get to it. Put a lot of emphasis on how unreachable it is for just about anyone that isn’t him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_0">
        <text>Hey, uh, when did Scavenger go missing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_1">
        <text>Two days ago. He picked up an SOS signal nearby and went to go check it out; never came back. When I sent Cutter and Mosquito—our only other two scouts—to find him, they found you instead. Not that that’s a bad thing; you’ve helped us so much already.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_2">
        <text>Well, I just try to help out where I can. I’ll go look for Scavenger, though. He sounded pretty important to you guys.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_3">
        <text>Yeah, it would mean a lot to us. Scavenger’s a good person. He’s really helped us stabilize our position in here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_lutiy_talk_to_padalshik_4">
        <text>Yeah… Anyways, if I find anything, I’ll text you on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_0">
        <text>I found Scavenger’s stash.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_1">
        <text>Oh? Whadja find?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_2">
        <text>Ammo, medical supplies, some food, and this weird looking metal box with a lock on it. No key nearby, either.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_3">
        <text>Well, we can let Screw mess around with it. Mechanisms are his specialty, after all. Lemme see it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_4">
        <text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_5">
        <text>Yeah, this thing’s pretty thick… It would be hard to even scratch it. I’ll let you know if Screw makes any progress on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_quest_padalshik_habar_done_6">
        <text>Sounds good. I’ve gotta go do something right now anyways.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_10">
        <text>Can I ask you something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_11">
        <text>Maybe. It depends on what you’re asking.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_12">
        <text>What do you think about the other guys here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_13">
        <text>Do you think we can really get out of here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_14">
        <text>Do you think love can bloom on a battlefield? Haha, joking. You should see your face. But what I really wanted to ask you was: Who were you before you came here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_15">
        <text>Nevermind…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_16">
        <text>I’ve gotta go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_17">
        <text>It’s not like I have any radical opinions on them. We’re all stuck in this mess together, like pebbles stuck in cement. Even if we wanted to fight each other, our hands are tied. Ammo is scarce and violence breeds violence, so it would start a chain reaction that would wipe all of us out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_18">
        <text>I don’t really know. That’s something only fate knows. It’s impressive that we’ve lasted this long though, so I think we can hold out until another development gets dropped into our lap. This place is absolutely ridiculous, though; I woke up in the middle of the night, and I couldn’t fall back asleep, so I went for a walk around the barn for some fresh air. The smell of smoke hits me like a truck, and I think, “What the hell could be burning? Didn’t it rain earlier today?”\n \nWith the naked eye, I could see a massive pillar of fire that kissed the clouds above. Had to be thirty yards wide. A real inferno. Someone was standing in the center of it, too. I scrambled back inside, got my binoculars, and took a look. The smoke got thicker, and I couldn’t see shit. I rub my eyes from the sting of smoke, take another look, and it’s all gone. I hear laughter that’s so harsh it makes me want to clear my own throat, like how you want to crack your knuckles after hearing someone else do it.\n \nI don’t know what to fucking make of it, whether it’s a new kind of mutant or a bad reaction to the mutant meat I ate earlier. I went back to sleep and dreamt about it… Really scared the shit out of me. Didn’t bode well. If it’s real, we have a time frame to get out of here before that god damn thing finds us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_19">
        <text>I came here as green as they come. Leather jacket, a kitchen knife, and my grandpa’s bolt action. Sidorovich had me doing pickups and minor negotiations for him, and a few hunting jobs. I had a pretty good aim with that rifle of mine. I made enough to get an actual stalker suit, looted an automatic from some guy who got mauled by mutants, and made my way to Yantar from the Agroprom. Talk about a harrowing journey…\n \nThe guys at Yantar are where the real money in the Zone lie, though. They’ve got contracts and sterile medical supplies, and doctors that don’t bill you before they save your life. The army doesn’t sniff around there more than they have to, and if you have a work permit from the scientists and a yellow patch on the back of your suit, you legally count as an “accepted individual into the Zone for work purposes.” They can’t touch you because you’re here legally. The only problem is that the scientists send you to the deep parts of the Zone that has stuff you can’t even dream of. In good *and* bad ways. I got stuck here collecting artifacts from a “special new kind of anomaly” in Yantar, north of the swamp near Sakharov’s bunker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_2">
        <text>Oh, hey, it’s you. Looking better than you did before. Thanks for clearing out those zombies earlier.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_3">
        <text>Well, I owed you for saving my hide. By the way, do you know where my stuff is? Where was I found?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_4">
        <text>We didn’t find a backpack on you. You probably dropped it before you entered the anomaly. We found you in one of the houses nearby. We combed that area pretty well, looking to see if we could maybe exit through an entrance portal. I think we could, though; I found a white looking cloud at ground level, tossed a bolt into it, and it disappeared along with the cloud.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_5">
        <text>Can you send me the coordinates? I need some fresh air anyways.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_6">
        <text>Uh, sure. Here, I’ll send it to you on your PDA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_7">
        <text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_rezak_first_meet_9">
        <text>So, Beast, whatcha got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Hey merc—er, Beast. Sorry. Uh, anyways, I’m the local technician. A mechanical genius. I’ll buy busted shooters off of you; I break them down for parts which let me repair your weapons. Also, if you find any sets of tools, I’ll take them off your hands. I’m working with a wooden mallet and a screwdriver to break weapons down, for christ’s sake.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Hey, Beast! Need any of my mechanical experise?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_5">
        <text>I’ll keep you in mind when my stuff starts breaking down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Well, come see me if you need anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_0">
        <text>Make any progress on Scavenger’s container?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_1">
        <text>Yeah, thing cracked right open once I got the right thickness of wire to jimmy the lock with. Anyways, it had a *lot* of shit in it; even a fancy set of tools. I kept that one for myself. Hope you don’t mind. Savage came by though and said he needed some of this stuff to share with the rest of the group, though, so take your pick of the loot, and I’ll give the rest to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_10">
        <text>I’ll take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_11">
        <text>Eh, I hardly ever use my sidearm. Markus can have that. What’s next?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_12">
        <text>That’s all of the specific stuff. The rest is just ammo and medical supplies, which I’ll let Savage distribute amongst the others. They’ll definitely be pleased to have more than two mags on them at a time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_13">
        <text>Here you go, along with a few mags that were in the container. Next up is three mags of 5.45x39 7H22, a special armor-piercing round with a tungsten core designed to pierce up to armor class IIIA, drywall, thin metal barriers, etc. Spetsnaz-issue. You want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_14">
        <text>Sure do. What’s next?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_15">
        <text>The only people I can think of that would have thick armor are mercenaries, and I already know the weak spots in their common armors. I’m good, but what’s next?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_16">
        <text>All right, here. Next up is a rare artifact, called the “Black Angel.” It helps you withstand a lot of psychic pressure from mutants and anomalies. You want it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_17">
        <text>Yeah. This will *definitely* come in handy later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_18">
        <text>I’m good. Anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_19">
        <text>Here. That was the last thing in the box except for the ammo and medical supplies that Savage requested. I’ll let him divide it amongst the rest of the guys, who should be very pleased to have more than one mag on them at any given moment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_2">
        <text>That’s fair. What was inside?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_20">
        <text>Uh, two packs of 5.45x39 7H22 armor piercing ammo with a hardened tungsten core. They’re designed to pierce armor up to class IIIA, drywall, thin metal barriers… You get the picture. You want it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_21">
        <text>We’ve got a Black Angel artifact that helps you withstand psy-emissions and psychic pressure. Did you want it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_22">
        <text>Great. See you later, Screw.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_3">
        <text>Well, first off was a Spetsnaz-issue 1PN58 night vision scope. Fits onto dovetail mounts and has a pretty clear image, no cracks, nothing. I manually zeroed it in and set it for three point five times zoom.</text> <!-- fix -->
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_4">
        <text>Sounds useful. Lemme get it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_5">
        <text>Mosquito could put that to better use. I’ll pass.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_6">
        <text>Here you go. Next up is an FNP-45, perfect condition. Two or three aftermarket parts, but other than that, looks completely original. .45 ACP, big mag size, excellent accuracy and handling characteristics. Probably the best pistol you can get in the Zone without an arms dealer contact. You want it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_7">
        <text>Hell yeah I want that! Pass it here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_8">
        <text>Eh… Sidearms aren’t that important to me. What’s next?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_open_habar_9">
        <text>That’s pretty fair. Next up though, is an FNP-45. Perfect condition, completely original parts. .45 ACP, big mag size, solid accuracy and handling characteristics and beats the hell out of that heavy SOCOM hunk of junk. One of the best sidearms in the whole Zone. You interested?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_toolkit_1_0">
        <text>I found a toolkit. You interested?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_toolkit_1_1">
        <text>Sure am. Pass it over here. Hmm… looks like they should be sufficient for basic work. They beat the hell out of this soviet mallet I was using before… thanks, Beast. I’ll be sure to give you special treatment and some lowered prices for this, heh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_shurup_talk_to_toolkit_1_2">
        <text>Haha. Thanks, Screw.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_10">
        <text>Find those fucking assholes!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_12">
        <text>Hey, Beast, you still busy? Wanna help me out with a little errand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_13">
        <text>What did you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_14">
        <text>We need to fix the radio transceiver in the basement. We should be able to fix it with a battery and about two rolls of copper wire. The copper wiring should be real easy to find, but the hard part is probably going to be finding a suitable battery with a charge. Your best bet would probably be looting it off another stalker or trading with someone who’s just come into this anomaly.\n \nIf you find anything, bring it here, please. The transceiver down there is pretty powerful, so we’ll probably be able to transmit outside of the anomaly. It’s looking like our only lead on a way out right now, so it’s pretty important that we get it working.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_15">
        <text>All right. I’ll keep an eye out for batteries and copper wire.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_16">
        <text>Not right now. Ask me again later, though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_18">
        <text>You find anything?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_2">
        <text>Hey, Beast! I’m chilling down here now. I kind of like it down here, and I wanted to stay out of the others’ way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_20">
        <text>Got a battery. Someone new came into the anomaly, and I traded him for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_21">
        <text>I’ve got the copper wire.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_22">
        <text>Unfortunate, but let’s hope his path ends up in a U-turn right out of this godforsaken place. It works, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_23">
        <text>It should. It came from another radio transceiver that broke on the way here, so it should match this one.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_24">
        <text>I think it will. He took it from a radio transceiver of his own that got broken on the way here. It should fit right into ours.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_25">
        <text>Okay… Yup. It fits right in. I just need the rolls of copper wiring so I can replace what got fried, and then I can try to restart it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_26">
        <text>Okay, let’s see… Yeah, it looks fine to me. If I did it right, we should be able to get this thing started again. Come back in about twenty minutes, give or take, and I’ll let you know if it’s working.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_27">
        <text>All right. Sounds good to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_29">
        <text>Hey, Beast, I’ll talk to you later. Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_3">
        <text>Well, that’s good news. Savage said you needed me for something. Everything okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_30">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_32">
        <text>Hey there, Beast. You need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_33">
        <text>Oh hey, it’s you. Did you have any questions for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_34">
        <text>I’m all ears, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_35">
        <text>No. I’ve been looking pretty hard, too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_36">
        <text>Excellent. All I need now is a battery and this thing will be working again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_37">
        <text>Well, I’ll just have to keep looking, I guess.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_38">
        <text>Well, keep me updated and all that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_39">
        <text>Okay. I’ll get busy looking again, so later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_4">
        <text>Yeah, Beast. There’s a radio transceiver down here, and it’s pretty powerful. I studied radio technology when I was younger; minored in it, and I was pretty damn good with it. I think I can get it working again, but I need some spare parts first. If you can find me a suitable battery with a charge and some copper wire to replace the fried wiring, I’ll have a good chance of restarting this bad boy and maybe broadcasting an SOS signal to people outside of this anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_40">
        <text>Excellent! Give me about twenty minutes and I think I can get this beast working…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_41">
        <text>Sure. Let me know when you’re done and I’ll come back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_42">
        <text>All right. I’ll try to find some.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_44">
        <text>Come back in a little while. I’m still trying to get this thing working.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_46">
        <text>I fixed it! I really fixed it…! All right, now let’s try to broadcast something…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_47">
        <text>Did you pick up on any outside signals while you were testing it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_48">
        <text>Not really. Just some Soviet-era alert broadcasts that were turned on when the Scorcher was turned on. I’ll keep trying, though; you may have just saved us all with a battery and some copper wire, Beast!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_49">
        <text>God, I hope so.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_5">
        <text>A battery? I would have to get one off someone who had just entered the anomaly in order for it to still have any charge…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_6">
        <text>Well, I’m kind of busy right now. Let’s discuss that later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_7">
        <text>Well, I’m just putting some options out there. The battery is the most important part, so we’ll just have to be vigilant. Just bring me the wire and battery if you find any.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_8">
        <text>All right, all right. It’s going straight to you if I manage to find any.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_9">
        <text>What kind of help did you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_final_2">
        <text>What’s up, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_final_3">
        <text>Oh hey, Beast. Did you need something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_meet_final_4">
        <text>I’m listening, Beast.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_10">
        <text>Jesus christ… I need… a medkit…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_11">
        <text>Oh, thank God… Wait a second. Where am I?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_12">
        <text>Well, have you ever heard of a space bubble?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_13">
        <text>Yeah. Why?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_14">
        <text>God really decided to supremely fuck you in particular today.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_15">
        <text>I knew I shouldn’t have flown today… The cloud-level anomaly maps were never reliable. Fucking colonel… Whatever. I’ll curse him and his god damn family later. Where’s the way out of here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_16">
        <text>We don’t know yet. Were you flying with a crew in tow?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_17">
        <text>Yeah, but if the ’copter crashed, they’re probably ground beef right now. Anomaly toasted the control mechanism; the blades straight up melted too.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_18">
        <text>Hmm… Well, in any case, you should take it easy. Try not to push yourself too much, or that medkit will have gone to waste.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_20">
        <text>All right… Wait, look around for my rifle. It should be nearby.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_23">
        <text>You need something, Beast?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_3">
        <text>Holy fuck… I might be finished…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_4">
        <text>Hold on, hold on! I can save you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_5">
        <text>Please, hurry…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_6">
        <text>You’ll live. I’ve seen people bounce back from worse. Let me stabilize you with a medkit, and I’ll bring you back to the medic back at base.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_7">
        <text>Holy fuck! Okay! Whatever! Just make this god damn pain stop!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_8">
        <text>Here. Use this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pb_soldier_oleynik_wounded_9">
        <text>Shit, let me find a medkit. There was one nearby…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="super_0">
        <text>default text</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
