<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_antirad">
		<text>Anti-radation drug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad_descr">
		<text>Radiation protection drugs are common in the Zone. When used, this drug induces contraction of peripheral blood vessels and oxygen deprivation, which serves to treat and prevent radiation exposure. The drug does not have severe side effects, although isolated cases of mild nausea, dizziness, cramps and stomach pain have been reported.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage">
		<text>Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage_descr">
		<text>A normal elastic bandage used to stop bleeding and prevent infection of wounds. For regular bleeding, carefully apply the bandage to the wound. For arterial bleeding, urgently tie the bandage around the affected area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_binocular_descr">
		<text>Standard issue military binoculars with a maximum of x7.5 magnification. Useful in the Zone in that they allow its owner to observe things from a distance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_binocular_name">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread">
		<text>Bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread_descr">
		<text>No bakers have ever been identified in the Zone, but this bread is neither contaminated nor radioactive, being fresh and quite edible. At least no complaints have been reported thus far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva">
		<text>“Tourist’s Breakfast”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva_descr">
		<text>Presumably, these canned goods were looted by stalkers from an army ration depot. Without any kind of label on the can, it’s hard to say for sure. Should still be good to eat, if you believe the best before date.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1">
		<text>“Echo” detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1_descr">
		<text>This dated anomalous activity detector produces an alarm signal when anomalous particles enter a special chamber as you approach an anomaly. It can also register the presence of artefacts and measure the distance to the nearest one. The distance is indicated by the frequency of the sound the detector emits. To switch to artefact search mode, open the device’s front cover. Due to its simple design, Echo can only be used to locate the most common artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2">
		<text>“Bear” detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3">
		<text>“Veles” detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3_descr">
		<text>A next generation scientific detection scanner. Thanks to three modernized detection chambers, the position of artefacts is shown on a special display screen. When closed, the device registers only radiation and anomalies. To switch to artefact search mode, open the front LED display. When in search mode, the detector is capable of locating all artefacts known to science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector4">
		<text>“Svarog” prototype detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector4_descr">
		<text>A prototype of an expanded functionality anomalous frequency scanner. This device comes with a program used to identify static areas of anomalous activity stored in its database, while retaining the ability to locate artefacts. The position of anomalous areas and artefacts is displayed on a special screen. The artefact search mode, which can be activated by opening the front LED display, has been modified to detect anomalous formations currently unknown to science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_descr">
		<text>A standard head-mounted flashlight. Useful for stalkers who find themselves out and about after dark, but may attract trouble if used unwisely.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_device_torch_name">
		<text>Flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic">
		<text>Anabiotics</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_antidot">
		<text>IP2 antitoxin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_antidot_descr">
		<text>A complex drug comprising several antidotes, including metoclopramidum, pyridoxine, thiamine, riboxin and other pharmaceuticals. The drug is used to inject a range of antibiotics to neutralize natural poisons, together with synthetic poison absorbers, into the bloodstream. IP2 is not particularly popular in the Zone, as most stalkers rely on a gas mask and a protective suit, there are still those who have a pack of this antidote stashed away. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_booster">
		<text>Hercules</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_coagulant">
		<text>Vikasolum</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_coagulant_descr">
		<text>An artificial equivalent of vitamin K. The main purpose of this drug is to increase blood coagulation speed. In great demand among stalkers who want slow-healing wounds and lacerations inflicted by mutants to close up faster. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade">
		<text>Psi-block</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_psy_blockade_descr">
		<text>A drug that blocks avalanche-like nerve impulses. Consumption induces short-term loss of all emotion. Used exclusively in the Zone to counteract the effects of anomalous psi-fields. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_radioprotector">
		<text>B190 Indraline</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink">
		<text>“Stalker” energy drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_energy_drink_descr">
		<text>Often used by stalkers on long trips when no breaks can be afforded. The drink contains easily digestible carbohydrates, as well as drugs that stimulate the release of adrenaline into the bloodstream.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_guitar_descr">
		<text>A trusty guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_guitar_name">
		<text>Guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa">
		<text>Diet sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa_descr">
		<text>For better or worse, this sausage—a mix of chicken and a soy substitute—is often a stalker’s breakfast, lunch and dinner in one. Can be stored for a long time due to high preservative content.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit">
		<text>Diagnostic first-aid kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army">
		<text>Army medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_army_descr">
		<text>A specialized medical kit for providing first aid to combat casualties. The kit includes blood coagulants based on menadione, painkillers, antibiotics and immunostimulants, as well as a kit for removing bullets and fragments from the body. This medkit is issued to army personnel as standard and is sometimes used by Duty forces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_descr">
		<text>A general purpose medical kit with a HEALTH-13 type injector. Handy for treating various injuries—wounds, bruises, regular and chemical burns and various types of poisoning. In demand among stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_science">
		<text>Scientific medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_science_descr">
		<text>A medical kit designed specifically for use in the Zone. The kit contains products for handling wounds, as well as preventing the development of radiation poisoning and reducing accumulated radiation in the body. Contains Vikasolum, Batilolum and Naphazoline, unlike other medkits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda_descr">
		<text>No saved data.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda_name">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka">
		<text>Cossacks Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka_descr">
		<text>Made by GSC. Goes down easy and considerably lowers the effects of radiation. Should be enjoyed in moderation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2_descr">
		<text>This last generation anomalous activity detector can be used to locate anomalous formations and has a colour diode panel, which not only indicates the direction of artifacts, but also measures the distance to them. To switch to artifact search mode, open the device’s front cover. Unfortunately, the device is programmed with a somewhat outdated list of detectable artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_anabiotic_descr">
		<text>An experimental drug developed by Professor Ozersky for scientific research teams working in the Zone. At its core, the drug contains tetrodotoxin, known colloquially as “zombie powder,” which causes a complete shutdown of the body’s central nervous system that may allow people to survive emissions outside cover. The drug has not undergone clinical or field testing, which puts its effectiveness in doubt and raises the quesition of possible side effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bolt">
		<text>Bolt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bolt_descr">
		<text>A 32x100 bolt. A stalker’s best friend.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_booster_descr">
		<text>The main component of this product is an anabolic androgen, an artificial steroid, the chemical composition of which resembles testosterone. Often used by stalkers during long raids to reduce muscle fatigue. Significantly increases weight-carrying capacity. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_drug_radioprotector_descr">
		<text>A radioprotectant, included in medkits issued to nuclear power plant personnel. Used in the Zone instead of the excessively toxic PC1 cystamine hydrochloride, repeated use of which often caused death. Reduces the effects of gamma radiation on live tissue. Best consumed before exposure, as effects are not instant. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="amk_metka">
		<text>GPS marker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="amk_metka_s">
		<text>GPS marker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_amk_metka">
		<text>GPS markers are used in the Zone for marking stashes. If the marker is placed inside a stash, the stash will show up on your map along with a list of the stash’s contents.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="spalnik">
		<text>Sleeping bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="spalnik_s">
		<text>Sleeping bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_spalnik">
		<text>A sleeping bag is one easiest ways to get some sleep in the Zone. However, it does not protect its user from radiation, so if you want to sleep in it, you better find some place that’s protected from blowouts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_pb_quest_document_1">
		<text>Note from Seriy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_document_1">
		<text>Note from Seriy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_document_1_descr">
		<text>A stalker’s note written on a sheet of paper torn out of a notebook. To read, click “Use.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_mail_shpala">
		<text>Note from Crosstie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_mail_shpala_descr">
		<text>A stalker’s note written on a sheet of paper torn out of a notebook. To read, click “Use.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_padalshik_pda_title">
		<text>Scavenger’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_padalshik_pda_title">
		<text>Scavenger’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_padalshik_pda_descr">
		<text>This PDA used to belong to a stalker nicknamed Scavenger. It is not locked and can be accessed. To open, click “Use.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_a2_suget_5_gui_razia_title">
		<text>Barmitsa-PC radio transmitter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_a2_suget_5_gui_razia_descr">
		<text>The Barmitsa-PC radio transmitter is used to contact Russian military radio stations, such as R-159, R-163, R-168, and others. It is equipped wiuth a built in voice changer. The radio is built for military use in the field and is therefore very light and damage-resistant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device_warning_module">
		<text>Decoder module</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device_warning_module_descr">
		<text>This device was made by scientists working in the Zone in order to see safe paths in anomalous areas. It can also block the activity of weak anomalous fields. Requires batteries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_bloknot">
		<text>Personal notepad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_bloknot_descr">
		<text>Sometimes, writing things down can help you find solutions…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tainik_padalshika">
		<text>Scavenger’s container</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tainik_padalshika_descr">
		<text>A metal container used for storing loot, secured by a complex lock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_radio_pharos">
		<text>Radio beacon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_radio_pharos_descr">
		<text>A device used for tracking radio signals within a large radius. In the Zone, this device can be used to locate stalkers by the signal of their PDAs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_rezerv_key_door">
		<text>Stockpile key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_rezerv_key_door_descr">
		<text>This key is used to open the armory containing the stockpile.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_flash_klim">
		<text>Klim’s flash drive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_flash_klim_descr">
		<text>According to Sidorovich, this flash drive has some very valuable information and it used belong to a stalker named Klim. This is the flashdrive Sidorovich asked me to bring.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_container_name">
		<text>Orest’s package</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_container_desc">
		<text>Sidorovich has given me this fairly heavy case and told me to give it to Orest. He hasn’t told me what’s inside, and, to be honest, I don’t really want to know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_pda_leader_base">
		<text>Father Valerian’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_pda_leader_base_descr">
		<text>This PDA used to belong to Father Valerian, who is now dead. The PDA is locked, and I can’t access it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blck_val_knife_killer">
		<text>Knife of the murder</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blck_val_knife_killer_descr">
		<text>This very sharp hunting knife most likely belongs to the one who killed Lefty. If I can find the owner, then I can find out the murderer.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_blck_val_chimik_pda_title">
		<text>Chemist’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_blck_val_chimik_pda_descr">
		<text>This PDA belonged to Chemist, the man who killed Lefty and Limp. This PDA might have some more useful information may prove he is, in fact, the murderer.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_esc_pashalka_shved_pda_title">
		<text>Swede’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_esc_pashalka_shved_pda_descr">
		<text>A PDA of dead stalker, whose body I found not far from the military outpost in Cordon.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="blck_val_miklucha_pda">
		<text>Miklukha’s PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blck_val_miklucha_pda_descr">
		<text>A PDA, formerly possessed by deceased Freedom leader Miklukha. The PDA is password protected, so I can’t access it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_blck_val_transiver_title">
		<text>R-250M2 radio transmitter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_blck_val_transiver_descr">
		<text>The R-250M2 is a communications receiver that works on short waves and is favored by many radio hobbyists. Two versions of this receiver have been produced: the R250/M/M2 for land forces and R-670/M for the Russian Navy. The original 1949 version was a dual conversion superheterodyne with a tuning range of 1.5–25.5 MHz spread over twelve bands. The final version, the R-250M2, was produced from 1968 until 1980. The main change was the tube type, as the set moved from metal octal tubes to miniature tubes.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_pb_quest_shell_brelok">
		<text>Shell’s dogtag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_shell_brelok_desc">
		<text>Shell is dead, and all he had on him was his dogtag. I should show this to Marcus.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_blck_val_key_to_prison">
		<text>Cell key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_blck_val_key_to_prison_descr">
		<text>A backup key to the Outpost cell. Since the death of Chemist, the key has been kept by Sologub, who leaves the key on the cupboard so that other guards can use it if necessary.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Mutant body parts -->
	<string id="st_meat_flesh_descr">
		<text>Flesh meat is both tasty and highly nutritious. It is recommend not to eat it raw, as there is high chance that the meat is infected with trichinosis or brucellosis. Such infections will infect the stalker who ingests them and cause symptoms that include but are not limited to fever, tiredness, and loss of appetite. The symptoms may prove fatal in the Zone, where danger lurks in every corner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_flesh">
		<text>Raw flesh meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_boar_descr">
		<text>Boar meat, highly nutritious and perfectly edible. It is recommend not to eat it raw, as there is high chance that the meat is infected with trichinosis or brucellosis. Such infections will infect the stalker who ingests them and cause symptoms that include but are not limited to fever, tiredness, and loss of appetite. The symptoms may prove fatal in the Zone, where danger lurks in every corner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_boar">
		<text>Raw boar meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_dog_descr">
		<text>Meat from a blind dog. Not as appetizing as flesh or boar meat, but still perfectly edible. It is recommend not to eat it raw, as there is high chance that the meat is infected with trichinosis or brucellosis. Such infections will infect the stalker who ingests them and cause symptoms that include but are not limited to fever, tiredness, and loss of appetite. The symptoms may prove fatal in the Zone, where danger lurks in every corner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_meat_dog">
		<text>Raw dog meat</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mutant_flesh_meat_descr">
		<text>Tasty, edible flesh meat. It is recommend not to eat it raw, as there is high chance that the meat is infected with trichinosis or brucellosis. Such infections will infect the stalker who ingests them and cause symptoms that include but are not limited to fever, tiredness, and loss of appetite. The symptoms may prove fatal in the Zone, where danger lurks in every corner.\n \n%c[0,204,0,51] • %c[0,140,140,140] Poisonous food\n%c[0,204,0,51] • %c[0,140,140,140] Radiation: %c[0,170,170,170] +584 mSv</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_meat">
		<text>Flesh meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_chop_descr">
		<text>Highly nutritious and perfectly edible boar meat. It is recommend not to eat it raw, as there is high chance that the meat is infected with trichinosis or brucellosis. Such infections will infect the stalker who ingests them and cause symptoms that include but are not limited to fever, tiredness, and loss of appetite. The symptoms may prove fatal in the Zone, where danger lurks in every corner.\n \n%c[0,204,0,51] • %c[0,140,140,140] Poisonous food\n%c[0,204,0,51] • %c[0,140,140,140] Radiation: %c[0,170,170,170] +646 mSv</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_chop">
		<text>Boar meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_meat_descr">
		<text>Blind dog meat. Not as good as flesh or boar meat, but still perfectly edible. It is recommend not to eat it raw, as there is high chance that the meat is infected with trichinosis or brucellosis. Such infections will infect the stalker who ingests them and cause symptoms that include but are not limited to fever, tiredness, and loss of appetite. The symptoms may prove fatal in the Zone, where danger lurks in every corner.\n \n%c[0,204,0,51] • %c[0,140,140,140] Poisonous food\n%c[0,204,0,51] • %c[0,140,140,140] Radiation: %c[0,170,170,170] +202 mSv</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_meat">
		<text>Dog meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flask_empty_name">
		<text>Empty canteen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flask_good_full_name">
		<text>Canteen with water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flask_empty_descr">
		<text>An empty canteen. It can hold up to 0.7 liters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flask_good_1_3_descr">
		<text>A canteen filled with water. Contains enough for 1 use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flask_good_2_3_descr">
		<text>A canteen filled with water. Contains enough for 2 uses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flask_good_full_descr">
		<text>A canteen full of water. Contains enough for 3 uses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_spez_razia">
		<text>DC 12V 9800mAh battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_quest_spez_razia_descr">
		<text>A lithium-ion battery that’s feat for radios. It has a fairly large capacity. It doesn’t seem to have suffered any damage, which is very lucky considering this battery was taken out of a broken radio transmitter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_kanistra_gas">
		<text>Jerry can with fuel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_kanistra_gas_descr">
		<text>A metallic jerry can with a 10 liter capacity. Filled with diesel fuel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_bolt_box_small_title">
		<text>Bag of bolts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pb_bolt_box_small_descr">
		<text>A bag containing 5 bolts. Stalkers enjoy storing bolts in bags of this type.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
