<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!-- Çàäàííèÿ -->
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_0_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: find the old notebook on one of the bandits</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_0_text">
    <text>Zokhan has told me that one of the bandits dropped an old notebook during battle. I should find it.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_1_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: check the coordinates</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_1_text">
    <text>A set of coordinates for an area not far from here are mentioned in the notebook. Time to check it out.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_2_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: wait until night</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_2_text">
    <text>The coordinates have led me to a note that holds the time and area of a meeting with a certain stalker. I have to wait until night and check everything there.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_3_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: go to the meeting with the unknown stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_3_text">
    <text>Whoever's behind this has appointed a meeting in the tunnel under the railroad embankment. I need to check that area. Perhaps I'll find out what the bandits were looking for.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_4_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: speak to Zokhan</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_4_text">
    <text>I underestimated the severity of the situation. Skull turned out wiser than I thought. He took a sum of money from me for some case and vanished into the dark. I need to warn Zokhan about what happened.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_5_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: open the case</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_5_text">
    <text>I need to find someone who can get this damn case open.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_6_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: speak to Zokhan</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_6_text">
    <text>The case is open. I need to show its contents to Zokhan.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_7_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: collect Zokhan's debts</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_7_text">
    <text>I need to retrieve the money from Zokhan.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_8_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: examine the contents of the notebook</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_8_text">
    <text>I found the notebook that Zokhan was talking about. I should read it to find out what else to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_9_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: read the note</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_9_text">
    <text>When I arrived at the designated coordinates, I discovered a note. I should read it.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_10_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: return to Zokhan</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_10_text">
    <text>I underestimated severity of the situation. The unknown stalker who organized the meeting turned out to be a bandit. He decided to take a sum of money from me; likely payment for a case that was in his possession. Good thing it didn't work out for him. I need to discuss this situation with Zokhan.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_11_name">
    <text>Zokhan's instinct: search the dead bandit</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zohan_flair_quest_11_text">
    <text>I underestimated the severity of the situation. The unknown stalker who organized the meeting turned out to be a bandit. He decided to take a sum of money from me, but fortunately, it didn't work out for him. I need to check his body.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_keys_lisiy_quest_0_name">
    <text>Strange case: wait until the case is opened</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_keys_lisiy_quest_0_text">
    <text>Van has assured me that he'll try to open the case, although he'll need some time to do it.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_keys_lisiy_quest_1_name">
    <text>Strange case: visit Van</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_keys_lisiy_quest_1_text">
    <text>I received a message from Van not long ago: “Beast, I've got some good news for you. When you have the time, come see me.”</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_witch_bounce_quest_0_name">
    <text>Witch circle: jump into the anomaly</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_witch_bounce_quest_0_text">
    <text>If Shilov's theory is true, the anomaly should teleport me into a predetermined area.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_witch_bounce_quest_1_name">
    <text>Witch circle: tell Shilov about recent events</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_witch_bounce_quest_1_text">
    <text>Seems I'm alive, though I feel a strange sensation. I should go see Shilov.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_chain_of_events_quest_0_name">
    <text>Chain of events: figure out recent events</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_chain_of_events_quest_1_name">
    <text>Chain of events: tell Shilov about recent events</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_chain_of_events_quest_2_name">
    <text>Chain of events: answer the call</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_chain_of_events_quest_0_text">
    <text>On the way to the farm, I saw the dead body of the guy in the tunnel. Everything is getting more incomprehensible and confusing.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_chain_of_events_quest_1_text">
    <text>Shit. My head is pounding. Seems I'm hearing some kind of voice, and it's calling me. I don't know how, but I know where it's calling me. I need to go there.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_chain_of_events_quest_2_text">
    <text>So that's where the voice came from: it was a controller. How the hell did it appear in the Cordon?…</text>
</string>
<!--------------------------->

<!-- Messages :) -->
<string id="esc_send_tip_furgon_from_keys">
    <text>Beast, I’ve got some good news for you. When you have the time, come see me. Van.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_send_tip_sidorovich_from_act1">
    <text>Merc, I’ve heard you’ve got some valuable information. Come pay me a visit. I’ll pay you well. Sidorovich.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_send_tip_zohan_from_actors1">
    <text>Beast, there’s something I need to tell you. Come by when you can. Zokhan.</text>
</string>
<!--------------------------->

<!-- Achievements -->
<string id="st_sp_achievement_terpenie_name">
    <text>Patience</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sp_achievement_terpenie_descr">
    <text>No matter how difficult or disturbing the situation may be, you always keep your cool. You plan every step ahead, no matter how small. In places where others panic, you display composure and confidence. This is the trait of a true leader.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_sp_achievement_terpenie_hint">
    <text>Your reputation among the stalkers has significantly improved.</text>
</string>

<string id="st_achievement_terpenie_sms">
    <text>You have attained the Patience achievement.</text>
</string>
<!--------------------------->

<!-- Items -->
<string id="esc_old_notebook">
    <text>Old notebook</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_old_notebook_descr">
    <text>A threadbare and seemingly unremarkable notebook. To read, click “Use.”</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_lisiy_notes">
    <text>Note from Skull</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_lisiy_notes_desc">
    <text>A stalker’s note written on a sheet of paper torn out of a notebook. To read, click “Use.”</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_lisiy_keys_name">
    <text>Metallic fireproof case</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_lisiy_keys_desc">
    <text>This case is relatively light despite its large size. I wonder what might be inside?</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_flash_for_keys_name">
    <text>USB flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_flash_for_keys_desc">
    <text>A device used for storing computer data. Can be plugged in to a computer or any other device via USB port.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_papka_for_keys_name">
    <text>Document folder</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_papka_for_keys_desc">
    <text>These documents most likely contained reports of a massive arms shipment sent to the bandit base that took place about a month ago. The source of these weapons is unknown.</text>
</string>
<!--------------------------->

<!-- Names -->
<string id="esc_lisiy_npc_name">
    <text>Skull</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_bobik_npc_name">
    <text>Bobby</text>
</string>
</string_table>