<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="actor_start_game">
		<text>I wish I had some painkillers for this headache. That dream didn’t help, either…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_kill_controler">
		<text>Shit! Another “gift” from the Zone! Just what I needed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_teleport">
		<text>What if I try to use one of the teleporters? Maybe one of them will lead me to Scavenger?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_phantom">
		<text>I need to check out the basement Marcus mentioned. Maybe I can find something useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_otshelnik">
		<text>What was that? Was that thing real or was I hallucinating? I think I’m losing my mind…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_signal">
		<text>An SOS. Strange. Do we have another “guest”? I should check it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_search_markus">
		<text>Damn it, Marcus. Where have you gone off to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_death_kuvalda">
		<text>Rest in peace, Sledgehammer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_tachenko_death">
		<text>Fucking hell… This anomaly never fails to surprise me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_exit_from_puzir">
		<text>Is this really it? Are we finally free from this godforsaken place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_anomaly">
		<text>I should check the arch-anomaly later. Perhaps I might find some valuable artifacts there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_tunel_angry">
		<text>I hate that tunnel…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_pain_in_head">
		<text>God damn it. My head feels like it’s about to explode.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_enot_job_1">
		<text>Raccoon might be able to help me complete the contract. I should go talk to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_enot_job_2">
		<text>I should go pay Raccoon a visit. I think he can help me out with this mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_note">
		<text>Besides a bunch of random personal notes, this notebook contains coordinates of some kind. I should check it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_prison">
		<text>What the hell? Why am I in this cage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_levsha">
		<text>All right, let’s find Lefty. Where would I go if I’d just killed my friend?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_anomal_zone">
		<text>I should inspect the surroundings when I have the time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_levsha_death">
		<text>Damn it, Lefty… Who could have done this? I should search the hangar. Perhaps the murderer left some kind of clue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_anomaly_wild">
		<text>One wrong move and I’ll fall off…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_kill_merc">
		<text>I gave you a chance to leave peacefully! Now you’ll rot in here for eternity!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_talk_to_phantom_1">
		<text>Get out of my head!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_talk_to_phantom_2">
		<text>You can’t break me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_bloodsucker">
		<text>Damn it. This place is swarming with bloodsuckers… I need to stay quiet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_lutiy_death">
		<text>I’ll avenge Savage’s death… I’ll make that creature pay!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_destroy_way">
		<text>I need to blow the entrance shut so that creature won’t follow me out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_otshelnik_death">
		<text>Goodbye, Hermit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intro_ending_neutral_0">
		<text>During the afternoon, Hunter and I went on our way, and after a few hours, we were already at the bar. By the time we reached it, it was already dark, so Hunter suggested we get some rest and head off to the Cordon next thing in the morning. The story’s not over yet, though…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intro_ending_neutral_1">
		<text>Alas, I wake up not in the bar but in the Lair. In front of me, I see a panicked Marcus, and with each moment, my memories of the past slowly fade away. Stronglav won’t release me from his net so easily. He’s playing with me, keeping me trapped inside some kind of time loop, restarting it over and over. Unfortunately, I won’t be able to remember how I got out of here previously; my memories fade away with a headache. I cannot leave this time loop while the creature is alive, but I will find a way. I promise!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intro_ending_good">
		<text>I don’t know what happened after my conversation with Marcus, but when I come to, I find myself in the Lair. In front of me, I see a panicked Marcus, and with each moment, my memories of the digger station and the Outpost fade away. Stronglav won’t release me from his net so easily. He needs me—or rather, my body—and he’s keeping me trapped inside some kind of time loop, restarting it over and over, until I give in. But I won’t give in, and I will find a way to kill that creature. I promise!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lutiy_talk_moskit">
		<text>Listen up, Mosquito: take Beast with you and hurry on over to the zombies. We need to eliminate them at all costs, or they’ll overrun the base in minutes. Use all the ammo you have left—Beast has supplied us with additional magazines. I hope you come out in one piece.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lutiy_meet_prison_actor">
		<text>Beast, can you hear me? I’ll try to talk to the base leader. He should free you. Just don’t do anything stupid in the meantime. See you later!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="moskit_talk_to_actor">
		<text>Are you ready? Then take the lead while I cover you from behind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="moskit_talk_to_kill_zombied">
		<text>I think that’s the last of them. Check the bodies; we need everything we can get right now.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
