<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="actor_start_game">
		<text>I could really use some headache pills. That dream didn’t help, either…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_kill_controler">
		<text>Damn it! Another “gift” from the Zone! Just what I needed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_teleport">
		<text>What if I try to use the teleporters? Maybe one of them will lead me to Scavenger?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_phantom">
		<text>I need to check out the basement that Marcus talked about. Maybe I’ll find something useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_otshelnik">
		<text>Was that thing real or was I just seeing things? I think I’m losing my mind…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_signal">
		<text>An SOS? Strange. Did someone fall into this trap again? I should check it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_search_markus">
		<text>Damn it. Marcus… Where have you gone off to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_death_kuvalda">
		<text>Rest in peace, Sledgehammer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_tachenko_death">
		<text>Damn it… This anomaly never fails to surprise me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_exit_from_puzir">
		<text>Are we finally free from this fucking anomaly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_anomaly">
		<text>I should check the arch-anomaly later. Perhaps I might find some valuable artifacts there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_tunel_angry">
		<text>I hate this tunnel!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_pain_in_head">
		<text>God damn it. My head is killing me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_enot_job_1">
		<text>Raccoon might be able to help me complete the contract. I should go talk to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_enot_job_2">
		<text>I should go pay Raccoon a visit. I think he can help me complete the contract.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_note">
		<text>Other than useless personal notes, the end of this notebook contains coordinates of some kind, written in big, red letters. I should check it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_prison">
		<text>What the hell? What am I doing behind bars?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_levsha">
		<text>All right, let’s find this Lefty. Where would I go if I’d just killed my friend?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_anomal_zone">
		<text>I’ll need to inspect the surroundings when I have some free time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_levsha_death">
		<text>Damn it. Lefty… Who could have done this? I should search the hangar. Perhaps the murderer left some kind of trace.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_anomaly_wild">
		<text>Okay… One wrong move on this thing and I’ll fall off…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_kill_merc">
		<text>I gave you a chance to leave peacefully! Now you’ll rot in here for eternity!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_talk_to_phantom_1">
		<text>Get out of my head!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_talk_to_phantom_2">
		<text>You won’t break me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_bloodsucker">
		<text>Damn it. This place is swarming with bloodsuckers… I need to stay quiet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_lutiy_death">
		<text>I’ll avenge you, Savage… I’ll make that creature pay for everything!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_destroy_way">
		<text>I need to blow the entrance shut so that creature won’t follow me out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_otshelnik_death">
		<text>Farewell, Hermit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intro_ending_neutral_0">
		<text>During the afternoon, Hunter and I went on our way, and after a few hours, we were already in the bar. By the time we got there, it was already dark, so Hunter suggested we get some rest and head off to the Cordon next thing in the morning. The story’s not over yet, though…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intro_ending_neutral_1">
		<text>Alas, I wake up not in the bar but in the Lair. In front of me, I see a panicked Marcus, and with each moment, my memories of the past slowly fade away. Stronglav won’t release me from his net so easily. He’s playing with me, keeping me trapped inside some kind of time loop, restarting it over and over. Unfortunately, I won’t be able to remember how I got out of here previously; my memories fade away with a headache. I cannot leave this time loop while the creature is alive, but I will find a way. I promise!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="intro_ending_good">
		<text>I don’t know what happened after my conversation with Marcus, but when I come to, I find myself in the Lair. In front of me, I see a panicked Marcus, and with each moment, my memories of the digger station and the Outpost fade away. Stronglav won’t release me from his net so easily. He needs me—or rather, my body—and he’s keeping me trapped inside some kind of time loop, restarting it over and over, until I give in. But I won’t give in, and I will find a way to kill that creature. I promise!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lutiy_talk_moskit">
		<text>Listen up, Mosquito: take Beast with you and hurry on over to the zombies. We need to eliminate them at all costs, or they’ll overrun the base in minutes. Use all the ammo you have left—Beast has supplied us with additional magazines. I hope you both pull this off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lutiy_meet_prison_actor">
		<text>Beast, can you hear me? I’ll try to talk to the base leader. He should free you. Just don’t do anything stupid in the meantime. See you later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="moskit_talk_to_actor">
		<text>Are you ready? Then take the lead while I cover you from behind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="moskit_talk_to_kill_zombied">
		<text>I think that’s the last of them. Check the bodies; we need everything we can get right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="moskit_controller_coming">
		<text>C—C—Controller… C—Careful…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dubolom_night_hunting_meet">
		<text>Uh-huh. The chimera’s in the bunker… Don’t let it get out of the bunker, or we’re dead meat. If it does come out in the open, I’ll provide fire support. Go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ghost_podval_talk">
		<text>A living soul… So I’ve made it. The emission won’t get me here. Hey, merc, grab that bottle on the table. Let’s drink to the fact that we’ve lived through another day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_killer_meet_1">
		<text>Be careful…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_killer_meet_2">
		<text>Step back!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_dubolom">
		<text>Okay. This trail is fresh. Means the doggy’s somewhere nearby… Merc, look sharp. Unless, of course, you want to become lunch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_thanks">
		<text>Thanks for freeing us, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="koordinator_first_meet">
		<text>I said come in. Don’t stand there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_to_atp_meet">
		<text>Merc, I take it you’re the leader here? Put down your weapons. We just want to talk… for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_wait_signal_actor">
		<text>Our squad is ready for action. Waiting for your signal!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_we_spotted">
		<text>Attention! We’ve been detected!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_raven_operation_start">
		<text>Let’s do this, boys!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enot_wake_up">
		<text>’Ey, what do you want? It’s the middle of the night…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="security_trader_talk">
		<text>Ugh, these people… Go on, then!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tesak_say_kill_kuvalda">
		<text>Bromine, take out one of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kuvalda_quest_meet_killer">
		<text>Shoot. I’m not afraid of death…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mrakobes_final_scene">
		<text>Good morning to you, Animal. How did you sleep? You’ll have to excuse me, but the time has come for us to say goodbye. Give my regards to our men on the other side.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="murad_quest_door_lock">
		<text>So, Savage told me the transformer should be somewhere around here. Wait a bit. I’ll try to open this lock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="murad_quest_door_open">
		<text>Okay. Continue on your own. I think you know what a transformer box looks like. Just turn the switch and get back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="security_meet_prison_actor">
		<text>Merc, step up to the door. Got a word with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="provodnik_call">
		<text>Hey, merc, what brings you here? Come over and we’ll talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_talk_rac_from_hutor">
		<text>Yo, boys, listen up… You ain’t all dead over there, are you?… Come on! Get on the air already! Hey, brothers, we ain’t clear on what’s going on! Our homies are laying low. Gotta take a peek and see what’s up.\n— Don’t worry, boss. We’re going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kisliy_first_meet">
		<text>Come on in, merc. Miklukha’s waiting for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="krivoy_shcool_no_meet">
		<text>Get out of my face. Go bother Ratter, not me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ghost_talk_about_stronglav_1">
		<text>Merc, you won’t stop him. Just accept the reality of things and stop resisting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ghost_talk_about_stronglav_2">
		<text>Let him consume you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zmeelov_talk_semen">
		<text>Hi, Semyon. Listen, you haven’t seen Markus, have you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="semen_talk_to_zmeelov">
		<text>Hi, Snakecatcher. As far as I know, he went to the cages. Seems like he’s still there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zmeelov_talk_actor">
		<text>Okay, merc, the cages are down the hall to the left. That door over there in the laboratory will lead you to them. Don’t get lost there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zmeelov_talk_semen_after">
		<text>Semyon, let him through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_transiver_1">
		<text>I need to start the transmitter outside the spatial anomaly, not here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_about_transiver_2">
		<text>I’ve already sent the coordinates to the anomaly exit. No need to do it again.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
